<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://imtheva.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://imtheva.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2026-01-05T21:21:52-05:00</updated><id>https://imtheva.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>Personal website of Thevathayarajh Thayananthan — research, projects, publications, and writing on science, engineering, and space. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">MIS</title><link href="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2025/MSc/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MIS"/><published>2025-12-27T19:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-12-27T19:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2025/MSc</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2025/MSc/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="project-overview">Project Overview</h2> <p>Several medical devices can directly analyze a patient’s medical condition; however, the physical presence of non-critical patients places a significant burden on hospital infrastructure, particularly bed availability. This issue becomes more critical during movement-restricted situations such as the COVID-19 pandemic.</p> <p>This project presents a <strong>budget-friendly, IoT-based distanced health monitoring system</strong> that enables continuous monitoring of non-critical patients without requiring physical hospital visits. The system provides real-time access to medical data for patients, caretakers, and doctors through a secure web application.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="system-architecture-and-methodology">System Architecture and Methodology</h2> <div class="row justify-content-sm-center"> <div class="col-sm-10 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/projects/project_1/Methods-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/Methods-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/Methods-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/projects/project_1/Methods.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" title="System Architecture of IoT-Based Health Monitoring System" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Overall system architecture showing patient-side sensing, Raspberry Pi-based processing, Firebase Firestore cloud storage, and web application access for patients, caretakers, and doctors. </div> <p>The system collects physiological data from patients using sensors connected to a <strong>Raspberry Pi</strong>. The processed data are transmitted securely to <strong>Firebase Firestore</strong>, enabling near real-time synchronization with the Medical Instrumentation System (MIS) web application.</p> <p>The web interface allows:</p> <ul> <li>Patients and caretakers to monitor real-time health parameters and danger levels</li> <li>Doctors to review medical history and provide prescriptions and feedback remotely</li> </ul> <hr/> <h2 id="scope-and-objectives">Scope and Objectives</h2> <ul> <li>Develop an <strong>IoT-based system</strong> for monitoring patient health</li> <li>Monitor <strong>physiological parameters and lifestyle indicators</strong></li> <li>Design a <strong>portable device</strong> suitable for continuous patient use</li> <li>Enable scalability for <strong>multiple patients and doctors</strong></li> </ul> <hr/> <h2 id="results-and-discussion">Results and Discussion</h2> <div class="row justify-content-sm-center"> <div class="col-sm-10 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/projects/project_1/R2-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/R2-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/R2-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/projects/project_1/R2.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" title="R2" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="row"> <div class="col-sm-6 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/projects/project_1/R1-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/R1-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/R1-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/projects/project_1/R1.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" title="R1" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm-6 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/projects/project_1/R4-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/R4-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/R4-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/projects/project_1/R4.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> IoT device for collecting physiological data and transmitting it to Firebase Firestore for real-time visualization. </div> <p>The developed Medical Instrumentation System (MIS) demonstrated that IoT-based distanced patient monitoring is feasible for non-critical cases.</p> <p>Key outcomes include:</p> <ul> <li>End-to-end data synchronization (device → Firestore → MIS page) within <strong>1–2 seconds</strong></li> <li>Patients and caretakers can view medical data, danger levels, and follow doctor prescriptions</li> <li>Secure storage of patient medical history enables informed clinical decision-making</li> </ul> <p>This study incorporates patient basic details to prioritize medical history, an aspect not widely explored in related works. Additionally, the system supports doctor prescriptions and feedback, which are absent in many existing solutions.</p> <p>Firestore allows up to <strong>1 MB of data per document</strong>, indicating the need for a dedicated database server during large-scale commercialization. An SMS gateway can be integrated for OTP-based authentication to enhance system security.</p> <div class="row"> <div class="col-sm-6 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/projects/project_1/D1-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/D1-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/D1-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/projects/project_1/D1.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" title="Doctor Dashboard" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm-6 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/projects/project_1/D2-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/D2-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/D2-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/projects/project_1/D2.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" title="Patient View" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="row justify-content-sm-center"> <div class="col-sm-10 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/projects/project_1/D3-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/D3-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/D3-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/projects/project_1/D3.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" title="Medical History and Graphs" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Web application interface showing doctor dashboard, patient view, and medical history visualization. </div> <hr/> <h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2> <p>This project demonstrates a feasible and scalable approach to implementing an <strong>IoT-based distanced health monitoring system</strong>. The MIS web application successfully displays medical data received from distributed devices and supports interactions among multiple patients, caretakers, and doctors.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="future-directions">Future Directions</h2> <ul> <li>Integrate additional medical devices and sensors based on specific health conditions</li> <li>Incorporate <strong>Machine Learning/Deep Learning</strong> models for early warning prediction</li> <li>Enhance security using <strong>SMS-based OTP authentication</strong></li> </ul> <hr/> <h2 id="live-demo">Live Demo</h2> <p>🔗 <strong>Web Application:</strong> <a href="https://rasp-med.web.app/">https://rasp-med.web.app/</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="references">References</h2> <ol> <li>V. Vippalapalli and S. Ananthula, “Internet of things (IoT) based smart health care system,” <em>SCOPES 2016</em>, 2017.</li> <li>S. Pinto, J. Cabral, and T. Gomes, “We-Care: An IoT-based Health Care System for Elderly People.”</li> <li>V. Tamilselvi et al., “IoT Based Health Monitoring System,” <em>ICACCS 2020</em>, 2020.</li> <li>S. Rajkumar et al., “Health monitoring system using Raspberry Pi,” <em>BID 2017</em>, 2018.</li> <li>M. Hamim et al., “IoT Based remote health monitoring system,” <em>ICREST 2019</em>, 2019.</li> <li>V. Pardeshi et al., “Health monitoring systems using IoT and Raspberry Pi – A review,” <em>ICIMIA 2017</em>, 2017.</li> </ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="Project"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A cost-effective remote health monitoring solution designed to continuously assess non-critical patients while reducing hospital congestion—especially during emergencies such as the COVID-19 pandemic.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">(PDF) Making Threads in SolidWorks</title><link href="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2025/pdf-making-threads-in-solidworks/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="(PDF) Making Threads in SolidWorks"/><published>2025-12-20T19:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-12-20T19:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2025/pdf-making-threads-in-solidworks</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2025/pdf-making-threads-in-solidworks/"><![CDATA[<p>OutlineDownload Free PDF…7 pagesComputer-Aided Design of Traditional Jigs and Fixtures, 2021Conventional design of jigs and fixtures has become unsuitable given the requirements of modern technology and complexity and diversity in the production with the rapid update of products. Computer-aided design (CAD) of jigs and fixtures is an effective solution in this direction. The current paper focuses on a computer-aided design of the traditional jigs and fixtures and developed a system containing tailor-made software, created using the Visual Basic programming language and installed on it the viewer screen to show the part. The developed system has been built by connecting Visual Basic programming language to the SolidWorks software on which the part is drawn and saved as STEP AP-203 file format, and the system reads and extracts the data from the STEP AP-203 file. Heuristic rules of feature recognition are pre-prepared for checking the extracted geometric data and deciding which data shape will represent the machining feature; then, the system provides the optimum design of the traditional jigs and fixtures for a group of hollow cylindrical parts that contain a group of cross-holes on the cylinder body, whether perpendicular or offset from the cylinder’s axis, (inclined or inclined offset, or blind or through, by applying pre-prepared heuristic rules for the design of traditional jigs and fixtures.2023 IEEE 17th International Symposium on Applied Computational Intelligence and Informatics (SACI), 2023In this paper, a carpenter software is designed and implemented that supports the daily management processes (customers, orders, inventory) and generates a pattern from the product descriptions based on the parameters specified. During the pattern generation process, a two-dimensional optimization is performed to generate a pattern that includes horizontal or vertical cuts, depending on the target machine, on which the position of the required parts is placed, generates the smallest material loss and uses leftover materials from the past. From the application, the pattern can be viewed and extracted online or in PDF format. This all is implemented in a layered web application with a modern approach.THREE DIMENSIONAL MODELING AND LOADING SIMULATION OF A STANDARD THREADED FASTENER IN CAD ENVIRONMENT (ТРИМЕРНО МОДЕЛИРАНЕ И СИМУЛАЦИОННО НАТОВАРВАНЕ В CAD-СРЕДА KНА СТАНДАРТНО РЕЗБОВО СЪЕДИНЕНИЕ ), 2006Abstract. The techniques of correct three dimensional modeling of geometry parameters of thread and of the body of standard threaded fasteners (bolt and nut) in CAD environment of software product SolidWoprks’2005 are presented. The model of joint are put under loading simulation and the zones of concentrations of stresses are determined. The values and distribution of stresses from loading simulation and from calculation and from experiments known from literature are compared. Key words: threaded fasteners, CAD, finite element method.This paper presents a mechanistic model for prediction of the thread milling forces. The mechanics of cutting for thread milling is analyzed similar to the end milling process but with modified cutting edge geometry. The chip thickness and cutting force models are developed considering the unique geometry of the tool. The model has been calibrated for 6061 Aluminum and validated. The effects of tool and thread geometry have been studied using the model. rZenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research), 2012Modular fixtures (MFs) are very important tools in manufacturing processes in terms of reduction the cost and the production time. This paper introduces an automated approach for assembling MFs elements by employing SolidWorks as a powerful 3D CAD software. Visual Basic (VB) programming language was applied integrating with SolidWorks API (Application programming interface) functions. This integration allowed creating plug-in file and generating new menus in the SolidWorks environment. The menus allow the user to select, insert, and assemble MFs elements.Drug and Alcohol Dependence, 2010Cigarette craving is an important contributor to cigarette smoking, and clinical approaches that focus on regulation of craving are effective in reducing rates of relapse. However, a laboratory model that targets the use of cognitive strategies to regulate craving is lacking. To develop such a model, twenty heavy cigarette smokers (&gt;12/day), twenty-two tobacco “chippers” (&lt;6/day), and twenty non-smoking controls completed this outpatient study, during which they were presented with photographs of cigarettes and foods that have been previously shown to induce craving. During each trial, participants were instructed to think of the stimulus in one of two ways: by focusing either on the short-term consequences associated with consuming the item (e.g., it will taste good) or on the long-term consequences associated with regular consumption (e.g., I may get lung cancer). Participants reported significantly reduced food cravings when focusing on the long-term consequences associated with eating. For cigarette-smoking participants, cigarette craving was significantly reduced when focusing on the long-term consequences associated with smoking. This latter finding confirms clinical data and extends it by highlighting the importance of cognition in the modulation of craving. Future studies using this laboratory model could test the efficacy of different cognitive strategies and develop targeted interventions for smoking cessation based on the regulation of craving.Journal of Interventional Cardiac Electrophysiology, 2023Background With advancements in technology and ablation techniques, catheter ablation for the treatment of atrial fibrillation (AF) has become safer with time. In the past, standard-of-care recommended overnight stay for outpatient procedures. As safety has improved and procedure times have shortened, some centers have allowed for same-day discharge. We report the results of a multi-center, randomized clinical trial investigating the safety of same-day discharge post-cryoballoon ablation. Methods Patients with paroxysmal atrial fibrillation underwent pulmonary vein isolation (PVI) with the Medtronic Arctic Advance cryoballoon at 3 US centers. Six hours after the procedure, patients were randomized to either stay overnight or be discharged same day. Results A total of 49 patients were enrolled. Two patients were withdrawn prior to randomization. One patient chose to withdraw after randomization. Of the 22 patients randomized to same-day discharge and the 23 patients randomized the overnight stay, no significant adverse outcomes were reported in either group. Occurrence of adverse events did not differ significantly between the two groups. Procedure time and fluoroscopy time did not significantly differ between groups. Conclusions This is the first randomized trial examining the safety of same-day discharge post-cryoballoon ablation. Based on our results, same-day discharge following cryoballoon ablation for paroxysmal AF is a safe option following uncomplicated ablation for PVI. Operators should use their discretion in selecting patients for same-day discharge.Micromachines, 2020We describe the manufacture of low-cost microfluidic systems to produce nanoscale liposomes with highly uniform size distributions (i.e., low polydispersity indexes (PDI)) and acceptable colloidal stability. This was achieved by exploiting a Y-junction device followed by a serpentine micromixer geometry to facilitate the diffusion between the mixing phases (i.e., continuous and dispersed) via advective processes. Two different geometries were studied. In the first one, the microchannels were engraved with a laser cutting machine on a polymethyl methacrylate (PMMA) sheet and covered with another PMMA sheet to form a two-layer device. In the second one, microchannels were not engraved but through-hole cut on a PMMA sheet and encased by a top and a bottom PMMA sheet to form a three-layer device. The devices were tested out by putting in contact lipids dissolved in alcohol as the dispersed phase and water as the continuous phase to self-assemble the liposomes. By fixing the total flow r…European Heart Journal, 2002The objective of this paper is to measure the potential burden of cardiovascular disease within the original Framingham Heart Study cohort by transforming its welldescribed epidemiological measures into time-based health policy measures, such as life years lost to or lived with the disease. We constructed multi-state life tables of the Framingham Heart Study cohort to calculate dwelling times with a history of cardiovascular disease. Age-specific probabilities determined transitions from healthy through disease to death. For this synthetic cohort, from age 50 men (women) live on average 26 (32) years; 20 (26) free of cardiovascular disease. Allowing occupancy of more than one disease state, 50-year-old males (females) live 2•9 (1•2) years with a history of myocardial infarction, 0•93 (1•2) with a history of stroke, and 0•67 (0•93) with congestive heart failure. Having ever suffered acute myocardial infarction, stroke or congestive heart failure, life expectancy is reduced by 9 (13), 12 (15) or 16 ( ) years, respectively in 60-year-old men (women). Transforming occurrence probabilities into time-based health measures, the prevalence of cardiovascular disease is remarkable: from age 50, 20% of remaining life expectancy is lived with the disease. Such measures are integral to appropriate health planning and assessment of the potential population health value of various treatment and prevention strategies.Asian Journal of Current Research, 2025Lead exposure is a pervasive environmental hazard known for its detrimental effects on renal function. Garcinia kola is traditionally valued for its medicinal properties, and its extract is believed to protect organs from toxic insults by mitigating oxidative stress and cellular damage. This study investigates the nephroprotective effects of Garcinia kola (bitter kola) aqueous extract against lead-induced kidney damage in Wistar rats. Twenty-five male Wistar rats were divided into five groups: a control group, a lead-only group (60 mg/kg lead acetate), and three treated groups receiving lead followed by Garcinia kola extract at doses of 150 mg/kg, 300 mg/kg, and 600 mg/kg for 21 days. Biochemical analyses were conducted to assess serum urea, creatinine, and uric acid levels, alongside morphological assessments of kidney tissues. Results indicated that lead acetate administration significantly elevated serum creatinine levels (P = .001) and caused observable morphological changes, indicating renal impairment. Conversely, treatment with Garcinia kola extract resulted in a dose-dependent restoration of kidney function, with groups receiving 300 mg/kg and 600 mg/kg showing significant reductions in creatinine (P = .001, P = .011) and improvements in overall health metrics. These findings suggest that Garcinia kola extract effectively mitigates lead-induced renal damage, likely due to its antioxidant properties. This study highlights the potential of Garcinia kola as a therapeutic agent for protecting against heavy metal toxicity, warranting further investigation into its mechanisms of action and long-term efficacy in clinical settings.Procedia Manufacturing, 2015The modulated tool path (MTP) chip breaking process has been modified to improve chip management capabilities and to prevent large chip nest accumulations commonly encountered in threading operations. The use of MTP to create segmented chips requires a different approach for threading operations than for normal MTP turning operations, although the fundamental principal is the same. The primary difference between MTP for threading and for straight turning is that the part surface that the tool repeatedly engages and disengages, during the modulation process, is the thread root rather than the cut face. The threading MTP part program developed in this paper is capable of machining a thread with the desired lead, depth, undercut angle, and taper angle while also producing segmented chips.International Journal of …, 2006This paper presents a mechanistic model for prediction of the thread milling forces. The mechanics of cutting for thread milling is analyzed similar to the end milling process but with modified cutting edge geometry. The chip thickness and cutting force models are developed considering the unique geometry of the tool. The model has been calibrated for 6061 Aluminum and validated. The effects of tool and thread geometry have been studied using the model. rVariations in cutting forces were investigated experimentally depending on infeed angles and cutting areas in the external threading on a CNC turning centre. For this purpose, AISI 1050 workpiece material, 16ERM AG 60 IC 908 cutting tool, and SER 2525 M16 tool holder were used. External threading operations were performed using 0 • , 14.5 • , 15 • , 27.5 • , and 30 • infeed angles while the cutting speed was held constant at 100 m/min for the experiments. Experimental results showed that the infeed angle and cutting area had significant effects on the main cutting force and the radial force components were considerable in threading operations in terms of energy consumption. In addition, the optimum infeed angle was 30 • in the external threading operations in terms of cutting forces.Acta Polytechnica Hungarica, 2014Different tool geometries have been developed by leading companies in the tool industry to different aims of application. The fastest progress can be observed in the development of coatings, in spite of this it can be noticed that there are only few coating types, but they can be used in a wide range. For users it offers the great advantage to select appropriate tool easier. Coating types, developed specially to individual aim of application, offer much better solution, compared to the generally used coating types. Platit AG, dealing with the development of optimised coating types, has requested our specialised group to carry out tests on specialised coating types. Our present study is going to summarise the results of the tests, carried out with thread forming tools.The International Journal of Advanced Manufacturing Technology, 2014is an open access repository that collects the work of Arts et Métiers ParisTech researchers and makes it freely available over the web where possible. This is an author-deposited version published in: http://sam.ensam.eu Handle ID: .http://hdl.handle.net/10985/8565 To cite this version : Vishal SHARMA, Guillaume FROMENTIN, Gérard POULACHON, Romain BRENDLEN -Investigation of tool geometry effect and penetration strategies on cutting forces during thread millingRANLP 2017 - Recent Advances in Natural Language Processing Meet Deep LearningWe address information credibility in community forums, in a setting in which the credibility of an answer posted in a question thread by a particular user has to be predicted. First, we motivate the problem and we create a publicly available annotated English corpus by crowdsourcing. Second, we propose a large set of features to predict the credibility of the answers. The features model the user, the answer, the question, the thread as a whole, and the interaction between them. Our experiments with ranking SVMs show that the credibility labels can be predicted with high performance according to several standard IR ranking metrics, thus supporting the potential usage of this layer of credibility information in practical applications. The features modeling the profile of the user (in particular trollness) turn out to be most important, but embedding features modeling the answer and the similarity between the question and the answer are also very relevant. Overall, half of the gap between the baseline performance and the perfect classifier can be covered using the proposed features.International series in management science/operations research, 1996Group the supplies and supply prices, respectively, into a column vector s ∈ R m and a column vector π ∈ R m . Similarly, group the demands and the demand prices, respectively, into a column vector d ∈ R n and a column vector ρ ∈ R n . Let Q ij denote the nonnegative commodity shipment between the supply and demand market pair (i, j) and let c ij denote the nonnegative unit transaction cost associated with trading the commodity between (i, j). Assume that the transaction cost includes the cost of transportation; depending upon the application, one may also include a tax/tariff, fee, duty, or subsidy within this cost. Group then the commodity shipments into a column vector Q ∈ R mn and the transaction costs into a column vector c ∈ R mn .Empowering minds: navigating the emerging clinical and mental health , 2025A Festschrift is a collection of scholarly works compiled to honor and recognise a scholar’s legacy and contributions. It serves as a mark of respect and appreciation for their impact on the field, often published on significant occasions like retirement, anniversaries, or milestones to celebrate individuals. This book, Empowering Minds: Navigating Emerging Clinical Mental Issues, is however, dedicated to the memory of Professor Jonathan Ohis Osiki, a renowned Clinical Psychologist whose scholarly works touched many lives. As a former Head of the Department of Counselling and Human Development Studies at the University of Ibadan, Nigeria, Jonathan Osiki’s contributions were widely acknowledged. Having had the privilege of knowing and relating with him as a classmate and later as a colleague in the Department, I believe his memory should be preserved for those who knew him and for others. This book therefore, is fittingly in order. The theme and chapters also align with his passion for clinical issues in Counselling Psychology, addressing contemporary mental health concerns and sparking meaningful discussions. I trust this book will make a valuable contribution to the field he cherished, and honouring Professor Osiki’s memory and impact.Reports of Practical Oncology &amp; Radiotherapy, 2016reports of practical oncology and radiotherapy 2 1 ( 2 0 1 6 ) 95-101 combination with (p,n) and (d,n) reactions. 9 Be(d,n) 10 B at 1.4 MeV, with a thin target has been shown to be a realistic option for the treatment of deep-seated lesions.Jurnal, 2026</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Making Threads in SolidWorks]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">(PDF) Measuring Pen – A digital device to measure distance</title><link href="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2025/pdf-measuring-pen-a-digital-device-to-measure-distance/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="(PDF) Measuring Pen – A digital device to measure distance"/><published>2025-12-19T19:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-12-19T19:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2025/pdf-measuring-pen--a-digital-device-to-measure-distance</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2025/pdf-measuring-pen-a-digital-device-to-measure-distance/"><![CDATA[<p>OutlineDownload Free PDF…3 pagesThis is a new approach on the section of measurement. Today, most of the garment companies are producing lot of clothes. While producing clothes they have to face lot of problems. For an example time of delivery and accuracy in clothes size. A traditional way of measuring a cloth is using a tape. Due to that there may be errors in measuring length and it take times time to check the length using tape. Main aim of this mini project is to solve these problems using a microcontroller measuring system. This will reduce the time taken for the cutting and will measure accurately. For this project Arduino Nano is used as the microcontroller for performing the algorithmic work.Hybrid Quantum-Classical Swarm Architecture: Timed and Criteria-Based Qubit Swarms with Relay Mechanisms, 2026My idea of combining an Autonomous Bot Swarm System Relay timed with precision with Qubits in superpositionBiomedical Journal of Scientific &amp; Technical Research, 2018A 1.2kg, preterm female baby presented with left sided congenital diaphragmatic hernia (CDH). On left subcostal exploration, left CDH with sac was identified. At the time of excision of sac, a large nodule was identified sequestered on sac, which was later identified as extrapulmonary sequestration of lung. The baby succumbed to persistent pulmonary hypertension and pulmonary hemorrhage in post-operative period.2011Operacja zatrzymania kierowcy niepodporządkowującego się poleceniom Policji, jest bardzo trudna i niebezpieczna. Zagrożenie może dotyczyć zarówno samego funkcjonariusza, osoby zatrzymywanej jak i osób postronnych. W ramach badań wykonano serie kontrolowanych przejazdów po kolczatce policyjnej z różnymi prędkościami, zaczynając od typowych prędkości w ruchu miejskim, aż do osiągnięcia prędkości charakterystycznych dla jazdy po autostradzie. Sprawdzono nie tylko zachowanie się pojazdu podczas momentu przebicia opony, ale również kierowalność i stateczność pojazdu podczas jazdy z już uszkodzoną oponą. Wykonano także porównanie standardowych opon i opon typu Run On Flat, umożliwiających jazdę bez ciśnienia powietrza. Dla obu typów opon przeprowadzono sprawdzenie skuteczności hamowania i wykonano jazdy przebiegowe, aż do chwili całkowitego zniszczenia barku opony. Badania te miały na celu sprawdzenie przydatności opon typu Run On Flat, w pojazdach policyjnych. Prace były realizowane w ramach projektu badawczo-rozwojowego nr 0R00000911, “Opracowanie wymagań technicznych i zakresu niezbędnego wyposażenia dla pojazdów policyjnych, na podstawie badań wzorcowych demonstratorów”, prowadzonego przez WITPiS wraz z firma AMZ Kutno.Iranian Journal of Biotechnology, 2016Circulation, 2000We have read the article by Kiechl et al 1 demonstrating that acquired activated protein C resistance (APC) may be a risk factor for atherosclerosis and arterial thrombosis in whites. We 2 previously demonstrated that acquired APC resistance is associated not only with venous thrombosis (deep vein thrombosis and pulmonary thromboembolism) but also with arterial thrombotic disease (cerebral infarction and coronary artery disease) in the Japanese population. It is well known that no Japanese has factor V Leiden mutation because of the founder effect of this mutation. 3 Thus, it is likely that in Japanese, some environmental factors might contribute to APC resistance. In addition, we demonstrated a positive association of APC sensitivity ratio with plasma levels of the activated form of factor VII (FVIIa, an activation marker of the early phase of the tissue factor pathway of coagulation 4 in healthy subjects; correlation coefficient Ϫ0.38, PϽ0.05, nϭ33). 2 This association was also found in subjects with a predisposing condition of thrombosis, namely, protein C deficiency (correlation coefficient Ϫ0.40, PϽ0.005, nϭ53). More recently, pregnancy-related APC resistance has also been reported 5 to be associated with thrombin-antithrombin complex (an indicator of in vivo thrombin generation) (correlation coefficient with APC sensitivity ratio Ϫ0.274, Pϭ0.01, nϭ128). Thus, the APC resistance may reflect the global insensitivity of APC and may provide a good method to assess the hypercoagulable state in vivo. The hypercoagulable state induced by acquired APC resistance should be given greater emphasis in clinical practice in the future.Política. Revista de Ciencia Política, 2025La Ciencia Política y su enseñanza están débilmente institucionalizadas en Paraguay. La producción académica en esta disciplina es aún limitada y posee escasa inserción a nivel internacional. Este artículo argumenta que la enseñanza de la disciplina como una de las principales causas de su debilidad estructural. A su vez, la situación de su enseñanza refleja problemas más generales como la falta de financiamiento para la enseñanza, la inestable y limitada presencia de profesores con doctorados en Ciencia Política, la estructura curricular inadecuada o los escasos incentivos para la investigación. La investigación se basa en revisión documental, entrevistas a profundidad a profesores y estudiantes en las dos principales universidades que ofrecen programas de grado en esta disciplina en Paraguay y literatura secundaria.— This paper deals with the design and implementation of a simple HMC6352 2-axis digital compass. Most compasses have been of the analogue type with magnetic needles as pointers. Replacing the “ old “ magnetic needle compass or the gyrocompass by an electronic solution offers advantages like having a solid-state component without moving parts and the ease of interfacing with other electronic systems. In this work, the aim is to design and implement a digital compass. To realize this, we made use of HMC6352 which is a 2-axis MR (magneto-resistive) sensor from Honeywell, Arduino Uno board with an onboard ATmega328 microcontroller chip, and a 16x2 character Liquid Crystal Display (LCD).We adopted the magneto-resistive (MR) technology as compared to flux-gate sensors common in most electronic compasses which has the disadvantage of making the device bulky. The trial test carried out with the completed HMC6352 digital compass showed a reading of 232.8 degrees West indicating its effectiveness in direction finding.Clinical Immunology (Fourth Edition), 2013Geografía Social. Permanencias, cambios y escenarios futurosNew Covenant Publications International Ltd, 2020Rupkatha Journal on Interdisciplinary Studies in Humanities, 2021The projection of the incongruities of contemporary times through the frame of satire is a powerful instrument in the genre of comics and graphic narratives and in Indian graphic literature as well. Mendiburo-Seguel and Heintz (2020) explain eight Comic Style Markers (CSM) in Latin-American cultures, and satire, a “darker style”, is one of them. The paper aims to conceptualise how Appupen’s wordless graphic narratives Moonward: Stories from Halahala (2009), Legends of Halahala (2013), Aspyrus: A Dream of Halahala (2014) and The Snake and the Lotus: A Halahala Adventure (2018) register black satire against society, politics, religion, industrialization, consumerism, advertisement and so on and how they prove to play the role of “corrective humour” (Ruch and Heintz, 2016). This paper attempts to explore how the “author-artist’s” (Aldama, 2010) fantastical and dystopic graphic narratives, excoriate social and political issues to create a unique aesthetic of thoughtful critical writing …</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is a new approach on the section of measurement. Today, most of the garment companies are producing lot of clothes. While producing clothes they have to face lot of problems. For an example time of delivery and accuracy in clothes size. A]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Google Gemini updates: Flash 1.5, Gemma 2 and Project Astra</title><link href="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2024/google-gemini-updates-flash-15-gemma-2-and-project-astra/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Google Gemini updates: Flash 1.5, Gemma 2 and Project Astra"/><published>2024-05-13T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-05-13T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2024/google-gemini-updates-flash-15-gemma-2-and-project-astra</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2024/google-gemini-updates-flash-15-gemma-2-and-project-astra/"><![CDATA[<p>May 14, 2024 We’re introducing a series of updates across the Gemini family of models, including the new 1.5 Flash, our lightweight model for speed and efficiency, and Project Astra, our vision for the future of AI assistants. In December, we launched our first natively multimodal model Gemini 1.0 in three sizes: Ultra, Pro and Nano. Just a few months later we released 1.5 Pro, with enhanced performance and a breakthrough long context window of 1 million tokens.Developers and enterprise customers have been putting 1.5 Pro to use in incredible ways and finding its long context window, multimodal reasoning capabilities and impressive overall performance incredibly useful.We know from user feedback that some applications need lower latency and a lower cost to serve. This inspired us to keep innovating, so today, we’re introducing Gemini 1.5 Flash: a model that’s lighter-weight than 1.5 Pro, and designed to be fast and efficient to serve at scale.Both 1.5 Pro and 1.5 Flash are available in public preview with a 1 million token context window in Google AI Studio and Vertex AI. And now, 1.5 Pro is also available with a 2 million token context window via waitlist to developers using the API and to Google Cloud customers.We’re also introducing updates across the Gemini family of models, announcing our next generation of open models, Gemma 2, and sharing progress on the future of AI assistants, with Project Astra.Context lengths of leading foundation models compared with Gemini 1.5’s 2 million token capability1.5 Flash is the newest addition to the Gemini model family and the fastest Gemini model served in the API. It’s optimized for high-volume, high-frequency tasks at scale, is more cost-efficient to serve and features our breakthrough long context window.While it’s a lighter weight model than 1.5 Pro, it’s highly capable of multimodal reasoning across vast amounts of information and delivers impressive quality for its size.The new Gemini 1.5 Flash model is optimized for speed and efficiency, is highly capable of multimodal reasoning and features our breakthrough long context window.1.5 Flash excels at summarization, chat applications, image and video captioning, data extraction from long documents and tables, and more. This is because it’s been trained by 1.5 Pro through a process called “distillation,” where the most essential knowledge and skills from a larger model are transferred to a smaller, more efficient model.Read more about 1.5 Flash in our updated Gemini 1.5 technical report, on the Gemini technology page, and learn about 1.5 Flash’s availability and pricing.Over the last few months, we’ve significantly improved 1.5 Pro, our best model for general performance across a wide range of tasks.Beyond extending its context window to 2 million tokens, we’ve enhanced its code generation, logical reasoning and planning, multi-turn conversation, and audio and image understanding through data and algorithmic advances. We see strong improvements on public and internal benchmarks for each of these tasks.1.5 Pro can now follow increasingly complex and nuanced instructions, including ones that specify product-level behavior involving role, format and style. We’ve improved control over the model’s responses for specific use cases, like crafting the persona and response style of a chat agent or automating workflows through multiple function calls. And we’ve enabled users to steer model behavior by setting system instructions.We added audio understanding in the Gemini API and Google AI Studio, so 1.5 Pro can now reason across image and audio for videos uploaded in Google AI Studio. And we’re now integrating 1.5 Pro into Google products, including Gemini Advanced and in Workspace apps.Read more about 1.5 Pro in our updated Gemini 1.5 technical report and on the Gemini technology page.Gemini Nano is expanding beyond text-only inputs to include images as well. Starting with Pixel, applications using Gemini Nano with Multimodality will be able to understand the world the way people do — not just through text, but also through sight, sound and spoken language.Read more about Gemini 1.0 Nano on Android.Today, we’re also sharing a series of updates to Gemma, our family of open models built from the same research and technology used to create the Gemini models.We’re announcing Gemma 2, our next generation of open models for responsible AI innovation. Gemma 2 has a new architecture designed for breakthrough performance and efficiency, and will be available in new sizes.The Gemma family is also expanding with PaliGemma, our first vision-language model inspired by PaLI-3. And we’ve upgraded our Responsible Generative AI Toolkit with LLM Comparator for evaluating the quality of model responses.Read more on the Developer blog.As part of Google DeepMind’s mission to build AI responsibly to benefit humanity, we’ve always wanted to develop universal AI agents that can be helpful in everyday life. That’s why today, we’re sharing our progress in building the future of AI assistants with Project Astra (advanced seeing and talking responsive agent).To be truly useful, an agent needs to understand and respond to the complex and dynamic world just like people do — and take in and remember what it sees and hears to understand context and take action. It also needs to be proactive, teachable and personal, so users can talk to it naturally and without lag or delay.While we’ve made incredible progress developing AI systems that can understand multimodal information, getting response time down to something conversational is a difficult engineering challenge. Over the past few years, we’ve been working to improve how our models perceive, reason and converse to make the pace and quality of interaction feel more natural.Building on Gemini, we’ve developed prototype agents that can process information faster by continuously encoding video frames, combining the video and speech input into a timeline of events, and caching this information for efficient recall.By leveraging our leading speech models, we also enhanced how they sound, giving the agents a wider range of intonations. These agents can better understand the context they’re being used in, and respond quickly, in conversation.With technology like this, it’s easy to envision a future where people could have an expert AI assistant by their side, through a phone or glasses. And some of these capabilities are coming to Google products, like the Gemini app and web experience, later this year.We’ve made incredible progress so far with our family of Gemini models, and we’re always striving to advance the state-of-the-art even further. By investing in a relentless production line of innovation, we’re able to explore new ideas at the frontier, while also unlocking the possibility of new and exciting Gemini use cases.Learn more about Gemini and its capabilities. Your information will be used in accordance with Google’s privacy policy.</p> <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>      Done. Just one step more.
    
      Check your inbox to confirm your subscription.
    You are already subscribed to our newsletter.
    You can also subscribe with a
    different email address
    
    .
    
  Let’s stay in touch. Get the latest news from Google in your inbox.
          Follow Us
</code></pre></div></div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re sharing updates across our Gemini family of models and a glimpse of Project Astra, our vision for the future of AI assistants.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Displaying External Posts on Your al-folio Blog</title><link href="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Displaying External Posts on Your al-folio Blog"/><published>2022-04-23T19:20:09-04:00</published><updated>2022-04-23T19:20:09-04:00</updated><id>https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog/"><![CDATA[<h3>External Posts on Your al-folio Blog</h3> <p>If you prefer publishing blog posts on medium.com or other external sources, starting version v0.5.0, <a href="https://github.com/alshedivat/al-folio">al-folio</a> lets you to display your external posts in the blog feed of your website! 🎉🎉</p> <p>Configuring external sources of super simple. After upgrading to v0.5.0, just add the following section to your _config.yml:</p> <pre>external_sources:<br />  - name: medium.com  # name of the source (arbitrary string)<br />    rss_url: <a href="https://medium.com/@al-folio/feed">https://medium.com/@&lt;your-medium-username&gt;/feed</a></pre> <p>The example above adds your medium.com blog post feed as an external source. But you can add arbitrary RSS feeds as sources.</p> <p>Any questions or suggestions? 👉 Start <a href="https://github.com/alshedivat/al-folio/discussions">a discussion on GitHub</a>!</p> <p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&amp;referrerSource=full_rss&amp;postId=b60a1d241a0a" width="1" height="1" alt=""/></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html">a post with TikZJax</title><link href="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2010/tikzjax/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="a post with TikZJax"/><published>2010-12-12T17:25:00-05:00</published><updated>2010-12-12T17:25:00-05:00</updated><id>https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2010/tikzjax</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2010/tikzjax/"><![CDATA[<p>This is an example post with TikZ code. TikZJax converts script tags (containing TikZ code) into SVGs.</p> <script type="text/tikz">
\begin{tikzpicture}
    \draw[red,fill=black!60!red] (0,0) circle [radius=1.5];
    \draw[green,fill=black!60!green] (0,0) circle [x radius=1.5cm, y radius=10mm];
    \draw[blue,fill=black!60!blue] (0,0) circle [x radius=1cm, y radius=5mm, rotate=30];
\end{tikzpicture}
</script>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="formatting"/><category term="diagrams"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[this is what included TikZ code could look like]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">a post with giscus comments</title><link href="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2010/giscus-comments/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="a post with giscus comments"/><published>2010-12-10T10:59:00-05:00</published><updated>2010-12-10T10:59:00-05:00</updated><id>https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2010/giscus-comments</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2010/giscus-comments/"><![CDATA[<p>This post shows how to add GISCUS comments.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="external-services"/><category term="comments"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[an example of a blog post with giscus comments]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">a post with disqus comments</title><link href="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2010/disqus-comments/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="a post with disqus comments"/><published>2010-10-20T11:59:00-04:00</published><updated>2010-10-20T11:59:00-04:00</updated><id>https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2010/disqus-comments</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2010/disqus-comments/"><![CDATA[<p>This post shows how to add DISQUS comments.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="external-services"/><category term="comments"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[an example of a blog post with disqus comments]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">a post with math</title><link href="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2010/math/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="a post with math"/><published>2010-10-20T11:12:00-04:00</published><updated>2010-10-20T11:12:00-04:00</updated><id>https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2010/math</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2010/math/"><![CDATA[<p>This theme supports rendering beautiful math in inline and display modes using <a href="https://www.mathjax.org/">MathJax 3</a> engine. You just need to surround your math expression with <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">$$</code>, like <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">$$ E = mc^2 $$</code>. If you leave it inside a paragraph, it will produce an inline expression, just like \(E = mc^2\).</p> <p>To use display mode, again surround your expression with <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">$$</code> and place it as a separate paragraph. Here is an example:</p> \[\sum_{k=1}^\infty |\langle x, e_k \rangle|^2 \leq \|x\|^2\] <p>You can also use <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">\begin{equation}...\end{equation}</code> instead of <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">$$</code> for display mode math. MathJax will automatically number equations:</p> <p>\begin{equation} \label{eq:cauchy-schwarz} \left( \sum<em>{k=1}^n a_k b_k \right)^2 \leq \left( \sum</em>{k=1}^n a<em>k^2 \right) \left( \sum</em>{k=1}^n b_k^2 \right) \end{equation}</p> <p>and by adding <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">\label{...}</code> inside the equation environment, we can now refer to the equation using <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">\eqref</code>.</p> <p>Note that MathJax 3 is <a href="https://docs.mathjax.org/en/latest/upgrading/whats-new-3.0.html">a major re-write of MathJax</a> that brought a significant improvement to the loading and rendering speed, which is now <a href="http://www.intmath.com/cg5/katex-mathjax-comparison.php">on par with KaTeX</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="formatting"/><category term="math"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[an example of a blog post with some math]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">a post with image galleries</title><link href="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2010/photo-gallery/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="a post with image galleries"/><published>2010-10-03T21:59:00-04:00</published><updated>2010-10-03T21:59:00-04:00</updated><id>https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2010/photo-gallery</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2010/photo-gallery/"><![CDATA[<p>The images in this post are all zoomable, arranged into different mini-galleries using different libraries.</p> <h2 id="lightbox2"><a href="https://lokeshdhakar.com/projects/lightbox2/">Lightbox2</a></h2> <p><a href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/1/img-2500.jpg" data-lightbox="roadtrip"><img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/1/img-200.jpg"/></a> <a href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/2/img-2500.jpg" data-lightbox="roadtrip"><img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/2/img-200.jpg"/></a> <a href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/3/img-2500.jpg" data-lightbox="roadtrip"><img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/3/img-200.jpg"/></a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="photoswipe"><a href="https://photoswipe.com/">PhotoSwipe</a></h2> <div class="pswp-gallery pswp-gallery--single-column" id="gallery--getting-started"> <a href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/2/img-2500.jpg" data-pswp-width="1669" data-pswp-height="2500" target="_blank"> <img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/2/img-200.jpg" alt=""/> </a> <a href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/7/img-2500.jpg" data-pswp-width="1875" data-pswp-height="2500" data-cropped="true" target="_blank"> <img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/7/img-200.jpg" alt=""/> </a> <a href="https://unsplash.com" data-pswp-src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/3/img-2500.jpg" data-pswp-width="2500" data-pswp-height="1666" target="_blank"> <img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/3/img-200.jpg" alt=""/> </a> <div> <a href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/6/img-2500.jpg" data-pswp-width="2500" data-pswp-height="1667" target="_blank"> <img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/6/img-200.jpg" alt=""/> </a> </div> </div> <hr/> <h2 id="spotlight-js"><a href="https://nextapps-de.github.io/spotlight/">Spotlight JS</a></h2> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/1/img-2500.jpg"> <img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/1/img-200.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/2/img-2500.jpg"> <img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/2/img-200.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/3/img-2500.jpg"> <img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/3/img-200.jpg"/> </a> </div> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/4/img-2500.jpg"> <img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/4/img-200.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/5/img-2500.jpg"> <img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/5/img-200.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/6/img-2500.jpg"> <img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/6/img-200.jpg"/> </a> </div> <hr/> <h2 id="venobox"><a href="https://veno.es/venobox/">Venobox</a></h2> <p><a class="venobox" data-gall="myGallery" href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/1/img-2500.jpg"><img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/1/img-200.jpg"/></a> <a class="venobox" data-gall="myGallery" href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/2/img-2500.jpg"><img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/2/img-200.jpg"/></a> <a class="venobox" data-gall="myGallery" href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/3/img-2500.jpg"><img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/3/img-200.jpg"/></a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="formatting"/><category term="images"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[this is what included image galleries could look like]]></summary></entry></feed>