<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://imtheva.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://imtheva.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2026-01-09T22:16:42-05:00</updated><id>https://imtheva.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>Personal website of Thevathayarajh Thayananthan — research, projects, publications, and writing on science, engineering, and space. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">From Science Fiction to Farmland: Why Robotics &amp;amp; AI Are Inevitable in Agriculture</title><link href="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2026/robotics-ai-agriculture/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="From Science Fiction to Farmland: Why Robotics &amp;amp; AI Are Inevitable in Agriculture"/><published>2026-01-09T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2026-01-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2026/robotics-ai-agriculture</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2026/robotics-ai-agriculture/"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="external-services"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[My first Medium article on why robotics & AI are becoming inevitable in agriculture.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">MIS</title><link href="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2025/MSc/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MIS"/><published>2025-12-27T19:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-12-27T19:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2025/MSc</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2025/MSc/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="project-overview">Project Overview</h2> <p>Several medical devices can directly analyze a patient’s medical condition; however, the physical presence of non-critical patients places a significant burden on hospital infrastructure, particularly bed availability. This issue becomes more critical during movement-restricted situations such as the COVID-19 pandemic.</p> <p>This project presents a <strong>budget-friendly, IoT-based distanced health monitoring system</strong> that enables continuous monitoring of non-critical patients without requiring physical hospital visits. The system provides real-time access to medical data for patients, caretakers, and doctors through a secure web application.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="system-architecture-and-methodology">System Architecture and Methodology</h2> <div class="row justify-content-sm-center"> <div class="col-sm-10 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/projects/project_1/Methods-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/Methods-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/Methods-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/projects/project_1/Methods.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" title="System Architecture of IoT-Based Health Monitoring System" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Overall system architecture showing patient-side sensing, Raspberry Pi-based processing, Firebase Firestore cloud storage, and web application access for patients, caretakers, and doctors. </div> <p>The system collects physiological data from patients using sensors connected to a <strong>Raspberry Pi</strong>. The processed data are transmitted securely to <strong>Firebase Firestore</strong>, enabling near real-time synchronization with the Medical Instrumentation System (MIS) web application.</p> <p>The web interface allows:</p> <ul> <li>Patients and caretakers to monitor real-time health parameters and danger levels</li> <li>Doctors to review medical history and provide prescriptions and feedback remotely</li> </ul> <hr/> <h2 id="scope-and-objectives">Scope and Objectives</h2> <ul> <li>Develop an <strong>IoT-based system</strong> for monitoring patient health</li> <li>Monitor <strong>physiological parameters and lifestyle indicators</strong></li> <li>Design a <strong>portable device</strong> suitable for continuous patient use</li> <li>Enable scalability for <strong>multiple patients and doctors</strong></li> </ul> <hr/> <h2 id="results-and-discussion">Results and Discussion</h2> <div class="row justify-content-sm-center"> <div class="col-sm-10 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/projects/project_1/R2-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/R2-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/R2-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/projects/project_1/R2.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" title="R2" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="row"> <div class="col-sm-6 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/projects/project_1/R1-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/R1-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/R1-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/projects/project_1/R1.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" title="R1" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm-6 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/projects/project_1/R4-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/R4-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/R4-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/projects/project_1/R4.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> IoT device for collecting physiological data and transmitting it to Firebase Firestore for real-time visualization. </div> <p>The developed Medical Instrumentation System (MIS) demonstrated that IoT-based distanced patient monitoring is feasible for non-critical cases.</p> <p>Key outcomes include:</p> <ul> <li>End-to-end data synchronization (device → Firestore → MIS page) within <strong>1–2 seconds</strong></li> <li>Patients and caretakers can view medical data, danger levels, and follow doctor prescriptions</li> <li>Secure storage of patient medical history enables informed clinical decision-making</li> </ul> <p>This study incorporates patient basic details to prioritize medical history, an aspect not widely explored in related works. Additionally, the system supports doctor prescriptions and feedback, which are absent in many existing solutions.</p> <p>Firestore allows up to <strong>1 MB of data per document</strong>, indicating the need for a dedicated database server during large-scale commercialization. An SMS gateway can be integrated for OTP-based authentication to enhance system security.</p> <div class="row"> <div class="col-sm-6 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/projects/project_1/D1-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/D1-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/D1-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/projects/project_1/D1.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" title="Doctor Dashboard" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm-6 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/projects/project_1/D2-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/D2-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/D2-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/projects/project_1/D2.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" title="Patient View" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="row justify-content-sm-center"> <div class="col-sm-10 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/projects/project_1/D3-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/D3-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/D3-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/projects/project_1/D3.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" title="Medical History and Graphs" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Web application interface showing doctor dashboard, patient view, and medical history visualization. </div> <hr/> <h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2> <p>This project demonstrates a feasible and scalable approach to implementing an <strong>IoT-based distanced health monitoring system</strong>. The MIS web application successfully displays medical data received from distributed devices and supports interactions among multiple patients, caretakers, and doctors.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="future-directions">Future Directions</h2> <ul> <li>Integrate additional medical devices and sensors based on specific health conditions</li> <li>Incorporate <strong>Machine Learning/Deep Learning</strong> models for early warning prediction</li> <li>Enhance security using <strong>SMS-based OTP authentication</strong></li> </ul> <hr/> <h2 id="live-demo">Live Demo</h2> <p>🔗 <strong>Web Application:</strong> <a href="https://rasp-med.web.app/">https://rasp-med.web.app/</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="references">References</h2> <ol> <li>V. Vippalapalli and S. Ananthula, “Internet of things (IoT) based smart health care system,” <em>SCOPES 2016</em>, 2017.</li> <li>S. Pinto, J. Cabral, and T. Gomes, “We-Care: An IoT-based Health Care System for Elderly People.”</li> <li>V. Tamilselvi et al., “IoT Based Health Monitoring System,” <em>ICACCS 2020</em>, 2020.</li> <li>S. Rajkumar et al., “Health monitoring system using Raspberry Pi,” <em>BID 2017</em>, 2018.</li> <li>M. Hamim et al., “IoT Based remote health monitoring system,” <em>ICREST 2019</em>, 2019.</li> <li>V. Pardeshi et al., “Health monitoring systems using IoT and Raspberry Pi – A review,” <em>ICIMIA 2017</em>, 2017.</li> </ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="Project"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A cost-effective remote health monitoring solution designed to continuously assess non-critical patients while reducing hospital congestion—especially during emergencies such as the COVID-19 pandemic.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">(PDF) Making Threads in SolidWorks</title><link href="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2025/pdf-making-threads-in-solidworks/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="(PDF) Making Threads in SolidWorks"/><published>2025-12-21T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-12-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2025/pdf-making-threads-in-solidworks</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2025/pdf-making-threads-in-solidworks/"><![CDATA[<p>OutlineDownload Free PDF…7 pagesComputer-Aided Design of Traditional Jigs and Fixtures, 2021Conventional design of jigs and fixtures has become unsuitable given the requirements of modern technology and complexity and diversity in the production with the rapid update of products. Computer-aided design (CAD) of jigs and fixtures is an effective solution in this direction. The current paper focuses on a computer-aided design of the traditional jigs and fixtures and developed a system containing tailor-made software, created using the Visual Basic programming language and installed on it the viewer screen to show the part. The developed system has been built by connecting Visual Basic programming language to the SolidWorks software on which the part is drawn and saved as STEP AP-203 file format, and the system reads and extracts the data from the STEP AP-203 file. Heuristic rules of feature recognition are pre-prepared for checking the extracted geometric data and deciding which data shape will represent the machining feature; then, the system provides the optimum design of the traditional jigs and fixtures for a group of hollow cylindrical parts that contain a group of cross-holes on the cylinder body, whether perpendicular or offset from the cylinder’s axis, (inclined or inclined offset, or blind or through, by applying pre-prepared heuristic rules for the design of traditional jigs and fixtures.2023 IEEE 17th International Symposium on Applied Computational Intelligence and Informatics (SACI), 2023In this paper, a carpenter software is designed and implemented that supports the daily management processes (customers, orders, inventory) and generates a pattern from the product descriptions based on the parameters specified. During the pattern generation process, a two-dimensional optimization is performed to generate a pattern that includes horizontal or vertical cuts, depending on the target machine, on which the position of the required parts is placed, generates the smallest material loss and uses leftover materials from the past. From the application, the pattern can be viewed and extracted online or in PDF format. This all is implemented in a layered web application with a modern approach.THREE DIMENSIONAL MODELING AND LOADING SIMULATION OF A STANDARD THREADED FASTENER IN CAD ENVIRONMENT (ТРИМЕРНО МОДЕЛИРАНЕ И СИМУЛАЦИОННО НАТОВАРВАНЕ В CAD-СРЕДА KНА СТАНДАРТНО РЕЗБОВО СЪЕДИНЕНИЕ ), 2006Abstract. The techniques of correct three dimensional modeling of geometry parameters of thread and of the body of standard threaded fasteners (bolt and nut) in CAD environment of software product SolidWoprks’2005 are presented. The model of joint are put under loading simulation and the zones of concentrations of stresses are determined. The values and distribution of stresses from loading simulation and from calculation and from experiments known from literature are compared. Key words: threaded fasteners, CAD, finite element method.This paper presents a mechanistic model for prediction of the thread milling forces. The mechanics of cutting for thread milling is analyzed similar to the end milling process but with modified cutting edge geometry. The chip thickness and cutting force models are developed considering the unique geometry of the tool. The model has been calibrated for 6061 Aluminum and validated. The effects of tool and thread geometry have been studied using the model. rZenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research), 2012Modular fixtures (MFs) are very important tools in manufacturing processes in terms of reduction the cost and the production time. This paper introduces an automated approach for assembling MFs elements by employing SolidWorks as a powerful 3D CAD software. Visual Basic (VB) programming language was applied integrating with SolidWorks API (Application programming interface) functions. This integration allowed creating plug-in file and generating new menus in the SolidWorks environment. The menus allow the user to select, insert, and assemble MFs elements.2014Background: The accuracy of cup placement in navigated total hip arthroplasty (THA) depends on the bony landmark registration intraoperatively. We created a semilateral decubitus position that combined the advantage of supine position for registration and lateral decubitus position for better femoral canal visualization. Objective: To evaluate the accuracy of cup placement within the “safe zone” and of imageless navigation measurement by comparing the intraoperative values of acetabular cup abduction and anteversion to postoperative CT values. Material and Method: All cases were performed in semilateral decubitus position with OrthoPilot THA plus 3.2 (cup only) software (Aesculap AG). Postoperatively, a multislice computed tomographic (CT) scan was obtained at two months or later for abduction and anteversion angle measurement. The abduction and anteversion angle measured on postoperative CT were compared to the intraoperative measurement with a paired t-test and a correlation test …Springer eBooks, 1998Journal of X-ray Science and Technology, 2012For finite detector and focal spot sizes, here we propose a projection model for high spatial resolution. First, for a given x-ray source point, a projection datum is modeled as an area integral over a narrow fan-beam connecting the detector elemental borders and the x-ray source point. Then, the final projection value is expressed as the integral obtained in the first step over the whole focal spot support. An ordered-subset simultaneous algebraic reconstruction technique (OS-SART) is developed using the proposed projection model. In the numerical simulation, our method produces improved spatial resolution and suppresses high-frequency artifacts.2013Bibliografía recomendada para el Tema: 3.5.-Sólidos Moleculares. Fuerzas intermoleculares. Fuerzas de van der Waals. Enlace de hidrógeno. Estructura de los sólidos moleculares.2014Silicon nanoparticles (SiNPs) hold prominent interest in various aspects of biomedical applications. For this purpose, surface functionalization of the NPs is essential to stabilize them. A facile method is reported here to synthesize highly stable and brightly luminescent amine-terminated SiNPs. The diameter of the crystal cores is 4.6 nm. The NPs emit strong blue-green photoluminescence (PL) at peak position 460 nm with quantum yield (QY) 22%. The NPs exhibited an exceptional stability over a wide pH range (4−14) and are resistant to aging over several weeks. For SiNPs to target specific disease area, and allow them to selectively bind to the cells or the bio-molecules present on the surface of the cells, carbohydrate capped SiNPs were synthesized. However, no such functionalization has been explored with SiNPs. In this study, we report the first synthesis of SiNPs functionalized with carbohydrates (Galactose, Mannose, Glucose and Lactose). The NPs show blue-green luminescence in …Still studying.Procedia Manufacturing, 2015The modulated tool path (MTP) chip breaking process has been modified to improve chip management capabilities and to prevent large chip nest accumulations commonly encountered in threading operations. The use of MTP to create segmented chips requires a different approach for threading operations than for normal MTP turning operations, although the fundamental principal is the same. The primary difference between MTP for threading and for straight turning is that the part surface that the tool repeatedly engages and disengages, during the modulation process, is the thread root rather than the cut face. The threading MTP part program developed in this paper is capable of machining a thread with the desired lead, depth, undercut angle, and taper angle while also producing segmented chips.International Journal of …, 2006This paper presents a mechanistic model for prediction of the thread milling forces. The mechanics of cutting for thread milling is analyzed similar to the end milling process but with modified cutting edge geometry. The chip thickness and cutting force models are developed considering the unique geometry of the tool. The model has been calibrated for 6061 Aluminum and validated. The effects of tool and thread geometry have been studied using the model. rVariations in cutting forces were investigated experimentally depending on infeed angles and cutting areas in the external threading on a CNC turning centre. For this purpose, AISI 1050 workpiece material, 16ERM AG 60 IC 908 cutting tool, and SER 2525 M16 tool holder were used. External threading operations were performed using 0 • , 14.5 • , 15 • , 27.5 • , and 30 • infeed angles while the cutting speed was held constant at 100 m/min for the experiments. Experimental results showed that the infeed angle and cutting area had significant effects on the main cutting force and the radial force components were considerable in threading operations in terms of energy consumption. In addition, the optimum infeed angle was 30 • in the external threading operations in terms of cutting forces.Acta Polytechnica Hungarica, 2014Different tool geometries have been developed by leading companies in the tool industry to different aims of application. The fastest progress can be observed in the development of coatings, in spite of this it can be noticed that there are only few coating types, but they can be used in a wide range. For users it offers the great advantage to select appropriate tool easier. Coating types, developed specially to individual aim of application, offer much better solution, compared to the generally used coating types. Platit AG, dealing with the development of optimised coating types, has requested our specialised group to carry out tests on specialised coating types. Our present study is going to summarise the results of the tests, carried out with thread forming tools.The International Journal of Advanced Manufacturing Technology, 2014is an open access repository that collects the work of Arts et Métiers ParisTech researchers and makes it freely available over the web where possible. This is an author-deposited version published in: http://sam.ensam.eu Handle ID: .http://hdl.handle.net/10985/8565 To cite this version : Vishal SHARMA, Guillaume FROMENTIN, Gérard POULACHON, Romain BRENDLEN -Investigation of tool geometry effect and penetration strategies on cutting forces during thread milling2010Aún recuerdo aquellos días en los que miraba los tablones de la Facultad de Químicas buscando una oportunidad para investigar. El destino quiso que terminase estudiando la grasa láctea y, pese a los momentos duros, no puedo estar más que agradecida por las coordenadas en las que ha transcurrido este trabajo. En primer lugar, quiero agradecer a mis directores de tesis, la Dra. Manuela Juárez y el Dr. Miguel Ángel de la Fuente, el darme la oportunidad de dedicarme a lo que siempre quise hacer y su inestimable ayuda. No creo que haya muchos “jefes” que se impliquen tanto… La curiosidad por los resultados de cada experimento, la pasión que demuestran en su trabajo, serán siempre mis modelos científicos. Muchas gracias, Manoli, por trabajar intensamente en esta tesis a pesar de todos tus compromisos, por leerte mi Introducción en el AVE en vez de dar una cabezada, y especialmente, por tu apoyo personal en momentos clave. ¡Y qué decirle a Miguel Ángel! Gracias por meter prisa, por tus correcciones cervantinas, por los planning difíciles de cumplir, por tu compromiso, por las cañas en Delias… Con el tiempo, creo que hemos formado un buen tándem. Espero que no se te hayan quitado las ganas de dirigir otra tesis y que otros becarios aprendan como yo a tu lado.New Covenant Publications International Ltd, 2020New Covenant Publications International Ltd. , 2020Tanan nga mga katungod gigahin. Wala’y bahin sa kini nga libro ang mahimong kopyahon o ipadala sa bisan unsang porma o sa bisan unsang paagi bisan kung wala ang tin-aw nga sinulat nga pagtugot gikan sa tagsulat, gawas sa kaso sa mubo nga mga kinutlo nga nahisulat sa mga kritikal nga artikulo ug mga pagsusi. Palihug tan-awa ang tanan nga hinungdanon nga mga pangutana sa nagpamantala. Tanan nga mga katungod gigahin. Wala’y bahin sa kini nga libro ang mahimo nga kopyahon o ipadala sa bisan unsang porma o sa bisan unsang paagi, electronic o mekanikal, lakip ang pag-photocopying, pagrekord, o sa usa ka sistema sa pagtipig ug pagkuha sa impormasyon -gawas sa usa ka tigtuon nga mahimong mokutlo sa mubo nga mga tudling sa usa ka pagsusi nga mahimo’g gipatik sa usa ka magasin o pamantalaannga wala’y pagtugot sa pagsulat gikan sa nagpatik.Gigantes del pensamiento y la acción: Fidel Castro Ruz, 2025Dedicatoria: Dedico la presente obra a mi esposa María M. Alberdi Bardina y a las familias españolas que viajaron a Cuba en misión solidaria desde los primeros años del triunfo de la presente etapa del proceso revolucionario cubano y muy especialmente a las que formaron parte de la Sociedad de Amistad Cubano-Española (SACE). Así mismo dedico el libro a mis compañeras y compañerosJurnal Ilmiah Literasi Indonesia, 2026Penelitian ini untuk mengetahui Pengaruh Penggunaan Teknologi Pembelajaran Terhadap Motivasi Belajar Mahasiswa. Penelitian ini menggunakan pendekatan kuantitatif dengan desain penelitian kausal (asosiatif). Penelitian ini dilakukan di jurusan Pendidikan Ekonomi Fakultas Keguruan Dan Ilmu Pendidikan Universitas Halu Oleo, dengan kuesioner yang dibagikan kepada mahasiswa yang secara aktif menggunakan Menggunakan Teknologi Pembelajaran (seperti sistem E-Learning, alat kecerdasan buatan, atau media interaktif) dalam kegiatan belajar mandiri dan kuliah. Berdasarkan hasil analisis data dan pembahasan yang telah dilakukan dalam penelitian ini, Penggunaan teknologi pembelajaran memiliki dampak positif dan signifikan terhadap motivasi belajar siswa. Hal ini dibuktikan oleh hasil uji t, yang menunjukkan nilai signifikansi 0.000 (Sig. &lt; 0.05), sehingga menerima hipotesis alternatif (Ha).Arah pengaruh yang positif (koefisien regresi b = 0.75) menunjukkan bahwa semakin tinggi intensitas dan kualitas penggunaan teknologi, semakin tinggi pula motivasi belajar Mahasiswa.Besar kontribusi Penggunaan Teknologi Pembelajaran terhadap Motivasi Belajar adalah sebesar 46,2%. Angka ini diperoleh dari Koefisien Determinasi (R²) sebesar 0,462. Kontribusi ini menegaskan bahwa teknologi digital merupakan prediktor yang kuat dan signifikan dalam meningkatkan antusiasme dan motivasi belajar mahasiwa.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Making Threads in SolidWorks]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">(PDF) Measuring Pen – A digital device to measure distance</title><link href="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2025/pdf-measuring-pen-a-digital-device-to-measure-distance/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="(PDF) Measuring Pen – A digital device to measure distance"/><published>2025-12-20T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-12-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2025/pdf-measuring-pen--a-digital-device-to-measure-distance</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2025/pdf-measuring-pen-a-digital-device-to-measure-distance/"><![CDATA[<p>OutlineDownload Free PDF…3 pagesThis is a new approach on the section of measurement. Today, most of the garment companies are producing lot of clothes. While producing clothes they have to face lot of problems. For an example time of delivery and accuracy in clothes size. A traditional way of measuring a cloth is using a tape. Due to that there may be errors in measuring length and it take times time to check the length using tape. Main aim of this mini project is to solve these problems using a microcontroller measuring system. This will reduce the time taken for the cutting and will measure accurately. For this project Arduino Nano is used as the microcontroller for performing the algorithmic work.European Journal of Cancer, 2009Clinical Cancer Research, 2010Purpose: To test the hypothesis that simultaneous, equipotent inhibition of epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR; erbB1), erbB2 (human epidermal growth factor receptor 2), and erbB3 receptor signaling, using the novel small-molecule inhibitor AZD8931, will deliver broad antitumor activity in vitro and in vivo. Experimental Design: A range of assays was used to model erbB family receptor signaling in homodimers and heterodimers, including in vitro evaluation of erbB kinase activity, erbB receptor phosphorylation, proliferation in cells, and in vivo testing in a human tumor xenograft panel, with ex vivo evaluation of erbB phosphorylation and downstream biomarkers. Gefitinib and lapatinib were used to compare the pharmacological profile of AZD8931 with other erbB family inhibitors. Results: In vitro, AZD8931 showed equipotent, reversible inhibition of EGFR (IC50, 4 nmol/L), erbB2 (IC50, 3 nmol/L), and erbB3 (IC50, 4 nmol/L) phosphorylation in cells. In proliferation assays, AZD8931 w…Springer eBooks, 2017The use of general descriptive names, registered names, trademarks, service marks, etc. in this publication does not imply, even in the absence of a specific statement, that such names are exempt from the relevant protective laws and regulations and therefore free for general use. The publisher, the authors and the editors are safe to assume that the advice and information in this book are believed to be true and accurate at the date of publication. Neither the publisher nor the authors or the editors give a warranty, express or implied, with respect to the material contained herein or for any errors or omissions that may have been made. The publisher remains neutral with regard to jurisdictional claims in published maps and institutional affiliations.1996Bibliotekarz Podlaski, 2020The present study aims to analyze several aspects of economic migration from Ukraine to Poland in the context of the last 10 years (2007-2017). It looks at how changes in migration policy in Poland and the EU impacted the dynamics of migration to Poland, which has been for a long time one of the most popular destinations for Ukrainians. In 2014, an increased number of Ukrainians migrating to Russia was observed, although no similar increase was recorded for EU countries (excluding Poland). In 2014, Polish consular services issued over 556,500 visas to Ukrainian citizens. Since 15 September 2012, Ukrainians no longer have to pay for national visas if they intend to stay in Poland for 3 months to 1 year. Since July 2009, the Agreement on Local Border Traffic between Poland and Ukraine has been in force. Based on this agreement, Ukrainian nationals residing in the border zone -the area extending 30 km from the border -do not need visas, only local border traffic permits entitling them to multiple crossings of the Polish border.Oncotarget, 2016Melanoma is a particularly virulent human cancer, due to its resistance to conventional treatments and high frequency of metastasis. Melanomas contain a fraction of cells, the melanoma-initiating cells (MICs), responsible for tumor propagation and relapse. Identification of the molecular pathways supporting MICs is, therefore, vital for the development of targeted treatments. One factor produced by melanoma cells and their microenvironment, insulin-like growth factor-1 (IGF- 1), is linked to epithelial-mesenchymal transition (EMT) and stemness features in several cancers.We evaluated the effect of IGF-1 on the phenotype and chemoresistance of B16-F10 cells. IGF-1 inhibition in these cells prevented malignant cell proliferation, migration and invasion, and lung colony formation in immunodeficient mice. IGF-1 downregulation also markedly inhibited EMT, with low levels of ZEB1 and mesenchymal markers (N-cadherin, CD44, CD29, CD105) associated with high levels of E-cadherin and MITF, th…— This paper deals with the design and implementation of a simple HMC6352 2-axis digital compass. Most compasses have been of the analogue type with magnetic needles as pointers. Replacing the “ old “ magnetic needle compass or the gyrocompass by an electronic solution offers advantages like having a solid-state component without moving parts and the ease of interfacing with other electronic systems. In this work, the aim is to design and implement a digital compass. To realize this, we made use of HMC6352 which is a 2-axis MR (magneto-resistive) sensor from Honeywell, Arduino Uno board with an onboard ATmega328 microcontroller chip, and a 16x2 character Liquid Crystal Display (LCD).We adopted the magneto-resistive (MR) technology as compared to flux-gate sensors common in most electronic compasses which has the disadvantage of making the device bulky. The trial test carried out with the completed HMC6352 digital compass showed a reading of 232.8 degrees West indicating its effectiveness in direction finding.นักเรียนโรงเรียนคณะราษฎรบำรุง ๒ ส่วนใหญ่เมื่อเรียนจบการศึกษาระดับมัธยมศึกษาจะขาดแรงจูงใจที่จะเข้าศึกษาต่อในระดับมหาวิทยาลัย ดังนั้นนักเรียนจึงมีความสนใจในการเรียนวิชาวิทยาศาสตรน์ อ้ ยมาก และวิชาเคมีเปน็ วิชาหนึ่งที่นักเรียนมีผลสัมฤทธิ์ต่ำ การศึกษาวิจัยในครั้งนี้มุง่ พัฒนาทั้งความเข้าใจเรื่องกรด-เบส และวิธีการทางวิทยาศาสตร์ควบคู่กัน โดยการจัดการเรียนรู้แบบร่วมมือร่วมกับโครงงานวิทยาศาสตร์ เป็นเวลา 20 ชั่วโมง กลุ่มเป้าหมายเป็นนักเรียนชั้น ม.5/1 โรงเรียนคณะราษฎรบำรุง ๒ ปีการศึกษา 2553 จำนวน 18 คน เครื่องมือที่ใช้ในการรวบรวมข้อมูลประกอบด้วยแบบทดสอบวัดผลสัมฤทธิ์แบบ 4 ตัวเลือก เรื่อง กรด-เบส แบบประเมินวิธีการทางวิทยาศาสตร์ในระหว่างการทำโครงงานวิทยาศาสตร์ และแบบประเมินโครงงานวิทยาศาสตร์โดยรวม ผลการวิจัยพบว่า นักเรียนได้คะแนนผลสัมฤทธิ์หลังเรียน (ค่าเฉลี่ย 16.78 และส่วนเบี่ยงเบนมาตรฐาน 2.46 ) สูงกว่าก่อนเรียน (ค่าเฉลี่ย 7.56 และส่วนเบี่ยงเบนมาตรฐาน 1.12 ) แตกต่างกันอย่างมีนัยสำคัญทางสถิติที่ระดับค่า p น้อยกว่า 0.05 โดยมีคะแนนความก้าวหน้าเป็น 9.22 หรือคิดเป็น 28.82 % ส่วนคะแนนวิธีการทางวิทยาศาสตร์ระหว่างการทำโครงงานและคะแนนโครงงานวิทยาศาสตร์โดยรวมมีค่าเฉลี่ยเป็น 72.52 % และ 71.64 % ตามลำดับอยู่ในระดับดี แสดงว่า การจัดการเรียนรู้แบบร่วมมือร่วมกับโครงงานวิทยาศาสตร์เป็นปัจจัยสำคัญในการเพิ่มความเข้าใจและเสริมวิธีการทางวิทยาศาสตร์ของนักเรียนJournal of Tourism, Hotels and HeritageInternational Journal of Finance &amp; Banking Studies (2147-4486), 2016The paper employed a two-stage Data Envelopment Analysis (DEA) approach to examine the sources of technical efficiency in the Nigerian banking sub-sector. Using a cross section of commercial and merchant banks, the study showed that the Nigerian banking industry was not efficient both in the pre-and-post-liberalization era. The study further revealed that market share was the strongest determinant of technical efficiency in the Nigerian banking Industry. Thus, appropriate macroeconomic policy, institutional development and structural reforms must accompany financial liberalization to create the stable environment required for it to succeed. Hence, the present bank consolidation and reforms by the Central Bank of Nigeria, which started with Soludo and continued with Sanusi, are considered necessary, especially in the areas of e banking and reorganizing the management of banks.1989Я верю, что практика такого рода отчетности за совершенные Тайны Пресвятого Розария воспитает уважительное отношение к Непорочному Сердцу Марии, осуществит профилактику оскорблений в Ее Адрес и поможет вместе с помощью Священноначалия выявить и раскрыть Призвания от Бога Отца в нашей Святой Католической Церкви.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is a new approach on the section of measurement. Today, most of the garment companies are producing lot of clothes. While producing clothes they have to face lot of problems. For an example time of delivery and accuracy in clothes size. A]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Google Gemini updates: Flash 1.5, Gemma 2 and Project Astra</title><link href="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2024/google-gemini-updates-flash-15-gemma-2-and-project-astra/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Google Gemini updates: Flash 1.5, Gemma 2 and Project Astra"/><published>2024-05-14T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-05-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2024/google-gemini-updates-flash-15-gemma-2-and-project-astra</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2024/google-gemini-updates-flash-15-gemma-2-and-project-astra/"><![CDATA[<p>May 14, 2024 We’re introducing a series of updates across the Gemini family of models, including the new 1.5 Flash, our lightweight model for speed and efficiency, and Project Astra, our vision for the future of AI assistants. In December, we launched our first natively multimodal model Gemini 1.0 in three sizes: Ultra, Pro and Nano. Just a few months later we released 1.5 Pro, with enhanced performance and a breakthrough long context window of 1 million tokens.Developers and enterprise customers have been putting 1.5 Pro to use in incredible ways and finding its long context window, multimodal reasoning capabilities and impressive overall performance incredibly useful.We know from user feedback that some applications need lower latency and a lower cost to serve. This inspired us to keep innovating, so today, we’re introducing Gemini 1.5 Flash: a model that’s lighter-weight than 1.5 Pro, and designed to be fast and efficient to serve at scale.Both 1.5 Pro and 1.5 Flash are available in public preview with a 1 million token context window in Google AI Studio and Vertex AI. And now, 1.5 Pro is also available with a 2 million token context window via waitlist to developers using the API and to Google Cloud customers.We’re also introducing updates across the Gemini family of models, announcing our next generation of open models, Gemma 2, and sharing progress on the future of AI assistants, with Project Astra.Context lengths of leading foundation models compared with Gemini 1.5’s 2 million token capability1.5 Flash is the newest addition to the Gemini model family and the fastest Gemini model served in the API. It’s optimized for high-volume, high-frequency tasks at scale, is more cost-efficient to serve and features our breakthrough long context window.While it’s a lighter weight model than 1.5 Pro, it’s highly capable of multimodal reasoning across vast amounts of information and delivers impressive quality for its size.The new Gemini 1.5 Flash model is optimized for speed and efficiency, is highly capable of multimodal reasoning and features our breakthrough long context window.1.5 Flash excels at summarization, chat applications, image and video captioning, data extraction from long documents and tables, and more. This is because it’s been trained by 1.5 Pro through a process called “distillation,” where the most essential knowledge and skills from a larger model are transferred to a smaller, more efficient model.Read more about 1.5 Flash in our updated Gemini 1.5 technical report, on the Gemini technology page, and learn about 1.5 Flash’s availability and pricing.Over the last few months, we’ve significantly improved 1.5 Pro, our best model for general performance across a wide range of tasks.Beyond extending its context window to 2 million tokens, we’ve enhanced its code generation, logical reasoning and planning, multi-turn conversation, and audio and image understanding through data and algorithmic advances. We see strong improvements on public and internal benchmarks for each of these tasks.1.5 Pro can now follow increasingly complex and nuanced instructions, including ones that specify product-level behavior involving role, format and style. We’ve improved control over the model’s responses for specific use cases, like crafting the persona and response style of a chat agent or automating workflows through multiple function calls. And we’ve enabled users to steer model behavior by setting system instructions.We added audio understanding in the Gemini API and Google AI Studio, so 1.5 Pro can now reason across image and audio for videos uploaded in Google AI Studio. And we’re now integrating 1.5 Pro into Google products, including Gemini Advanced and in Workspace apps.Read more about 1.5 Pro in our updated Gemini 1.5 technical report and on the Gemini technology page.Gemini Nano is expanding beyond text-only inputs to include images as well. Starting with Pixel, applications using Gemini Nano with Multimodality will be able to understand the world the way people do — not just through text, but also through sight, sound and spoken language.Read more about Gemini 1.0 Nano on Android.Today, we’re also sharing a series of updates to Gemma, our family of open models built from the same research and technology used to create the Gemini models.We’re announcing Gemma 2, our next generation of open models for responsible AI innovation. Gemma 2 has a new architecture designed for breakthrough performance and efficiency, and will be available in new sizes.The Gemma family is also expanding with PaliGemma, our first vision-language model inspired by PaLI-3. And we’ve upgraded our Responsible Generative AI Toolkit with LLM Comparator for evaluating the quality of model responses.Read more on the Developer blog.As part of Google DeepMind’s mission to build AI responsibly to benefit humanity, we’ve always wanted to develop universal AI agents that can be helpful in everyday life. That’s why today, we’re sharing our progress in building the future of AI assistants with Project Astra (advanced seeing and talking responsive agent).To be truly useful, an agent needs to understand and respond to the complex and dynamic world just like people do — and take in and remember what it sees and hears to understand context and take action. It also needs to be proactive, teachable and personal, so users can talk to it naturally and without lag or delay.While we’ve made incredible progress developing AI systems that can understand multimodal information, getting response time down to something conversational is a difficult engineering challenge. Over the past few years, we’ve been working to improve how our models perceive, reason and converse to make the pace and quality of interaction feel more natural.Building on Gemini, we’ve developed prototype agents that can process information faster by continuously encoding video frames, combining the video and speech input into a timeline of events, and caching this information for efficient recall.By leveraging our leading speech models, we also enhanced how they sound, giving the agents a wider range of intonations. These agents can better understand the context they’re being used in, and respond quickly, in conversation.With technology like this, it’s easy to envision a future where people could have an expert AI assistant by their side, through a phone or glasses. And some of these capabilities are coming to Google products, like the Gemini app and web experience, later this year.We’ve made incredible progress so far with our family of Gemini models, and we’re always striving to advance the state-of-the-art even further. By investing in a relentless production line of innovation, we’re able to explore new ideas at the frontier, while also unlocking the possibility of new and exciting Gemini use cases.Learn more about Gemini and its capabilities. Your information will be used in accordance with Google’s privacy policy.</p> <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>      Done. Just one step more.
    
      Check your inbox to confirm your subscription.
    You are already subscribed to our newsletter.
    You can also subscribe with a
    different email address
    
    .
    
  Let’s stay in touch. Get the latest news from Google in your inbox.
          Follow Us
</code></pre></div></div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re sharing updates across our Gemini family of models and a glimpse of Project Astra, our vision for the future of AI assistants.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Displaying External Posts on Your al-folio Blog</title><link href="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Displaying External Posts on Your al-folio Blog"/><published>2022-04-23T19:20:09-04:00</published><updated>2022-04-23T19:20:09-04:00</updated><id>https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog/"><![CDATA[<h3>External Posts on Your al-folio Blog</h3> <p>If you prefer publishing blog posts on medium.com or other external sources, starting version v0.5.0, <a href="https://github.com/alshedivat/al-folio">al-folio</a> lets you to display your external posts in the blog feed of your website! 🎉🎉</p> <p>Configuring external sources of super simple. After upgrading to v0.5.0, just add the following section to your _config.yml:</p> <pre>external_sources:<br />  - name: medium.com  # name of the source (arbitrary string)<br />    rss_url: <a href="https://medium.com/@al-folio/feed">https://medium.com/@&lt;your-medium-username&gt;/feed</a></pre> <p>The example above adds your medium.com blog post feed as an external source. But you can add arbitrary RSS feeds as sources.</p> <p>Any questions or suggestions? 👉 Start <a href="https://github.com/alshedivat/al-folio/discussions">a discussion on GitHub</a>!</p> <p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&amp;referrerSource=full_rss&amp;postId=b60a1d241a0a" width="1" height="1" alt=""/></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html">a post with TikZJax</title><link href="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2010/tikzjax/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="a post with TikZJax"/><published>2010-12-12T17:25:00-05:00</published><updated>2010-12-12T17:25:00-05:00</updated><id>https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2010/tikzjax</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2010/tikzjax/"><![CDATA[<p>This is an example post with TikZ code. TikZJax converts script tags (containing TikZ code) into SVGs.</p> <script type="text/tikz">
\begin{tikzpicture}
    \draw[red,fill=black!60!red] (0,0) circle [radius=1.5];
    \draw[green,fill=black!60!green] (0,0) circle [x radius=1.5cm, y radius=10mm];
    \draw[blue,fill=black!60!blue] (0,0) circle [x radius=1cm, y radius=5mm, rotate=30];
\end{tikzpicture}
</script>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="formatting"/><category term="diagrams"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[this is what included TikZ code could look like]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">a post with giscus comments</title><link href="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2010/giscus-comments/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="a post with giscus comments"/><published>2010-12-10T10:59:00-05:00</published><updated>2010-12-10T10:59:00-05:00</updated><id>https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2010/giscus-comments</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2010/giscus-comments/"><![CDATA[<p>This post shows how to add GISCUS comments.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="external-services"/><category term="comments"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[an example of a blog post with giscus comments]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">a post with disqus comments</title><link href="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2010/disqus-comments/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="a post with disqus comments"/><published>2010-10-20T11:59:00-04:00</published><updated>2010-10-20T11:59:00-04:00</updated><id>https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2010/disqus-comments</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2010/disqus-comments/"><![CDATA[<p>This post shows how to add DISQUS comments.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="external-services"/><category term="comments"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[an example of a blog post with disqus comments]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">a post with math</title><link href="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2010/math/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="a post with math"/><published>2010-10-20T11:12:00-04:00</published><updated>2010-10-20T11:12:00-04:00</updated><id>https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2010/math</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2010/math/"><![CDATA[<p>This theme supports rendering beautiful math in inline and display modes using <a href="https://www.mathjax.org/">MathJax 3</a> engine. You just need to surround your math expression with <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">$$</code>, like <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">$$ E = mc^2 $$</code>. If you leave it inside a paragraph, it will produce an inline expression, just like \(E = mc^2\).</p> <p>To use display mode, again surround your expression with <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">$$</code> and place it as a separate paragraph. Here is an example:</p> \[\sum_{k=1}^\infty |\langle x, e_k \rangle|^2 \leq \|x\|^2\] <p>You can also use <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">\begin{equation}...\end{equation}</code> instead of <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">$$</code> for display mode math. MathJax will automatically number equations:</p> <p>\begin{equation} \label{eq:cauchy-schwarz} \left( \sum<em>{k=1}^n a_k b_k \right)^2 \leq \left( \sum</em>{k=1}^n a<em>k^2 \right) \left( \sum</em>{k=1}^n b_k^2 \right) \end{equation}</p> <p>and by adding <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">\label{...}</code> inside the equation environment, we can now refer to the equation using <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">\eqref</code>.</p> <p>Note that MathJax 3 is <a href="https://docs.mathjax.org/en/latest/upgrading/whats-new-3.0.html">a major re-write of MathJax</a> that brought a significant improvement to the loading and rendering speed, which is now <a href="http://www.intmath.com/cg5/katex-mathjax-comparison.php">on par with KaTeX</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="formatting"/><category term="math"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[an example of a blog post with some math]]></summary></entry></feed>