<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://imtheva.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://imtheva.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2026-01-01T01:58:32-05:00</updated><id>https://imtheva.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>Personal website of Thevathayarajh Thayananthan — research, projects, publications, and writing on science, engineering, and space. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">MIS</title><link href="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2025/MSc/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MIS"/><published>2025-12-27T19:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-12-27T19:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2025/MSc</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2025/MSc/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="project-overview">Project Overview</h2> <p>Several medical devices can directly analyze a patient’s medical condition; however, the physical presence of non-critical patients places a significant burden on hospital infrastructure, particularly bed availability. This issue becomes more critical during movement-restricted situations such as the COVID-19 pandemic.</p> <p>This project presents a <strong>budget-friendly, IoT-based distanced health monitoring system</strong> that enables continuous monitoring of non-critical patients without requiring physical hospital visits. The system provides real-time access to medical data for patients, caretakers, and doctors through a secure web application.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="system-architecture-and-methodology">System Architecture and Methodology</h2> <div class="row justify-content-sm-center"> <div class="col-sm-10 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/projects/project_1/Methods-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/Methods-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/Methods-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/projects/project_1/Methods.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" title="System Architecture of IoT-Based Health Monitoring System" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Overall system architecture showing patient-side sensing, Raspberry Pi-based processing, Firebase Firestore cloud storage, and web application access for patients, caretakers, and doctors. </div> <p>The system collects physiological data from patients using sensors connected to a <strong>Raspberry Pi</strong>. The processed data are transmitted securely to <strong>Firebase Firestore</strong>, enabling near real-time synchronization with the Medical Instrumentation System (MIS) web application.</p> <p>The web interface allows:</p> <ul> <li>Patients and caretakers to monitor real-time health parameters and danger levels</li> <li>Doctors to review medical history and provide prescriptions and feedback remotely</li> </ul> <hr/> <h2 id="scope-and-objectives">Scope and Objectives</h2> <ul> <li>Develop an <strong>IoT-based system</strong> for monitoring patient health</li> <li>Monitor <strong>physiological parameters and lifestyle indicators</strong></li> <li>Design a <strong>portable device</strong> suitable for continuous patient use</li> <li>Enable scalability for <strong>multiple patients and doctors</strong></li> </ul> <hr/> <h2 id="results-and-discussion">Results and Discussion</h2> <div class="row justify-content-sm-center"> <div class="col-sm-10 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/projects/project_1/R2-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/R2-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/R2-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/projects/project_1/R2.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" title="R2" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="row"> <div class="col-sm-6 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/projects/project_1/R1-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/R1-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/R1-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/projects/project_1/R1.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" title="R1" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm-6 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/projects/project_1/R4-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/R4-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/R4-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/projects/project_1/R4.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> IoT device for collecting physiological data and transmitting it to Firebase Firestore for real-time visualization. </div> <p>The developed Medical Instrumentation System (MIS) demonstrated that IoT-based distanced patient monitoring is feasible for non-critical cases.</p> <p>Key outcomes include:</p> <ul> <li>End-to-end data synchronization (device → Firestore → MIS page) within <strong>1–2 seconds</strong></li> <li>Patients and caretakers can view medical data, danger levels, and follow doctor prescriptions</li> <li>Secure storage of patient medical history enables informed clinical decision-making</li> </ul> <p>This study incorporates patient basic details to prioritize medical history, an aspect not widely explored in related works. Additionally, the system supports doctor prescriptions and feedback, which are absent in many existing solutions.</p> <p>Firestore allows up to <strong>1 MB of data per document</strong>, indicating the need for a dedicated database server during large-scale commercialization. An SMS gateway can be integrated for OTP-based authentication to enhance system security.</p> <div class="row"> <div class="col-sm-6 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/projects/project_1/D1-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/D1-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/D1-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/projects/project_1/D1.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" title="Doctor Dashboard" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm-6 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/projects/project_1/D2-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/D2-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/D2-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/projects/project_1/D2.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" title="Patient View" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="row justify-content-sm-center"> <div class="col-sm-10 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/projects/project_1/D3-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/D3-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/D3-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/projects/project_1/D3.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" title="Medical History and Graphs" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Web application interface showing doctor dashboard, patient view, and medical history visualization. </div> <hr/> <h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2> <p>This project demonstrates a feasible and scalable approach to implementing an <strong>IoT-based distanced health monitoring system</strong>. The MIS web application successfully displays medical data received from distributed devices and supports interactions among multiple patients, caretakers, and doctors.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="future-directions">Future Directions</h2> <ul> <li>Integrate additional medical devices and sensors based on specific health conditions</li> <li>Incorporate <strong>Machine Learning/Deep Learning</strong> models for early warning prediction</li> <li>Enhance security using <strong>SMS-based OTP authentication</strong></li> </ul> <hr/> <h2 id="live-demo">Live Demo</h2> <p>🔗 <strong>Web Application:</strong> <a href="https://rasp-med.web.app/">https://rasp-med.web.app/</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="references">References</h2> <ol> <li>V. Vippalapalli and S. Ananthula, “Internet of things (IoT) based smart health care system,” <em>SCOPES 2016</em>, 2017.</li> <li>S. Pinto, J. Cabral, and T. Gomes, “We-Care: An IoT-based Health Care System for Elderly People.”</li> <li>V. Tamilselvi et al., “IoT Based Health Monitoring System,” <em>ICACCS 2020</em>, 2020.</li> <li>S. Rajkumar et al., “Health monitoring system using Raspberry Pi,” <em>BID 2017</em>, 2018.</li> <li>M. Hamim et al., “IoT Based remote health monitoring system,” <em>ICREST 2019</em>, 2019.</li> <li>V. Pardeshi et al., “Health monitoring systems using IoT and Raspberry Pi – A review,” <em>ICIMIA 2017</em>, 2017.</li> </ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="Project"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A cost-effective remote health monitoring solution designed to continuously assess non-critical patients while reducing hospital congestion—especially during emergencies such as the COVID-19 pandemic.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">(PDF) Making Threads in SolidWorks</title><link href="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2025/pdf-making-threads-in-solidworks/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="(PDF) Making Threads in SolidWorks"/><published>2025-12-20T19:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-12-20T19:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2025/pdf-making-threads-in-solidworks</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2025/pdf-making-threads-in-solidworks/"><![CDATA[<p>OutlineDownload Free PDF…7 pagesComputer-Aided Design of Traditional Jigs and Fixtures, 2021Conventional design of jigs and fixtures has become unsuitable given the requirements of modern technology and complexity and diversity in the production with the rapid update of products. Computer-aided design (CAD) of jigs and fixtures is an effective solution in this direction. The current paper focuses on a computer-aided design of the traditional jigs and fixtures and developed a system containing tailor-made software, created using the Visual Basic programming language and installed on it the viewer screen to show the part. The developed system has been built by connecting Visual Basic programming language to the SolidWorks software on which the part is drawn and saved as STEP AP-203 file format, and the system reads and extracts the data from the STEP AP-203 file. Heuristic rules of feature recognition are pre-prepared for checking the extracted geometric data and deciding which data shape will represent the machining feature; then, the system provides the optimum design of the traditional jigs and fixtures for a group of hollow cylindrical parts that contain a group of cross-holes on the cylinder body, whether perpendicular or offset from the cylinder’s axis, (inclined or inclined offset, or blind or through, by applying pre-prepared heuristic rules for the design of traditional jigs and fixtures.2023 IEEE 17th International Symposium on Applied Computational Intelligence and Informatics (SACI), 2023In this paper, a carpenter software is designed and implemented that supports the daily management processes (customers, orders, inventory) and generates a pattern from the product descriptions based on the parameters specified. During the pattern generation process, a two-dimensional optimization is performed to generate a pattern that includes horizontal or vertical cuts, depending on the target machine, on which the position of the required parts is placed, generates the smallest material loss and uses leftover materials from the past. From the application, the pattern can be viewed and extracted online or in PDF format. This all is implemented in a layered web application with a modern approach.THREE DIMENSIONAL MODELING AND LOADING SIMULATION OF A STANDARD THREADED FASTENER IN CAD ENVIRONMENT (ТРИМЕРНО МОДЕЛИРАНЕ И СИМУЛАЦИОННО НАТОВАРВАНЕ В CAD-СРЕДА KНА СТАНДАРТНО РЕЗБОВО СЪЕДИНЕНИЕ ), 2006Abstract. The techniques of correct three dimensional modeling of geometry parameters of thread and of the body of standard threaded fasteners (bolt and nut) in CAD environment of software product SolidWoprks’2005 are presented. The model of joint are put under loading simulation and the zones of concentrations of stresses are determined. The values and distribution of stresses from loading simulation and from calculation and from experiments known from literature are compared. Key words: threaded fasteners, CAD, finite element method.This paper presents a mechanistic model for prediction of the thread milling forces. The mechanics of cutting for thread milling is analyzed similar to the end milling process but with modified cutting edge geometry. The chip thickness and cutting force models are developed considering the unique geometry of the tool. The model has been calibrated for 6061 Aluminum and validated. The effects of tool and thread geometry have been studied using the model. rZenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research), 2012Modular fixtures (MFs) are very important tools in manufacturing processes in terms of reduction the cost and the production time. This paper introduces an automated approach for assembling MFs elements by employing SolidWorks as a powerful 3D CAD software. Visual Basic (VB) programming language was applied integrating with SolidWorks API (Application programming interface) functions. This integration allowed creating plug-in file and generating new menus in the SolidWorks environment. The menus allow the user to select, insert, and assemble MFs elements.Jurnal Psikologi Udayana, 2016Revista Turismo em Análise, 1992RESUMO: O Turismo, frente à questão ambiental. apresenta amplas possibilidades que vem sendo divulgadas pelos meios de comunicação. Este artigo considera a oferta alternativa, do ponlo de vista geográfi• coo identificando a variedade de formas. conceitos e interferências no meio ambiente. UNITERMOS: Turismo: meio ambiente: geografia; oferta alternati• va; atividades recreacionais.Jurnal Manajemen, Strategi Bisnis dan Kewirausahaan, 2017Jurnal Ilmiah Akuntansi dan Bisnis, 2020Clinical liver disease, 2020Cirrhosis and its end-stage complications have been well-known by medical practitioners for many centuries and were frequently described in historical writings and medical literature as far back as Hippocrates in 400 bce. 1 The ancient Greeks believed the liver to be the center of the circulation and the site of blood production, perhaps because of its propensity to bleed when injured in battle or accidents. Indeed, the liver was referred to by Galen 2 as the “blood sac” because of its abundant blood flow, which comes from its almost unique dual blood supply, namely, the hepatic artery and the portal vein (almost because there is also a portal venous system between the pituitary and the hypothalamus 3 ) (Fig. ). In 200 ce, Galen wrote of the liver as the fons venarum, the source of the major veins of the body and the sanguifactionis officina or the “factory of the blood,” the site of sanguification. 2 In modern times, even after the gross anatomy of the liver was clearly elucidated, poor understanding of liver disease resulted in a diagnosis of cirrhosis Abbreviations: ADAMTS13, a disintegrin and metalloproteinase with a thrombospondin type 1 motif, member 13; AHG, antihemophilic globulin; aPTT, activated partial thromboplastin time; AT, antithrombin; C, protein C; FFP, fresh frozen plasma; HMWK,Procedia Manufacturing, 2015The modulated tool path (MTP) chip breaking process has been modified to improve chip management capabilities and to prevent large chip nest accumulations commonly encountered in threading operations. The use of MTP to create segmented chips requires a different approach for threading operations than for normal MTP turning operations, although the fundamental principal is the same. The primary difference between MTP for threading and for straight turning is that the part surface that the tool repeatedly engages and disengages, during the modulation process, is the thread root rather than the cut face. The threading MTP part program developed in this paper is capable of machining a thread with the desired lead, depth, undercut angle, and taper angle while also producing segmented chips.International Journal of …, 2006This paper presents a mechanistic model for prediction of the thread milling forces. The mechanics of cutting for thread milling is analyzed similar to the end milling process but with modified cutting edge geometry. The chip thickness and cutting force models are developed considering the unique geometry of the tool. The model has been calibrated for 6061 Aluminum and validated. The effects of tool and thread geometry have been studied using the model. rVariations in cutting forces were investigated experimentally depending on infeed angles and cutting areas in the external threading on a CNC turning centre. For this purpose, AISI 1050 workpiece material, 16ERM AG 60 IC 908 cutting tool, and SER 2525 M16 tool holder were used. External threading operations were performed using 0 • , 14.5 • , 15 • , 27.5 • , and 30 • infeed angles while the cutting speed was held constant at 100 m/min for the experiments. Experimental results showed that the infeed angle and cutting area had significant effects on the main cutting force and the radial force components were considerable in threading operations in terms of energy consumption. In addition, the optimum infeed angle was 30 • in the external threading operations in terms of cutting forces.Acta Polytechnica Hungarica, 2014Different tool geometries have been developed by leading companies in the tool industry to different aims of application. The fastest progress can be observed in the development of coatings, in spite of this it can be noticed that there are only few coating types, but they can be used in a wide range. For users it offers the great advantage to select appropriate tool easier. Coating types, developed specially to individual aim of application, offer much better solution, compared to the generally used coating types. Platit AG, dealing with the development of optimised coating types, has requested our specialised group to carry out tests on specialised coating types. Our present study is going to summarise the results of the tests, carried out with thread forming tools.The International Journal of Advanced Manufacturing Technology, 2014is an open access repository that collects the work of Arts et Métiers ParisTech researchers and makes it freely available over the web where possible. This is an author-deposited version published in: http://sam.ensam.eu Handle ID: .http://hdl.handle.net/10985/8565 To cite this version : Vishal SHARMA, Guillaume FROMENTIN, Gérard POULACHON, Romain BRENDLEN -Investigation of tool geometry effect and penetration strategies on cutting forces during thread millingCiência da Informação, 2003e os seus respectivos desafios e dificuldades. Os resultados e as contribuições relatam sobre a viabilidade prática do projeto PEI e os detalhes da execução de sua metodologia. A conclusão reitera a importância da metodologia do PEI, implementada e aceita como uma ferramenta para contribuir de forma efetiva nas inteligências interna, competitiva e organizacional do Senac-PR.Jurnal kajian bimbingan dan konseling, 2023Extensive work has documented an association between sustaining intimate partner violence (IPV) and posttraumatic stress disorder (PTSD) among women, yet little research has documented the same association in men, even though men comprise 25-50% of all IPV victims in a given year. Previous studies also show that women who sustain intimate terrorism (IT), a form of IPV that is characterized by much violence and controlling behavior, are at even greater risk for PTSD than women who sustain common couple violence (CCV), a lower level of more minor, reciprocal IPV. However, no research has documented this trend in men who sustain IT versus CCV. The present study investigates the associations among sustaining IPV and PTSD among both a clinical and community sample of men. The clinical sample is comprised of 302 men who sustained IT from their female partners and sought help. The community sample is comprised of 520 men, 16% of whom sustained CCV. Analyses showed that in both samples, the associations between sustaining several types of IPV and PTSD were significant, and that men who sustained IT were at exponentially increased risk of exceeding the clinical cut-off on the PTSD measure than men who sustained CCV or no violence. The path models predicting PTSD symptoms differed for both samples, indicating that perhaps treatment implications differ by group as well.2017Cryogenics is dealing with very low temperatures of less than 120 K. Thermal insulation is a key to minimize heat leak in cryogenics during transportation in transfer line. The present study is conducted to derive three-dimensional heat transfer mathematical equations to predict conductivity of insulation systems for liquid nitrogen pipe flow. Elliptic differential equations on special domains were derived based on Fourier method for three-dimensional heat equations. As a result from the study, three-dimensional heat conduction equation for a cylindrical problem was successfully derived. The derived equation provides a mathematical solution to determine the heat transfer rate for a system of cryogenic pipe insulated with multiple layers.Einstein, 2024Sabadin et al. demonstrated that most yeasts isolated from patients who have undergone liver transplantation are susceptible to the antifungal agents fluconazole, amphotericin B, and micafungin. Fifteen patients presented with either atrophic or pseudomembranous oral candidiasis. Candida albicans and Candida glabrata were the most prevalent in these patients.Inflammation Research, 2003Objective: To investigate the effects of ibandronate, a novel aminobisphosphonate, on inflammation as well as leukocyte-endothelial cell interaction in mouse antigen-induced arthritis (AiA). Material and Treatment: 36 Balb/c mice were subcutaneously injected with 160 mg/kg of ibandronate once per day beginning at day 7 until day 13 after induction of AiA. Methods: The severity of arthritis was assessed by changes of the transverse knee joint diameter. For the intravital fluorescence microscopy measurements on day 14 after AiA induction, the patella tendon was partly resected to visualize the intraarticular synovial tissue of the knee joint. The number of rolling and adherent leukocytes as well as red blood cell (RBC) velocity and functional capillary density (FCD) were quantified in synovial microvessels. Furthermore, leukocyte infiltration in the synovium was determined in histological sections with an established score. Results: Both fractions of rolling leukocytes (p = 0.016) as well as number of extravasated leukocytes (p = 0.004) were enhanced in control animals treated with ibandronate in comparison to animals which received saline. Arthritic animals with and without ibandronate treatment revealed an increased FCD (p = 0.006, p = 0.008), enhanced number of rolling ( p = 0.002, p = 0.001) and adherent leukocytes (p = 0.009, p = 0.007) and greater swelling of the left knee joint (p = 0.002, p = 0.001) when compared to control animals. No significant differences between arthritic animals and arthritic animals treated with ibandronate were found in any of the parameters assessed including leukocyte adherence, FCD, histology, and knee joint swelling. Conclusion: Ibandronate treatment of healthy mice was associated with an enhanced fraction of rolling leukocytes and increased numbers of extravasated leukocytes indicating a proinflammatory effect on the synovial microcirculation. In animals with a preexisting antigen-induced arthritis, however, ibandronate did not induce an exacerbation of joint inflammation and leukocyte adherence.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Making Threads in SolidWorks]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">(PDF) Measuring Pen – A digital device to measure distance</title><link href="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2025/pdf-measuring-pen-a-digital-device-to-measure-distance/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="(PDF) Measuring Pen – A digital device to measure distance"/><published>2025-12-19T19:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-12-19T19:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2025/pdf-measuring-pen--a-digital-device-to-measure-distance</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2025/pdf-measuring-pen-a-digital-device-to-measure-distance/"><![CDATA[<p>OutlineDownload Free PDF…3 pagesThis is a new approach on the section of measurement. Today, most of the garment companies are producing lot of clothes. While producing clothes they have to face lot of problems. For an example time of delivery and accuracy in clothes size. A traditional way of measuring a cloth is using a tape. Due to that there may be errors in measuring length and it take times time to check the length using tape. Main aim of this mini project is to solve these problems using a microcontroller measuring system. This will reduce the time taken for the cutting and will measure accurately. For this project Arduino Nano is used as the microcontroller for performing the algorithmic work.JOURNAL OF ENGINEERING &amp; PROCESSING MANAGEMENT, 2017U ovom radu autori su razvili i implementirali HACCP plan za proces proizvodnjefermentisanih proizvoda od mlijeka, što je prikazano na primjeru jogurta. Analizaopasnosti je obuhvatila 241 opasnost, od čega je moguće 99 opasnostieliminisati, odnosno spriječiti njihovu pojavu, blagovremenim preduzimanjempreventivnih mjera. HACCP sistem je neophodno primijeniti za otklanjanje svega11 identifikovanih opasnosti. U prikazanom modelu, identifikovano je pet CCP, odčega tri za biološke i po jedna hemijske i fizičke opasnosti.Tokom višegodišnje praktične primjene razvijeni HACCP sistem je pokazaoprednosti primjene u odnosu na druge sisteme za osiguranje bezbjednosti hrane:efikasnost, jednostavnost i niska cijena primjene.Cancer Research, 2017The cBioPortal for Cancer Genomics is an open-access portal (http://cbioportal.org) that enables interactive, exploratory analysis of large-scale cancer genomics data. It integrates genomic and clinical data, and provides a suite of visualization and analysis options, including cohort and patient-level visualization, mutation visualization, survival analysis, enrichment analysis, and network analysis. The user interface is user-friendly, responsive, and makes genomic data easily accessible to translational scientists, biologists, and clinicians. The cBioPortal is a fully open source platform. All code is available on GitHub (https://github.com/cBioPortal/) under GNU Affero GPL license. The code base is maintained by multiple groups, including Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center, Dana-Farber Cancer Institute, Children’s Hospital of Philadelphia, Princess Margaret Cancer Centre, and The Hyve, an open source bioinformatics company based in the Netherlands. More than 30 academic cent…IP INNOVATIVE PUBLICATION PVT LTD, 2025Background: Hypertensive emergencies during pregnancy pose significant risks to both mother and fetus. This study examines the time and dosage needed to achieve target blood pressure levels using two antihypertensive agents: oral Nifedipine retard and intravenous Labetalol. Through a randomized trial, it aims to provide insights into the safety and efficacy of these treatments, enhancing management strategies for hypertensive disorders in pregnancy. Materials and Methods: A randomized study with 104 pregnant women who had a blood pressure of 160/110 mm Hg or higher compared the effects of Nifedipine (20 mg every 30 minutes, up to five doses) and Labetalol (20 mg, 40 mg, or 80 mg every 15 minutes) until a target blood pressure of 150/100 mm Hg or lower was reached. The main focus was on the time and dosage needed to achieve this goal. Results: The mean time to achieve target blood pressure was significantly shorter with IV Labetalol (33.85 ± 11.87 minutes) compared to oral Nifedipine (48.56 ± 17.36 minutes; P &lt; 0.0001). The average dose required was lower for Nifedipine (1.73 ± 0.63 mg) than for Labetalol (2.06 ± 0.67 mg; P &lt; 0.01). The total dose needed was higher for Labetalol (70.00 ± 42.57 mg) compared to Nifedipine (33.71 ± 13.14 mg). Conclusion: Labetalol quickly lowers blood pressure, while oral nifedipine retard is also effective and well tolerated for managing severe hypertension, showing minimal side effects.Tropical Medicine and Infectious Disease, 2022Background: Ghana joined the Global Programme to Eliminate Lymphatic Filariasis (GPELF), established in the year 2000, with the aim of eliminating the disease as a public health problem through annual mass treatment of entire endemic populations. Since 2001, the country has implemented mass drug administration (MDA) in endemic districts, with great reductions in the population at risk for infection. However, in many districts, the elimination programme is faced with the presence of hotspots, which may be due in part to individuals not taking part in MDA (either intentionally or unintentionally) who may serve as reservoirs to sustain transmission. This paper compares the LF-related perceptions among individuals who regularly take the MDA drugs and those who seldom or never take part in the MDA in the Ahanta West Municipality of Ghana to determine community acceptable ways to implement an intervention aimed to track, engage, and treat individuals who regularly miss MDA or to test individuals who intentionally refuse MDA and treat them if positive for LF. Methods: This was a mixed method study employing questionnaire surveys and focus group discussions (FDG) for data collection. Survey participants were randomly selected from the 2019 treatment register to stratify respondents into treated and non-treated groups. FGD participants were selected purposively such that there are at least two non-treated persons in each discussion session. Results: Over 90% of the respondents were aware of the disease. Poor hygiene/dirty environment was wrongly reported by most respondents (76.8%) as the causes. MDA awareness was very high among both treated (96.9%) and non-treated (98.6%) groups. A low sense of vulnerability to LF infection was evident by a reduction in the number of people presenting clinical manifestations of the disease in communities. Slightly more, 65 (29.0%) of the non-treated group compared to the 42 (19.4%) treated group reported ever experiencing adverse effects of the MDA drugs. Barriers to MDA uptake reported in both groups were poor planning and implementation of the MDA, lack of commitments on the part of drug distributors, and adverse drug reactions. About 51% of the non-treated group reported never taking the drugs even once in the last five years, while 61% among the treated group took the MDA drug consistently in the past five years. Respondents in both groups believed that, when engaged properly, most non-treated persons will accept to take the drug but insisted community drug distributors (CDDs) must be trained to effectively engage people and have time for those they will be engaging in dialogue. The chiefs emerged as the most influential people who can influence people to take MDA drugs. Conclusions: The reduction in risk perception among respondents, adverse reactions and the timing of MDA activities may be influencing MDA non-participation in the study area; however, respondents think that non-treated individuals will accept the interventions when engaged properly by the CDDs.Journal of Cancer, 2019Purpose: Prostate cancer (PCa) varies clinically from very indolent, not requiring therapeutic intervention, to highly aggressive, entailing radical treatment. Currently, stratification of PCa aggressiveness is mostly based on Gleason score, serum PSA and TNM stage, but outcome prediction in an individual basis is suboptimal. Thus, perfecting pre-therapeutic discrimination between indolent and aggressive PCa, avoiding overtreatment is a major challenge. Epithelial to mesenchymal transition (EMT) allows epithelial cells to acquire mesenchymal properties, constituting a critical step in tumor invasion and metastization. Thus, we hypothesized that EMT-related markers might allow for improved assessment of PCa aggressiveness. Methods and Results: Using RealTime ready Custom Panel 384 assay, 93 EMT-related genes were assessed in normal prostate tissues (NPT, n=5), stage pT2a+b-PCa (n=5) and stage pT3b-PCa (n=5), from which CAMK2N1, CD44, KRT14, TGFβ3 and WNT5A genes emerged as the most significantly altered. Expression levels were then evaluated in a larger series (16 NPT and 94 PCa) of frozen tissues using quantitative RT-PCR. Globally, CAMK2N1, CD44 and WNT5A displayed higher expression levels at higher stages and less differentiated PCa. CAMK2N1 and WNT5A immunoexpression analysis disclosed significantly lower expression in NPT and increasing proportion of high-expression cases from pT2a+b to pT3b and metastatic PCa. Furthermore, higher CAMK2N1 and WNT5A transcript levels associated with shorter disease-free and disease-specific survival. In multivariable analysis, a trend for WNT5A expression levels to independently predict DFS was disclosed (p=0.056). Conclusions: Globally, our findings suggest an association between PCa aggressiveness and increased expression of CAMK2N1 and WNT5A, reflecting the acquisition of effective EMT characteristics by PCa cells.— This paper deals with the design and implementation of a simple HMC6352 2-axis digital compass. Most compasses have been of the analogue type with magnetic needles as pointers. Replacing the “ old “ magnetic needle compass or the gyrocompass by an electronic solution offers advantages like having a solid-state component without moving parts and the ease of interfacing with other electronic systems. In this work, the aim is to design and implement a digital compass. To realize this, we made use of HMC6352 which is a 2-axis MR (magneto-resistive) sensor from Honeywell, Arduino Uno board with an onboard ATmega328 microcontroller chip, and a 16x2 character Liquid Crystal Display (LCD).We adopted the magneto-resistive (MR) technology as compared to flux-gate sensors common in most electronic compasses which has the disadvantage of making the device bulky. The trial test carried out with the completed HMC6352 digital compass showed a reading of 232.8 degrees West indicating its effectiveness in direction finding.Jurnal Kimia Sains dan Aplikasi, 2019Jernang resin is secretion of jernang rattan (Daemonorops draco, Arecaceae family) fruits which is endemic in Southeast Asia. This resin has various biological activities and empirically used as wound healing, headache medicines, and fever remedies by Anak Dalam ethnic group from Jambi. This study was performed to evaluate the antioxidant activity of nonpolar fraction of D. draco resin which collected from Jambi Province, Sumatera, Indonesia. Resin was extracted with n-hexane, ethyl acetate, and methanol respectively. The antioxidant properties of the extracts were then evaluated using i,i-diphenyl-2picryl-hidrazyl radical scavenging assay. The most active extract was further fractionated using n-hexane and methanol and separated using column chromatography and preparative thin layer chromatography. Separation of the extract was conducted through antioxidant assay-guided fractionation. Characterization of the active fraction was carried out by infrared spectroscopy. The result shows that ethyl acetate extract provides higher antioxidant activity (IC50 = 27.61 pg/mL) compare to methanol and n-hexane extracts. N-hexane fraction of ethyl acetate extract used for further separation using column and preparative thin layer chromatography due to its antioxidant activity. Separation using column chromatography resulting in 9 fractions (F.1-9). Fraction F.5 provide high antioxidant activity (IC50 = 17.27 pg/mL) and further separated using preparative thin layer chromatography resulting two fractions with lower antioxidant activity F.5.1 (IC50 = 85.18 pg/mL) and F.5. 2 (IC50 = 34-94 pg/mL). Characterization of fraction F.5.2 using infrared spectroscopy showed that component in fraction F.5.2 contains NH-substituted benzene.Jurnal Udayana Mengabdi, 2019The amount of teenage smokers has significantly increased in the present. The desire to smoke in teenagers is associated with the exposure of peer group. This is triggered by the urge to be accepted in the community and the lack of information. The beginning age of a person to smoke is getting younger. This phenomenon triggers the addiction and increase the vulnerability of serious diseases in the future. Therefore, there should be an effort to empower the teenagers by molding peer educator as RADAR. It has roles to influence their peer friends to avoid tobacco and campaign about the danger of tobacco and recent issues about tobacco in their school. The aims were decreasing the early teenage smokers and creating a sustainable extracurricular that generates regeneration of peer educator in SMPN 10 Denpasar. The methods were 1) Roadshow; 2) Trainings; 3) Selection and final; and 4) Campaign activity. The result showed that there was an increasing score from pretest to posttest after implementing the program which was 25.8%. The activities of RADAR in social media were shown from the amount of likes on each topic which comprised of 200 likes of the danger of tobacco, 90 likes of TAPS, 120 likes of PHW, and 100 likes of KTR. This program succeeded in educating the danger of tobacco in early teenagers and create an extracurricular in school. This program is expected to be applied in another junior high school in Bali.2022this study proposed a model to assess visitor experience quality and its effect on their image, perceived value, delight, satisfaction, and behavioral intentions in Iranian water parks. Based on convenience sampling, a sample of 384 visitors at five water parks in Mashhad, Iran was selected. Data were subjected to partial least squares analysis based on structural equation modeling (PLS-SEM). The findings of this study showed that quality of visitors’ experiences significantly affects water park image, perceived value, and visitor’s satisfaction. Also, water park image significantly affects perceived value, delight, and visitor’s satisfaction. Moreover, perceived value and water park image exert a direct influence on customer satisfaction, and they also positively affect behavioral intentions. But, the visitor’s delight affects indirectly and through satisfaction on behavioral intentions. Therefore, the results of this study will assist water parks management to develop and implement market-orientated service strategies both to increase experience quality and water park image and to enhance perceived value, delight, and satisfaction among visitors. It is hoped such changes will increase visitors’ favorable Davood Ghorbanzade ABOUT THE AUTHORS Davood Ghorbanzadeh is a Ph.D. Candidates Of Business Management-Marketing Management and graduated of MSc in Business Management-Marketing from the department of Management and Social science,Jurnal IPTA (Industri Perjalanan Wisata), 2023</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is a new approach on the section of measurement. Today, most of the garment companies are producing lot of clothes. While producing clothes they have to face lot of problems. For an example time of delivery and accuracy in clothes size. A]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Google Gemini updates: Flash 1.5, Gemma 2 and Project Astra</title><link href="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2024/google-gemini-updates-flash-15-gemma-2-and-project-astra/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Google Gemini updates: Flash 1.5, Gemma 2 and Project Astra"/><published>2024-05-13T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-05-13T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2024/google-gemini-updates-flash-15-gemma-2-and-project-astra</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2024/google-gemini-updates-flash-15-gemma-2-and-project-astra/"><![CDATA[<p>May 14, 2024 We’re introducing a series of updates across the Gemini family of models, including the new 1.5 Flash, our lightweight model for speed and efficiency, and Project Astra, our vision for the future of AI assistants. In December, we launched our first natively multimodal model Gemini 1.0 in three sizes: Ultra, Pro and Nano. Just a few months later we released 1.5 Pro, with enhanced performance and a breakthrough long context window of 1 million tokens.Developers and enterprise customers have been putting 1.5 Pro to use in incredible ways and finding its long context window, multimodal reasoning capabilities and impressive overall performance incredibly useful.We know from user feedback that some applications need lower latency and a lower cost to serve. This inspired us to keep innovating, so today, we’re introducing Gemini 1.5 Flash: a model that’s lighter-weight than 1.5 Pro, and designed to be fast and efficient to serve at scale.Both 1.5 Pro and 1.5 Flash are available in public preview with a 1 million token context window in Google AI Studio and Vertex AI. And now, 1.5 Pro is also available with a 2 million token context window via waitlist to developers using the API and to Google Cloud customers.We’re also introducing updates across the Gemini family of models, announcing our next generation of open models, Gemma 2, and sharing progress on the future of AI assistants, with Project Astra.Context lengths of leading foundation models compared with Gemini 1.5’s 2 million token capability1.5 Flash is the newest addition to the Gemini model family and the fastest Gemini model served in the API. It’s optimized for high-volume, high-frequency tasks at scale, is more cost-efficient to serve and features our breakthrough long context window.While it’s a lighter weight model than 1.5 Pro, it’s highly capable of multimodal reasoning across vast amounts of information and delivers impressive quality for its size.The new Gemini 1.5 Flash model is optimized for speed and efficiency, is highly capable of multimodal reasoning and features our breakthrough long context window.1.5 Flash excels at summarization, chat applications, image and video captioning, data extraction from long documents and tables, and more. This is because it’s been trained by 1.5 Pro through a process called “distillation,” where the most essential knowledge and skills from a larger model are transferred to a smaller, more efficient model.Read more about 1.5 Flash in our updated Gemini 1.5 technical report, on the Gemini technology page, and learn about 1.5 Flash’s availability and pricing.Over the last few months, we’ve significantly improved 1.5 Pro, our best model for general performance across a wide range of tasks.Beyond extending its context window to 2 million tokens, we’ve enhanced its code generation, logical reasoning and planning, multi-turn conversation, and audio and image understanding through data and algorithmic advances. We see strong improvements on public and internal benchmarks for each of these tasks.1.5 Pro can now follow increasingly complex and nuanced instructions, including ones that specify product-level behavior involving role, format and style. We’ve improved control over the model’s responses for specific use cases, like crafting the persona and response style of a chat agent or automating workflows through multiple function calls. And we’ve enabled users to steer model behavior by setting system instructions.We added audio understanding in the Gemini API and Google AI Studio, so 1.5 Pro can now reason across image and audio for videos uploaded in Google AI Studio. And we’re now integrating 1.5 Pro into Google products, including Gemini Advanced and in Workspace apps.Read more about 1.5 Pro in our updated Gemini 1.5 technical report and on the Gemini technology page.Gemini Nano is expanding beyond text-only inputs to include images as well. Starting with Pixel, applications using Gemini Nano with Multimodality will be able to understand the world the way people do — not just through text, but also through sight, sound and spoken language.Read more about Gemini 1.0 Nano on Android.Today, we’re also sharing a series of updates to Gemma, our family of open models built from the same research and technology used to create the Gemini models.We’re announcing Gemma 2, our next generation of open models for responsible AI innovation. Gemma 2 has a new architecture designed for breakthrough performance and efficiency, and will be available in new sizes.The Gemma family is also expanding with PaliGemma, our first vision-language model inspired by PaLI-3. And we’ve upgraded our Responsible Generative AI Toolkit with LLM Comparator for evaluating the quality of model responses.Read more on the Developer blog.As part of Google DeepMind’s mission to build AI responsibly to benefit humanity, we’ve always wanted to develop universal AI agents that can be helpful in everyday life. That’s why today, we’re sharing our progress in building the future of AI assistants with Project Astra (advanced seeing and talking responsive agent).To be truly useful, an agent needs to understand and respond to the complex and dynamic world just like people do — and take in and remember what it sees and hears to understand context and take action. It also needs to be proactive, teachable and personal, so users can talk to it naturally and without lag or delay.While we’ve made incredible progress developing AI systems that can understand multimodal information, getting response time down to something conversational is a difficult engineering challenge. Over the past few years, we’ve been working to improve how our models perceive, reason and converse to make the pace and quality of interaction feel more natural.Building on Gemini, we’ve developed prototype agents that can process information faster by continuously encoding video frames, combining the video and speech input into a timeline of events, and caching this information for efficient recall.By leveraging our leading speech models, we also enhanced how they sound, giving the agents a wider range of intonations. These agents can better understand the context they’re being used in, and respond quickly, in conversation.With technology like this, it’s easy to envision a future where people could have an expert AI assistant by their side, through a phone or glasses. And some of these capabilities are coming to Google products, like the Gemini app and web experience, later this year.We’ve made incredible progress so far with our family of Gemini models, and we’re always striving to advance the state-of-the-art even further. By investing in a relentless production line of innovation, we’re able to explore new ideas at the frontier, while also unlocking the possibility of new and exciting Gemini use cases.Learn more about Gemini and its capabilities. Your information will be used in accordance with Google’s privacy policy.</p> <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>      Done. Just one step more.
    
      Check your inbox to confirm your subscription.
    You are already subscribed to our newsletter.
    You can also subscribe with a
    different email address
    
    .
    
  Let’s stay in touch. Get the latest news from Google in your inbox.
          Follow Us
</code></pre></div></div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re sharing updates across our Gemini family of models and a glimpse of Project Astra, our vision for the future of AI assistants.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Displaying External Posts on Your al-folio Blog</title><link href="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Displaying External Posts on Your al-folio Blog"/><published>2022-04-23T19:20:09-04:00</published><updated>2022-04-23T19:20:09-04:00</updated><id>https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog/"><![CDATA[<h3>External Posts on Your al-folio Blog</h3> <p>If you prefer publishing blog posts on medium.com or other external sources, starting version v0.5.0, <a href="https://github.com/alshedivat/al-folio">al-folio</a> lets you to display your external posts in the blog feed of your website! 🎉🎉</p> <p>Configuring external sources of super simple. After upgrading to v0.5.0, just add the following section to your _config.yml:</p> <pre>external_sources:<br />  - name: medium.com  # name of the source (arbitrary string)<br />    rss_url: <a href="https://medium.com/@al-folio/feed">https://medium.com/@&lt;your-medium-username&gt;/feed</a></pre> <p>The example above adds your medium.com blog post feed as an external source. But you can add arbitrary RSS feeds as sources.</p> <p>Any questions or suggestions? 👉 Start <a href="https://github.com/alshedivat/al-folio/discussions">a discussion on GitHub</a>!</p> <p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&amp;referrerSource=full_rss&amp;postId=b60a1d241a0a" width="1" height="1" alt=""/></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html">a post with TikZJax</title><link href="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2010/tikzjax/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="a post with TikZJax"/><published>2010-12-12T17:25:00-05:00</published><updated>2010-12-12T17:25:00-05:00</updated><id>https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2010/tikzjax</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2010/tikzjax/"><![CDATA[<p>This is an example post with TikZ code. TikZJax converts script tags (containing TikZ code) into SVGs.</p> <script type="text/tikz">
\begin{tikzpicture}
    \draw[red,fill=black!60!red] (0,0) circle [radius=1.5];
    \draw[green,fill=black!60!green] (0,0) circle [x radius=1.5cm, y radius=10mm];
    \draw[blue,fill=black!60!blue] (0,0) circle [x radius=1cm, y radius=5mm, rotate=30];
\end{tikzpicture}
</script>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="formatting"/><category term="diagrams"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[this is what included TikZ code could look like]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">a post with giscus comments</title><link href="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2010/giscus-comments/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="a post with giscus comments"/><published>2010-12-10T10:59:00-05:00</published><updated>2010-12-10T10:59:00-05:00</updated><id>https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2010/giscus-comments</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2010/giscus-comments/"><![CDATA[<p>This post shows how to add GISCUS comments.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="external-services"/><category term="comments"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[an example of a blog post with giscus comments]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">a post with disqus comments</title><link href="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2010/disqus-comments/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="a post with disqus comments"/><published>2010-10-20T11:59:00-04:00</published><updated>2010-10-20T11:59:00-04:00</updated><id>https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2010/disqus-comments</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2010/disqus-comments/"><![CDATA[<p>This post shows how to add DISQUS comments.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="external-services"/><category term="comments"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[an example of a blog post with disqus comments]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">a post with math</title><link href="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2010/math/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="a post with math"/><published>2010-10-20T11:12:00-04:00</published><updated>2010-10-20T11:12:00-04:00</updated><id>https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2010/math</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2010/math/"><![CDATA[<p>This theme supports rendering beautiful math in inline and display modes using <a href="https://www.mathjax.org/">MathJax 3</a> engine. You just need to surround your math expression with <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">$$</code>, like <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">$$ E = mc^2 $$</code>. If you leave it inside a paragraph, it will produce an inline expression, just like \(E = mc^2\).</p> <p>To use display mode, again surround your expression with <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">$$</code> and place it as a separate paragraph. Here is an example:</p> \[\sum_{k=1}^\infty |\langle x, e_k \rangle|^2 \leq \|x\|^2\] <p>You can also use <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">\begin{equation}...\end{equation}</code> instead of <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">$$</code> for display mode math. MathJax will automatically number equations:</p> <p>\begin{equation} \label{eq:cauchy-schwarz} \left( \sum<em>{k=1}^n a_k b_k \right)^2 \leq \left( \sum</em>{k=1}^n a<em>k^2 \right) \left( \sum</em>{k=1}^n b_k^2 \right) \end{equation}</p> <p>and by adding <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">\label{...}</code> inside the equation environment, we can now refer to the equation using <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">\eqref</code>.</p> <p>Note that MathJax 3 is <a href="https://docs.mathjax.org/en/latest/upgrading/whats-new-3.0.html">a major re-write of MathJax</a> that brought a significant improvement to the loading and rendering speed, which is now <a href="http://www.intmath.com/cg5/katex-mathjax-comparison.php">on par with KaTeX</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="formatting"/><category term="math"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[an example of a blog post with some math]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">a post with image galleries</title><link href="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2010/photo-gallery/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="a post with image galleries"/><published>2010-10-03T21:59:00-04:00</published><updated>2010-10-03T21:59:00-04:00</updated><id>https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2010/photo-gallery</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2010/photo-gallery/"><![CDATA[<p>The images in this post are all zoomable, arranged into different mini-galleries using different libraries.</p> <h2 id="lightbox2"><a href="https://lokeshdhakar.com/projects/lightbox2/">Lightbox2</a></h2> <p><a href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/1/img-2500.jpg" data-lightbox="roadtrip"><img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/1/img-200.jpg"/></a> <a href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/2/img-2500.jpg" data-lightbox="roadtrip"><img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/2/img-200.jpg"/></a> <a href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/3/img-2500.jpg" data-lightbox="roadtrip"><img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/3/img-200.jpg"/></a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="photoswipe"><a href="https://photoswipe.com/">PhotoSwipe</a></h2> <div class="pswp-gallery pswp-gallery--single-column" id="gallery--getting-started"> <a href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/2/img-2500.jpg" data-pswp-width="1669" data-pswp-height="2500" target="_blank"> <img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/2/img-200.jpg" alt=""/> </a> <a href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/7/img-2500.jpg" data-pswp-width="1875" data-pswp-height="2500" data-cropped="true" target="_blank"> <img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/7/img-200.jpg" alt=""/> </a> <a href="https://unsplash.com" data-pswp-src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/3/img-2500.jpg" data-pswp-width="2500" data-pswp-height="1666" target="_blank"> <img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/3/img-200.jpg" alt=""/> </a> <div> <a href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/6/img-2500.jpg" data-pswp-width="2500" data-pswp-height="1667" target="_blank"> <img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/6/img-200.jpg" alt=""/> </a> </div> </div> <hr/> <h2 id="spotlight-js"><a href="https://nextapps-de.github.io/spotlight/">Spotlight JS</a></h2> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/1/img-2500.jpg"> <img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/1/img-200.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/2/img-2500.jpg"> <img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/2/img-200.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/3/img-2500.jpg"> <img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/3/img-200.jpg"/> </a> </div> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/4/img-2500.jpg"> <img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/4/img-200.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/5/img-2500.jpg"> <img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/5/img-200.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/6/img-2500.jpg"> <img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/6/img-200.jpg"/> </a> </div> <hr/> <h2 id="venobox"><a href="https://veno.es/venobox/">Venobox</a></h2> <p><a class="venobox" data-gall="myGallery" href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/1/img-2500.jpg"><img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/1/img-200.jpg"/></a> <a class="venobox" data-gall="myGallery" href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/2/img-2500.jpg"><img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/2/img-200.jpg"/></a> <a class="venobox" data-gall="myGallery" href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/3/img-2500.jpg"><img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/3/img-200.jpg"/></a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="formatting"/><category term="images"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[this is what included image galleries could look like]]></summary></entry></feed>