<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://imtheva.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://imtheva.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2026-01-24T13:03:58-05:00</updated><id>https://imtheva.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>Personal website of Thevathayarajh Thayananthan — research, projects, publications, and writing on science, engineering, and space. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Winter Storms: How They Form, Why They’re Dangerous, and What They Mean for Agriculture</title><link href="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2026/Winter_Storm/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Winter Storms: How They Form, Why They’re Dangerous, and What They Mean for Agriculture"/><published>2026-01-24T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2026-01-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2026/Winter_Storm</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2026/Winter_Storm/"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="external-services"/><category term="Winter"/><category term="Winter-storm"/><category term="Climate"/><category term="links"/><category term="Agriculture"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[An overview of winter storms—how they form, how they differ from normal snow events, and the often-overlooked impacts they have on agriculture, livestock, and farming systems.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How Computer Vision Is Transforming Agricultural Engineering</title><link href="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2026/CV/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How Computer Vision Is Transforming Agricultural Engineering"/><published>2026-01-16T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2026-01-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2026/CV</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2026/CV/"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="external-services"/><category term="Ag-Eng"/><category term="Agricultural-Engineering"/><category term="Robotics"/><category term="links"/><category term="Agriculture"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[An accessible overview of how computer vision is transforming agricultural engineering through crop detection, robotics, and intelligent farm automation.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">From Science Fiction to Farmland: Why Robotics &amp;amp; AI Are Inevitable in Agriculture</title><link href="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2026/robotics-ai-agriculture/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="From Science Fiction to Farmland: Why Robotics &amp;amp; AI Are Inevitable in Agriculture"/><published>2026-01-09T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2026-01-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2026/robotics-ai-agriculture</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2026/robotics-ai-agriculture/"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="external-services"/><category term="Ag-Eng"/><category term="Agricultural-Engineering"/><category term="Robotics"/><category term="links"/><category term="Agriculture"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[My first Medium article on why robotics & AI are becoming inevitable in agriculture.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">MIS</title><link href="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2025/MSc/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MIS"/><published>2025-12-27T19:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-12-27T19:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2025/MSc</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2025/MSc/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="project-overview">Project Overview</h2> <p>Several medical devices can directly analyze a patient’s medical condition; however, the physical presence of non-critical patients places a significant burden on hospital infrastructure, particularly bed availability. This issue becomes more critical during movement-restricted situations such as the COVID-19 pandemic.</p> <p>This project presents a <strong>budget-friendly, IoT-based distanced health monitoring system</strong> that enables continuous monitoring of non-critical patients without requiring physical hospital visits. The system provides real-time access to medical data for patients, caretakers, and doctors through a secure web application.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="system-architecture-and-methodology">System Architecture and Methodology</h2> <div class="row justify-content-sm-center"> <div class="col-sm-10 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/projects/project_1/Methods-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/Methods-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/Methods-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/projects/project_1/Methods.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" title="System Architecture of IoT-Based Health Monitoring System" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Overall system architecture showing patient-side sensing, Raspberry Pi-based processing, Firebase Firestore cloud storage, and web application access for patients, caretakers, and doctors. </div> <p>The system collects physiological data from patients using sensors connected to a <strong>Raspberry Pi</strong>. The processed data are transmitted securely to <strong>Firebase Firestore</strong>, enabling near real-time synchronization with the Medical Instrumentation System (MIS) web application.</p> <p>The web interface allows:</p> <ul> <li>Patients and caretakers to monitor real-time health parameters and danger levels</li> <li>Doctors to review medical history and provide prescriptions and feedback remotely</li> </ul> <hr/> <h2 id="scope-and-objectives">Scope and Objectives</h2> <ul> <li>Develop an <strong>IoT-based system</strong> for monitoring patient health</li> <li>Monitor <strong>physiological parameters and lifestyle indicators</strong></li> <li>Design a <strong>portable device</strong> suitable for continuous patient use</li> <li>Enable scalability for <strong>multiple patients and doctors</strong></li> </ul> <hr/> <h2 id="results-and-discussion">Results and Discussion</h2> <div class="row justify-content-sm-center"> <div class="col-sm-10 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/projects/project_1/R2-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/R2-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/R2-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/projects/project_1/R2.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" title="R2" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="row"> <div class="col-sm-6 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/projects/project_1/R1-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/R1-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/R1-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/projects/project_1/R1.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" title="R1" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm-6 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/projects/project_1/R4-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/R4-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/R4-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/projects/project_1/R4.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> IoT device for collecting physiological data and transmitting it to Firebase Firestore for real-time visualization. </div> <p>The developed Medical Instrumentation System (MIS) demonstrated that IoT-based distanced patient monitoring is feasible for non-critical cases.</p> <p>Key outcomes include:</p> <ul> <li>End-to-end data synchronization (device → Firestore → MIS page) within <strong>1–2 seconds</strong></li> <li>Patients and caretakers can view medical data, danger levels, and follow doctor prescriptions</li> <li>Secure storage of patient medical history enables informed clinical decision-making</li> </ul> <p>This study incorporates patient basic details to prioritize medical history, an aspect not widely explored in related works. Additionally, the system supports doctor prescriptions and feedback, which are absent in many existing solutions.</p> <p>Firestore allows up to <strong>1 MB of data per document</strong>, indicating the need for a dedicated database server during large-scale commercialization. An SMS gateway can be integrated for OTP-based authentication to enhance system security.</p> <div class="row"> <div class="col-sm-6 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/projects/project_1/D1-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/D1-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/D1-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/projects/project_1/D1.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" title="Doctor Dashboard" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm-6 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/projects/project_1/D2-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/D2-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/D2-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/projects/project_1/D2.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" title="Patient View" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="row justify-content-sm-center"> <div class="col-sm-10 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/projects/project_1/D3-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/D3-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/projects/project_1/D3-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/projects/project_1/D3.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" title="Medical History and Graphs" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Web application interface showing doctor dashboard, patient view, and medical history visualization. </div> <hr/> <h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2> <p>This project demonstrates a feasible and scalable approach to implementing an <strong>IoT-based distanced health monitoring system</strong>. The MIS web application successfully displays medical data received from distributed devices and supports interactions among multiple patients, caretakers, and doctors.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="future-directions">Future Directions</h2> <ul> <li>Integrate additional medical devices and sensors based on specific health conditions</li> <li>Incorporate <strong>Machine Learning/Deep Learning</strong> models for early warning prediction</li> <li>Enhance security using <strong>SMS-based OTP authentication</strong></li> </ul> <hr/> <h2 id="live-demo">Live Demo</h2> <p>🔗 <strong>Web Application:</strong> <a href="https://rasp-med.web.app/">https://rasp-med.web.app/</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="references">References</h2> <ol> <li>V. Vippalapalli and S. Ananthula, “Internet of things (IoT) based smart health care system,” <em>SCOPES 2016</em>, 2017.</li> <li>S. Pinto, J. Cabral, and T. Gomes, “We-Care: An IoT-based Health Care System for Elderly People.”</li> <li>V. Tamilselvi et al., “IoT Based Health Monitoring System,” <em>ICACCS 2020</em>, 2020.</li> <li>S. Rajkumar et al., “Health monitoring system using Raspberry Pi,” <em>BID 2017</em>, 2018.</li> <li>M. Hamim et al., “IoT Based remote health monitoring system,” <em>ICREST 2019</em>, 2019.</li> <li>V. Pardeshi et al., “Health monitoring systems using IoT and Raspberry Pi – A review,” <em>ICIMIA 2017</em>, 2017.</li> </ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Biomedical-Engineering"/><category term="IoT"/><category term="code"/><category term="Project"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A cost-effective remote health monitoring solution designed to continuously assess non-critical patients while reducing hospital congestion—especially during emergencies such as the COVID-19 pandemic.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">(PDF) Making Threads in SolidWorks</title><link href="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2025/pdf-making-threads-in-solidworks/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="(PDF) Making Threads in SolidWorks"/><published>2025-12-21T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-12-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2025/pdf-making-threads-in-solidworks</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2025/pdf-making-threads-in-solidworks/"><![CDATA[<p>OutlineDownload Free PDF…7 pagesComputer-Aided Design of Traditional Jigs and Fixtures, 2021Conventional design of jigs and fixtures has become unsuitable given the requirements of modern technology and complexity and diversity in the production with the rapid update of products. Computer-aided design (CAD) of jigs and fixtures is an effective solution in this direction. The current paper focuses on a computer-aided design of the traditional jigs and fixtures and developed a system containing tailor-made software, created using the Visual Basic programming language and installed on it the viewer screen to show the part. The developed system has been built by connecting Visual Basic programming language to the SolidWorks software on which the part is drawn and saved as STEP AP-203 file format, and the system reads and extracts the data from the STEP AP-203 file. Heuristic rules of feature recognition are pre-prepared for checking the extracted geometric data and deciding which data shape will represent the machining feature; then, the system provides the optimum design of the traditional jigs and fixtures for a group of hollow cylindrical parts that contain a group of cross-holes on the cylinder body, whether perpendicular or offset from the cylinder’s axis, (inclined or inclined offset, or blind or through, by applying pre-prepared heuristic rules for the design of traditional jigs and fixtures.2023 IEEE 17th International Symposium on Applied Computational Intelligence and Informatics (SACI), 2023In this paper, a carpenter software is designed and implemented that supports the daily management processes (customers, orders, inventory) and generates a pattern from the product descriptions based on the parameters specified. During the pattern generation process, a two-dimensional optimization is performed to generate a pattern that includes horizontal or vertical cuts, depending on the target machine, on which the position of the required parts is placed, generates the smallest material loss and uses leftover materials from the past. From the application, the pattern can be viewed and extracted online or in PDF format. This all is implemented in a layered web application with a modern approach.THREE DIMENSIONAL MODELING AND LOADING SIMULATION OF A STANDARD THREADED FASTENER IN CAD ENVIRONMENT (ТРИМЕРНО МОДЕЛИРАНЕ И СИМУЛАЦИОННО НАТОВАРВАНЕ В CAD-СРЕДА KНА СТАНДАРТНО РЕЗБОВО СЪЕДИНЕНИЕ ), 2006Abstract. The techniques of correct three dimensional modeling of geometry parameters of thread and of the body of standard threaded fasteners (bolt and nut) in CAD environment of software product SolidWoprks’2005 are presented. The model of joint are put under loading simulation and the zones of concentrations of stresses are determined. The values and distribution of stresses from loading simulation and from calculation and from experiments known from literature are compared. Key words: threaded fasteners, CAD, finite element method.This paper presents a mechanistic model for prediction of the thread milling forces. The mechanics of cutting for thread milling is analyzed similar to the end milling process but with modified cutting edge geometry. The chip thickness and cutting force models are developed considering the unique geometry of the tool. The model has been calibrated for 6061 Aluminum and validated. The effects of tool and thread geometry have been studied using the model. rZenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research), 2012Modular fixtures (MFs) are very important tools in manufacturing processes in terms of reduction the cost and the production time. This paper introduces an automated approach for assembling MFs elements by employing SolidWorks as a powerful 3D CAD software. Visual Basic (VB) programming language was applied integrating with SolidWorks API (Application programming interface) functions. This integration allowed creating plug-in file and generating new menus in the SolidWorks environment. The menus allow the user to select, insert, and assemble MFs elements.Revista Española de Educación Comparada, 2020Latin American higher education in recent decades has experienced the main world trends, relative to the massification of student access, insufficient state funding, increase of private institutions in the tertiary education system, as well as a regional debate on its consideration as a good public guaranteed by the State, increasing the relevance of the university mission in solving global needs. Through the comparative method developed through a documentary analysis, the influence in Latin America of the Supranational Policy on social responsibility of UNESCO higher education institutions is analyzed. The results show this influence in the Region, through the Declarations of the UNESCO World Conferences on Higher Education, materialized in the actions developed by the International Institute for Higher Education in Latin America and the Caribbean (IESALC), such as the holding of the Regional Conferences on Higher Education or the creation of the Regional Observatory of Social Resp…Canadian Journal of Cardiology, 2009Effect of operator and institutional volume on clinical outcomes after percutaneous coronary interventions performed in Canada and the United States: A brief report from the Enhanced Suppression of the Platelet glycoprotein IIb/IIIa Receptor with Integrilin Therapy (ESPRIT) study. Can J Cardiol 2009;25(8):e269-e272. The Enhanced Suppression of the Platelet glycoprotein IIb/IIIa Receptor with Integrilin Therapy (ESPRIT) trial compared the use of eptifibatide with placebo in 2064 coronary intervention patients. It was previously reported that Canadian patients had reduced rates of 30-day and one-year death, myocardial infarction (MI) or targetvessel revascularization (TVR) compared with patients in the United States (US). OBJECTIVE: To examine whether operator or institutional volume differences explain the regional variation in clinical outcome. METHODS AND RESULTS: Each site received an operator and institutional volume survey. Fifty-seven sites (62%) returned complete data on 1338 patients. In this smaller cohort, Canadian patients had reduced rates of 30-day and one-year death, MI or TVR compared with US patients (6.3% versus 10.3% and 14.9% versus 20.1%, respectively; P&lt;0.05 for both comparisons). Among 176 physicians with a median of 13 years experience, the median operator volume was 200 cases per year. Operators with fewer than 100 cases per year had higher rates of 30-day death, MI or TVR (13.2% versus 8.7%; P=0.18) and large MI (7.7% versus 3.3%; P=0.06) than those with 100 or more cases per year. The median institutional volume was 1064 cases per year. Canadian and US centres had similar operator and institutional volumes. By multivariate modelling, operator volume was not predictive of adverse clinical events. However, the rates of 30-day and one-year death, MI or TVR fell by 3% for every 100 patients treated by the institution (OR 0.97; P=0.058 and P=0.002, respectively). Enrollment in Canada was associated with improved outcomes at 30 days (OR 0.50; P=0.001) and one year (OR 0.66; P=0.001) despite inclusion of volume variables in the models. CONCLUSIONS: In the ESPRIT study, institutional volume was associated with a modest reduction in risk of death, MI or TVR over short-and long-term follow-up periods. The Canadian and US investigators and institutions selected in ESPRIT had similar annual procedural volumes. Therefore, volume variables did not explain the differential risk of clinical events observed for patients enrolled in the two countries.2013Bibliografía recomendada para el Tema: 6.1.-Conceptos ácido-base. Definiciones de Arrhenius, Brønsted-Lowry, Lux-Flood y Lewis. Ácidos y bases duros y blandos (clasificación de Pearson). Medida de la fortaleza ácido-base. Variación de la acidez / basicidad en la tabla periódica: óxidos básicos y ácidos, basicidad de los hidróxidos, acidez de los oxoácidos.European Journal of Operational Research, 2002Sensitivity analysis in investment problems is an important tool to determine which factors can jeopardize the future of the investment. Information on the probability distribution of those factors that affect the investment is mostly lacking. In those situations the analysts have two options: (i) apply a method that does not require knowledge of that distribution, or (ii) make assumptions about the distribution. In both approaches sensitivity analysis should result in practical information about the actual importance of potential factors. For approach (i) we apply statistical design of experiments (DOE) in combination with regression analysis or meta-modeling. For approach (ii) we investigate five types of relationships between the model output and each individual factor; Pearson’s D, Spearman’s rank correlation, and location, dispersion, and statistical dependence. We introduce two distribution types popular with practitioners: uniform and triangular. In an environmental case study both approaches identify the same factors as important.Still studying.Procedia Manufacturing, 2015The modulated tool path (MTP) chip breaking process has been modified to improve chip management capabilities and to prevent large chip nest accumulations commonly encountered in threading operations. The use of MTP to create segmented chips requires a different approach for threading operations than for normal MTP turning operations, although the fundamental principal is the same. The primary difference between MTP for threading and for straight turning is that the part surface that the tool repeatedly engages and disengages, during the modulation process, is the thread root rather than the cut face. The threading MTP part program developed in this paper is capable of machining a thread with the desired lead, depth, undercut angle, and taper angle while also producing segmented chips.International Journal of …, 2006This paper presents a mechanistic model for prediction of the thread milling forces. The mechanics of cutting for thread milling is analyzed similar to the end milling process but with modified cutting edge geometry. The chip thickness and cutting force models are developed considering the unique geometry of the tool. The model has been calibrated for 6061 Aluminum and validated. The effects of tool and thread geometry have been studied using the model. rVariations in cutting forces were investigated experimentally depending on infeed angles and cutting areas in the external threading on a CNC turning centre. For this purpose, AISI 1050 workpiece material, 16ERM AG 60 IC 908 cutting tool, and SER 2525 M16 tool holder were used. External threading operations were performed using 0 • , 14.5 • , 15 • , 27.5 • , and 30 • infeed angles while the cutting speed was held constant at 100 m/min for the experiments. Experimental results showed that the infeed angle and cutting area had significant effects on the main cutting force and the radial force components were considerable in threading operations in terms of energy consumption. In addition, the optimum infeed angle was 30 • in the external threading operations in terms of cutting forces.Acta Polytechnica Hungarica, 2014Different tool geometries have been developed by leading companies in the tool industry to different aims of application. The fastest progress can be observed in the development of coatings, in spite of this it can be noticed that there are only few coating types, but they can be used in a wide range. For users it offers the great advantage to select appropriate tool easier. Coating types, developed specially to individual aim of application, offer much better solution, compared to the generally used coating types. Platit AG, dealing with the development of optimised coating types, has requested our specialised group to carry out tests on specialised coating types. Our present study is going to summarise the results of the tests, carried out with thread forming tools.The International Journal of Advanced Manufacturing Technology, 2014is an open access repository that collects the work of Arts et Métiers ParisTech researchers and makes it freely available over the web where possible. This is an author-deposited version published in: http://sam.ensam.eu Handle ID: .http://hdl.handle.net/10985/8565 To cite this version : Vishal SHARMA, Guillaume FROMENTIN, Gérard POULACHON, Romain BRENDLEN -Investigation of tool geometry effect and penetration strategies on cutting forces during thread millingPuji dan syukur kehadirat Tuhan Yang Maha Esa. Atas rahmat dan hidayah Nya, saya sebagai penyusun dapat menyelesaikan tugas makalah yang berjudul “Memperhitungkan PPh 21” dengan tepat waktu. Makalahini disusun untuk memenuhi tugas Mata Kuliah Perpajakan 2. Selain itu, makalah ini bertujuan menambah wawasan tentang apa itu definisi pajak dan apa saja yang menjadi dasar hukum pajak penghasilan bagi pembaca dan juga saya sendirisebagai penyusun.Tyndale Bulletin, 1999Socio-rhetorical interpretation pursues a richly textured exegesis of Scripture through co-ordinating multiple methods of reading and investigating texts. This interpretive model is put to the test as it is applied to Hebrews 6:4-8. In this, the first instalment of a two-part article, Hebrews 6:4-8 is analysed within the contexts of classical rhetoric, Jewish and Graeco-Roman intertexture, and prominent aspects of the first-century social and cultural environment. This passage presents an argument ‘from the contrary’ supporting the author’s deliberative agenda of promoting commitment to Jesus and fellow believers, drawing heavily on the social codes of patronage obligations as well as a wide spectrum of intertextual resources. Perseverance is shown to be the only just and expedient course of action, since it alone preserves obligations of gratitude. Part 2 of this article (to appear in Tyndale Bulletin 50.2) will examine the ideology promoted within the passage and how it contribute…2015Insinöörityö 22.04.2015 Tiivistelmä Tekijä(t) Otsikko Sivumäärä Aika Ilari Stenroos CLT-tilaelementtien käyttö asuinkerrostalojen ullakoiden lisärakentamisessa 57 sivua + 10 liitettä 22.04.2015 Tutkinto Insinööri (AMK) Koulutusohjelma Rakennustekniikka Suuntautumisvaihtoehto Rakennetekniikka Ohjaaja(t) Nuorempi rakennesuunnittelija Arto Hokkanen Ryhmäpäällikkö Heikki Aronen Lehtori Jouni Kalliomäki Tämän opinnäytetyön tavoitteena oli tutkia CLT-levyistä koottujen tilaelementtien käyttömahdollisuuksia 1920 -1950 -luvuilla rakennettujen asuinkerrostalojen käyttöullakoiden lisärakentamisessa. Tilaelementtien tarkoituksena on lyhentää rakennusaikaa, jolloin vesikaton aukioloaika lyhenee ja siten myös aika, jona rakenteet ovat alttiina kosteusvaurioille. CLT-levyt ovat 60 mm -400 mm paksuja massiivipuisia levyjä, jotka koostuvat ristikkäin liimatuista kerroksista, josta tulee nimi CLT -Cross Laminated Timber. Opinnäytetyössä tarkasteltiin aluksi tilaelementtien käyttömahdollisuuksia ullakkorakentamisessa yleensä, eli esimerkiksi ulkomittojen ja -muotojen sekä tuentamahdollisuuksien mukaan. Työssä tutkittiin uusien kantavien rakenteiden sijoittamista vanhaan runkoon, kun yläpohjatyyppinä on 1920 -1950 -luvuilla paljon käytetty alalaattapalkisto. Yhtenä suurimpana osana työhön kuului myös CLT-rakenteisten vaipparakenteiden kosteusteknisen toiminnan tutkiminen, jonka tuloksia apuna käyttäen luotiin eri vaipparakennetyyppejä rakennetyyppikirjastoon. Lisäksi työhön kuului palomääräysten asettamien suojaverhousvaatimusten selvittäminen sekä CLT-rakenteiden mitoituksen perusteiden tutkiminen. Selvitystyöstä ilmeni, että CLT-tilaelementtien hyödyntäminen ullakkorakentamisessa on mahdollista, mutta yleisesti tilaelementtien käyttömahdollisuuksia rajaa esimerkiksi ullakon kattokorkeus, joka on usein enemmän mitä tilaelementtien suositeltu kokonaiskorkeus on. Itse CLT:n käytölle rakennustarvikkeena ei selvitystyössä löytynyt esteitä. CLT:llä on paljon hyviä ominaisuuksia, joista on hyötyä tilaelementtirakentamisen kannalta. Tällaisia ovat esimerkiksi levyn korkea jäykkyys, keveys ja ilmatiiveys. Opinnäytetyön tarkoituksena oli myös tuottaa yritykselle lyhyt suunnitteluohje sekä rakennedetalji-ja rakennetyyppikirjasto. Lisäksi opinnäytetyössä tehtiin tilaelementtejä kantavien uusien teräspalkkien nopea alkumitoitustaulukko. Taulukon avulla voi tehdä hankesuunnittelua varten karkean arvion tarvittavasta teräspalkin koosta palkkien jännevälin ja jakovälin perusteella. Koska selvitystyössä ei tullut vastaan asioita, jotka estäisivät CLT-tilaelementtien käytön ullakoiden lisärakentamisessa, voidaan sitä pitää vaihtoehtoisena rakennustapana yrityksen tulevissa ullakon lisärakentamiskohteissa. Lisäksi työ antaa karkeita ohjeita ullakon CLT-tilaelementtien suunnitteluun.AI Flashcard: Applied Biomedical Engineering Using Artificial Intelligence and Cognitive Models, 2025Some examples as an AI Flashcards of my book from Academic Press - Elsevier, “Applied Biomedical Engineering Using Artificial Intelligence and Cognitive Models”. The goal of this book is Analyze and Modeling Non-motor symptoms form diseases, injuries, and diseases with Artificial Intelligence (AI), Machine Learning (ML), Deep Learning (DL) and cognitive learning (CC). These models will be used to study how the nervous system and musculoskeletal system obey movement orders from the brain, as well as the mental processes of the information during cognition when injuries illness and disease are present in the human bodySAE Technical Paper Series, 2009NO x Modelling of a Complete Diesel Engine / SCR System C. Ericson Licentiate thesis, Division of Combustion Engines, ISRN LUTMDN/TMHP-07/</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Making Threads in SolidWorks]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">(PDF) Measuring Pen – A digital device to measure distance</title><link href="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2025/pdf-measuring-pen-a-digital-device-to-measure-distance/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="(PDF) Measuring Pen – A digital device to measure distance"/><published>2025-12-20T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-12-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2025/pdf-measuring-pen--a-digital-device-to-measure-distance</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2025/pdf-measuring-pen-a-digital-device-to-measure-distance/"><![CDATA[<p>OutlineDownload Free PDF…3 pagesThis is a new approach on the section of measurement. Today, most of the garment companies are producing lot of clothes. While producing clothes they have to face lot of problems. For an example time of delivery and accuracy in clothes size. A traditional way of measuring a cloth is using a tape. Due to that there may be errors in measuring length and it take times time to check the length using tape. Main aim of this mini project is to solve these problems using a microcontroller measuring system. This will reduce the time taken for the cutting and will measure accurately. For this project Arduino Nano is used as the microcontroller for performing the algorithmic work.Poznan University of Technology Academic Journals. Electrical Engineering, 2015W artykule przedstawiono propozycję wykorzystania programu Dialux, służącego obliczeniom oświetleniowym, do symulacji radiacyjnego przekazywania ciepła przez promienniki podczerwieni. Przeprowadzono porównanie wyników symulacji dla prostego układu wymiany radiacyjnej otrzymanych z obliczeń teoretycznych oraz z symulacji. Ponadto przedstawiono praktyczne wykorzystanie obliczeń symulacyjnych dokonywanych przy użyciu tego programu w celu wyznaczenia rozkładu natężenia napromienienia dla bardziej skomplikowanych radiacyjnych układów grzejnych.Academia Oncology, 2025Colorectal cancer (CRC) continues to be a major contributor to global cancer-related mortality, with <italic>KRAS</italic> and <italic>NRAS</italic> oncogenic mutations playing a pivotal role in tumorigenesis and therapeutic resistance. These genetic alterations drive uncontrolled proliferation and modulate responses to targeted treatments, significantly influencing clinical outcomes. This review examines the prevalence and prognostic implications of <italic>KRAS</italic> and <italic>NRAS</italic> mutations, with particular attention paid to the Venezuelan population. Reported frequencies in Venezuela (13–23% for <italic>KRAS</italic> and 1.6–2.6% for <italic>NRAS</italic>) are markedly lower than global averages (36–45% for <italic>KRAS</italic>), a discrepancy potentially attributable to population-specific genetic variations or methodological constraints of conventional sequencing techniques, which may lack sensitivity for variant detection. The presence of <italic>RAS</italic> mutations is a well-established biomarker of resistance to anti-EGFR monoclonal antibodies, necessitating alternative treatment regimens for affected patients. Although novel agents such as <italic>KRAS</italic> G12C inhibitors exhibit therapeutic potential, their efficacy remains under investigation in clinical trials, highlighting the need for regionally tailored drug development and improved access to innovative therapies in Venezuela. Beyond proliferative signaling, <italic>KRAS</italic>-mediated oncogenesis involves metabolic adaptation, angiogenic activation, and immune system evasion, underscoring its multifaceted role in CRC progression. Advanced molecular diagnostic techniques, such as next-generation sequencing (NGS) and circulating tumor DNA (ctDNA) analysis, have significantly improved the detection of oncogenic mutations, offering higher sensitivity and specificity compared to traditional methods. However, their widespread adoption in resource-limited settings remains hindered by infrastructural, economic, and technical barriers.Academia Biology, 2025Correction InformationIn the original publication, there were errors in a data point described within the Abstract and Conclusions. These errors were unintentionally introduced during the final proofreading process and do not affect the actual results, raw data, or the overall conclusions and interpretations of the study, as the finding was correctly detailed in the main text.The original (incorrect) sentence in the Abstract stated: “An analysis of the phylogenetic relationship showed a significant degree of genetic diversity with &lt;50% bootstrap values, indicating the genetic distinctiveness of the accessions.” The corrected sentence in the Abstract now reads: “An analysis of the phylogenetic relationship revealed a significant degree of genetic diversity, with most bootstrap values exceeding 50%, indicating the genetic distinctiveness of accessions.” The original (incorrect) sentence in the Conclusions stated:”An analysis of the phylogenetic relationship revealed a high level of genetic diversity with &lt;50% bootstrap values, indicating the genetic distinctiveness of the accessions.” The corrected sentence in Conclusions now reads: “An analysis of the phylogenetic relationship revealed a significant degree of genetic diversity, with most bootstrap values exceeding 50%, indicating the genetic distinctiveness of accessions.”The Editor-in-Chief has reviewed and approved this correction, and the original publication has also been updatedOsservatorio Nazionale sulle reti d’impresa 2024, 2025The 2024 edition of the Observatory on interfirm network contracts provides an extensive analysis of the evolution, performance, and management of these networks (“contratti di rete”) in Italy. Drawing on comprehensive data from InfoCamere up to the end of 2024, combined with insights from surveys conducted in 2019, 2021, and 2023, the report identifies clear trends and strategic implications. This edition highlights the continued growth of network contracts, which reached a total of 9,630 by the end of 2024, involving approximately 50,000 enterprises nationwide. Notably, there has been a significant resurgence of micro-networks and intra-provincial collaborations, alongside increased sector-specific clustering. The agrifood sector leads in participation, followed by mechanical engineering and construction. The findings underscore the growing prominence of female entrepreneurship within these networks. Conversely, youth and foreign entrepreneurship remain limited, suggesting untapped potential and opportunities for policy interventions to enhance inclusivity. Geographical analyses reveal distinct regional patterns, with Veneto, Lombardy, and Emilia-Romagna standing out. The Observatory also explores network resilience through case studies such as Slow Bike Tourism and Jubea, which illustrate the flexible, responsive nature of these structures in navigating economic uncertainties. Additionally, the analysis examines financial strategies, particularly mini-bond issuance, highlighting missed opportunities to leverage network affiliation as a driver for attracting investment. Overall, the study emphasizes the strategic importance of adaptive governance models, promoting internal coordination, fostering trust among members, and enhancing organizational performance. This comprehensive evaluation offers valuable insights for businesses and policymakers seeking to optimize network effectiveness and economic resilience. Furthermore, the study highlights the pivotal role of associations, cooperatives, and foundations in facilitating network formation, strategic coordination, and the promotion of innovation and competitiveness.Programa de Fiestas de Cercedilla, 2025En octubre de 1925 el Ayuntamiento de Cercedilla inaugura su Fábrica de la Luz, un proyecto municipal pionero hoy convertido en un interesante museo2010Aún recuerdo aquellos días en los que miraba los tablones de la Facultad de Químicas buscando una oportunidad para investigar. El destino quiso que terminase estudiando la grasa láctea y, pese a los momentos duros, no puedo estar más que agradecida por las coordenadas en las que ha transcurrido este trabajo. En primer lugar, quiero agradecer a mis directores de tesis, la Dra. Manuela Juárez y el Dr. Miguel Ángel de la Fuente, el darme la oportunidad de dedicarme a lo que siempre quise hacer y su inestimable ayuda. No creo que haya muchos “jefes” que se impliquen tanto… La curiosidad por los resultados de cada experimento, la pasión que demuestran en su trabajo, serán siempre mis modelos científicos. Muchas gracias, Manoli, por trabajar intensamente en esta tesis a pesar de todos tus compromisos, por leerte mi Introducción en el AVE en vez de dar una cabezada, y especialmente, por tu apoyo personal en momentos clave. ¡Y qué decirle a Miguel Ángel! Gracias por meter prisa, por tus correcciones cervantinas, por los planning difíciles de cumplir, por tu compromiso, por las cañas en Delias… Con el tiempo, creo que hemos formado un buen tándem. Espero que no se te hayan quitado las ganas de dirigir otra tesis y que otros becarios aprendan como yo a tu lado.Still studying.— This paper deals with the design and implementation of a simple HMC6352 2-axis digital compass. Most compasses have been of the analogue type with magnetic needles as pointers. Replacing the “ old “ magnetic needle compass or the gyrocompass by an electronic solution offers advantages like having a solid-state component without moving parts and the ease of interfacing with other electronic systems. In this work, the aim is to design and implement a digital compass. To realize this, we made use of HMC6352 which is a 2-axis MR (magneto-resistive) sensor from Honeywell, Arduino Uno board with an onboard ATmega328 microcontroller chip, and a 16x2 character Liquid Crystal Display (LCD).We adopted the magneto-resistive (MR) technology as compared to flux-gate sensors common in most electronic compasses which has the disadvantage of making the device bulky. The trial test carried out with the completed HMC6352 digital compass showed a reading of 232.8 degrees West indicating its effectiveness in direction finding.Journal of Tourism, Hotels and Heritage2007Clinical Immunology (Fourth Edition), 2013Journal of Entomology and Zoology studies, 2025This study provides a comprehensive overview of aspergillosis, also known as brooder pneumonia, a fatal fungal disease significantly impacting poultry health and the industry. The primary objectives are to elucidate the etiology, pathogenesis, clinical manifestations, diagnosis, treatment, and prevention strategies for aspergillosis in poultry. The disease is caused mainly by Aspergillus fumigatus and Aspergillus flavus, ubiquitous environmental fungi that produce spores capable of infecting young and immunocompromised birds through inhalation or penetration of eggshells. The study emphasizes that environmental factors such as poor ventilation, high humidity, organic matter accumulation, and mismanagement practices are critical predisposing factors facilitating fungal growth and spore dissemination, especially in hatcheries and poultry houses. The material and methods involve reviewing existing literature, analyzing clinical and postmortem findings, and evaluating diagnostic techniques such as histopathology, culture, and molecular assays. Results indicate that aspergillosis manifests predominantly as acute or chronic respiratory disease, with clinical signs including nasal discharge, dyspnea, gasping, ocular lesions, and neurological symptoms like torticollis and paralysis. Gross pathology reveals granulomatous lesions in lungs, air sacs, and other organs, often with characteristic plaques. Diagnosis relies on clinical history, lesion examination, fungal isolation, and microscopic identification. Treatment options are limited and often ineffective; antifungal agents like itraconazole and amphotericin B are used, complemented by environmental management and supportive care. Prevention remains the most effective approach, focusing on stringent sanitation, adequate ventilation, biosecurity, and control of environmental contamination to reduce spore load. The findings underscore that controlling environmental factors and early intervention are vital to mitigate outbreaks. In conclusion, integrated management encompassing hygiene, environmental control, and judicious use of antifungal agents is essential to combat aspergillosis, safeguarding poultry health, and reducing economic losses.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is a new approach on the section of measurement. Today, most of the garment companies are producing lot of clothes. While producing clothes they have to face lot of problems. For an example time of delivery and accuracy in clothes size. A]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Google Gemini updates: Flash 1.5, Gemma 2 and Project Astra</title><link href="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2024/google-gemini-updates-flash-15-gemma-2-and-project-astra/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Google Gemini updates: Flash 1.5, Gemma 2 and Project Astra"/><published>2024-05-14T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-05-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2024/google-gemini-updates-flash-15-gemma-2-and-project-astra</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2024/google-gemini-updates-flash-15-gemma-2-and-project-astra/"><![CDATA[<p>Learn more:Learn more:Learn more:Learn more:Learn more:Learn more:May 14, 2024 We’re introducing a series of updates across the Gemini family of models, including the new 1.5 Flash, our lightweight model for speed and efficiency, and Project Astra, our vision for the future of AI assistants. In December, we launched our first natively multimodal model Gemini 1.0 in three sizes: Ultra, Pro and Nano. Just a few months later we released 1.5 Pro, with enhanced performance and a breakthrough long context window of 1 million tokens.Developers and enterprise customers have been putting 1.5 Pro to use in incredible ways and finding its long context window, multimodal reasoning capabilities and impressive overall performance incredibly useful.We know from user feedback that some applications need lower latency and a lower cost to serve. This inspired us to keep innovating, so today, we’re introducing Gemini 1.5 Flash: a model that’s lighter-weight than 1.5 Pro, and designed to be fast and efficient to serve at scale.Both 1.5 Pro and 1.5 Flash are available in public preview with a 1 million token context window in Google AI Studio and Vertex AI. And now, 1.5 Pro is also available with a 2 million token context window via waitlist to developers using the API and to Google Cloud customers.We’re also introducing updates across the Gemini family of models, announcing our next generation of open models, Gemma 2, and sharing progress on the future of AI assistants, with Project Astra.Context lengths of leading foundation models compared with Gemini 1.5’s 2 million token capability1.5 Flash is the newest addition to the Gemini model family and the fastest Gemini model served in the API. It’s optimized for high-volume, high-frequency tasks at scale, is more cost-efficient to serve and features our breakthrough long context window.While it’s a lighter weight model than 1.5 Pro, it’s highly capable of multimodal reasoning across vast amounts of information and delivers impressive quality for its size.The new Gemini 1.5 Flash model is optimized for speed and efficiency, is highly capable of multimodal reasoning and features our breakthrough long context window.1.5 Flash excels at summarization, chat applications, image and video captioning, data extraction from long documents and tables, and more. This is because it’s been trained by 1.5 Pro through a process called “distillation,” where the most essential knowledge and skills from a larger model are transferred to a smaller, more efficient model.Read more about 1.5 Flash in our updated Gemini 1.5 technical report, on the Gemini technology page, and learn about 1.5 Flash’s availability and pricing.Over the last few months, we’ve significantly improved 1.5 Pro, our best model for general performance across a wide range of tasks.Beyond extending its context window to 2 million tokens, we’ve enhanced its code generation, logical reasoning and planning, multi-turn conversation, and audio and image understanding through data and algorithmic advances. We see strong improvements on public and internal benchmarks for each of these tasks.1.5 Pro can now follow increasingly complex and nuanced instructions, including ones that specify product-level behavior involving role, format and style. We’ve improved control over the model’s responses for specific use cases, like crafting the persona and response style of a chat agent or automating workflows through multiple function calls. And we’ve enabled users to steer model behavior by setting system instructions.We added audio understanding in the Gemini API and Google AI Studio, so 1.5 Pro can now reason across image and audio for videos uploaded in Google AI Studio. And we’re now integrating 1.5 Pro into Google products, including Gemini Advanced and in Workspace apps.Read more about 1.5 Pro in our updated Gemini 1.5 technical report and on the Gemini technology page.Gemini Nano is expanding beyond text-only inputs to include images as well. Starting with Pixel, applications using Gemini Nano with Multimodality will be able to understand the world the way people do — not just through text, but also through sight, sound and spoken language.Read more about Gemini 1.0 Nano on Android.Today, we’re also sharing a series of updates to Gemma, our family of open models built from the same research and technology used to create the Gemini models.We’re announcing Gemma 2, our next generation of open models for responsible AI innovation. Gemma 2 has a new architecture designed for breakthrough performance and efficiency, and will be available in new sizes.The Gemma family is also expanding with PaliGemma, our first vision-language model inspired by PaLI-3. And we’ve upgraded our Responsible Generative AI Toolkit with LLM Comparator for evaluating the quality of model responses.Read more on the Developer blog.As part of Google DeepMind’s mission to build AI responsibly to benefit humanity, we’ve always wanted to develop universal AI agents that can be helpful in everyday life. That’s why today, we’re sharing our progress in building the future of AI assistants with Project Astra (advanced seeing and talking responsive agent).To be truly useful, an agent needs to understand and respond to the complex and dynamic world just like people do — and take in and remember what it sees and hears to understand context and take action. It also needs to be proactive, teachable and personal, so users can talk to it naturally and without lag or delay.While we’ve made incredible progress developing AI systems that can understand multimodal information, getting response time down to something conversational is a difficult engineering challenge. Over the past few years, we’ve been working to improve how our models perceive, reason and converse to make the pace and quality of interaction feel more natural.Building on Gemini, we’ve developed prototype agents that can process information faster by continuously encoding video frames, combining the video and speech input into a timeline of events, and caching this information for efficient recall.By leveraging our leading speech models, we also enhanced how they sound, giving the agents a wider range of intonations. These agents can better understand the context they’re being used in, and respond quickly, in conversation.With technology like this, it’s easy to envision a future where people could have an expert AI assistant by their side, through a phone or glasses. And some of these capabilities are coming to Google products, like the Gemini app and web experience, later this year.We’ve made incredible progress so far with our family of Gemini models, and we’re always striving to advance the state-of-the-art even further. By investing in a relentless production line of innovation, we’re able to explore new ideas at the frontier, while also unlocking the possibility of new and exciting Gemini use cases.Learn more about Gemini and its capabilities. Your information will be used in accordance with Google’s privacy policy.</p> <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>      Done. Just one step more.
    
      Check your inbox to confirm your subscription.
    You are already subscribed to our newsletter.
    You can also subscribe with a
    different email address
    
    .
    
  Let’s stay in touch. Get the latest news from Google in your inbox.
          Follow Us
</code></pre></div></div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re sharing updates across our Gemini family of models and a glimpse of Project Astra, our vision for the future of AI assistants.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Displaying External Posts on Your al-folio Blog</title><link href="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Displaying External Posts on Your al-folio Blog"/><published>2022-04-23T19:20:09-04:00</published><updated>2022-04-23T19:20:09-04:00</updated><id>https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog/"><![CDATA[<h3>External Posts on Your al-folio Blog</h3> <p>If you prefer publishing blog posts on medium.com or other external sources, starting version v0.5.0, <a href="https://github.com/alshedivat/al-folio">al-folio</a> lets you to display your external posts in the blog feed of your website! 🎉🎉</p> <p>Configuring external sources of super simple. After upgrading to v0.5.0, just add the following section to your _config.yml:</p> <pre>external_sources:<br />  - name: medium.com  # name of the source (arbitrary string)<br />    rss_url: <a href="https://medium.com/@al-folio/feed">https://medium.com/@&lt;your-medium-username&gt;/feed</a></pre> <p>The example above adds your medium.com blog post feed as an external source. But you can add arbitrary RSS feeds as sources.</p> <p>Any questions or suggestions? 👉 Start <a href="https://github.com/alshedivat/al-folio/discussions">a discussion on GitHub</a>!</p> <p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&amp;referrerSource=full_rss&amp;postId=b60a1d241a0a" width="1" height="1" alt=""/></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html">a distill-style blog post</title><link href="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2021/distill/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="a distill-style blog post"/><published>2021-05-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-05-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2021/distill</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://imtheva.github.io/blog/2021/distill/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="equations">Equations</h2> <p>This theme supports rendering beautiful math in inline and display modes using <a href="https://www.mathjax.org/">MathJax 3</a> engine. You just need to surround your math expression with <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">$$</code>, like <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">$$ E = mc^2 $$</code>. If you leave it inside a paragraph, it will produce an inline expression, just like \(E = mc^2\).</p> <p>In fact, you can also use a single dollar sign <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">$</code> to create inline formulas, such as <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">$ E = mc^2 $</code>, which will render as $ E = mc^2 $. This approach provides the same effect during TeX-based compilation, but visually it appears slightly less bold compared to double-dollar signs <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">$$</code>, making it blend more naturally with surrounding text.</p> <p>To use display mode, again surround your expression with <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">$$</code> and place it as a separate paragraph. Here is an example:</p> \[\left( \sum_{k=1}^n a_k b_k \right)^2 \leq \left( \sum_{k=1}^n a_k^2 \right) \left( \sum_{k=1}^n b_k^2 \right)\] <p>Note that MathJax 3 is <a href="https://docs.mathjax.org/en/latest/upgrading/whats-new-3.0.html">a major re-write of MathJax</a> that brought a significant improvement to the loading and rendering speed, which is now <a href="http://www.intmath.com/cg5/katex-mathjax-comparison.php">on par with KaTeX</a>.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="citations">Citations</h2> <p>Citations are then used in the article body with the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">&lt;d-cite&gt;</code> tag. The key attribute is a reference to the id provided in the bibliography. The key attribute can take multiple ids, separated by commas.</p> <p>The citation is presented inline like this: <d-cite key="gregor2015draw"></d-cite> (a number that displays more information on hover). If you have an appendix, a bibliography is automatically created and populated in it.</p> <p>Distill chose a numerical inline citation style to improve readability of citation dense articles and because many of the benefits of longer citations are obviated by displaying more information on hover. However, we consider it good style to mention author last names if you discuss something at length and it fits into the flow well — the authors are human and it’s nice for them to have the community associate them with their work.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="footnotes">Footnotes</h2> <p>Just wrap the text you would like to show up in a footnote in a <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">&lt;d-footnote&gt;</code> tag. The number of the footnote will be automatically generated.<d-footnote>This will become a hoverable footnote.</d-footnote></p> <hr/> <h2 id="code-blocks">Code Blocks</h2> <p>Syntax highlighting is provided within <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">&lt;d-code&gt;</code> tags. An example of inline code snippets: <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">&lt;d-code language="html"&gt;let x = 10;&lt;/d-code&gt;</code>. For larger blocks of code, add a <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">block</code> attribute:</p> <d-code block="" language="javascript"> var x = 25; function(x) { return x * x; } </d-code> <p><strong>Note:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">&lt;d-code&gt;</code> blocks do not look good in the dark mode. You can instead use the standard Jekyll syntax highlight with the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">highlight</code> liquid tag.</p> <figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-javascript" data-lang="javascript"><span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">x</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="mi">25</span><span class="p">;</span>
<span class="kd">function</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">x</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
<span class="k">return</span> <span class="nx">x</span> <span class="err">\</span><span class="o">*</span> <span class="nx">x</span><span class="p">;</span>
<span class="p">}</span></code></pre></figure> <p>You can also write standard Markdown code blocks in triple ticks with a language tag, for instance:</p> <div class="language-python highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">foo</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">x</span><span class="p">):</span>
  <span class="k">return</span> <span class="n">x</span>
</code></pre></div></div> <hr/> <h2 id="interactive-plots">Interactive Plots</h2> <p>You can add interative plots using plotly + iframes :framed_picture:</p> <div class="l-page"> <iframe src="/assets/plotly/demo.html" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" height="500px" width="100%" style="border: 1px dashed grey;"></iframe> </div> <p>The plot must be generated separately and saved into an HTML file. To generate the plot that you see above, you can use the following code snippet:</p> <figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-python" data-lang="python"><span class="kn">import</span> <span class="n">pandas</span> <span class="k">as</span> <span class="n">pd</span>
<span class="kn">import</span> <span class="n">plotly.express</span> <span class="k">as</span> <span class="n">px</span>
<span class="n">df</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="n">pd</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nf">read_csv</span><span class="p">(</span>
<span class="sh">'</span><span class="s">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/plotly/datasets/master/earthquakes-23k.csv</span><span class="sh">'</span>
<span class="p">)</span>
<span class="n">fig</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="n">px</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nf">density_mapbox</span><span class="p">(</span>
<span class="n">df</span><span class="p">,</span>
<span class="n">lat</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="sh">'</span><span class="s">Latitude</span><span class="sh">'</span><span class="p">,</span>
<span class="n">lon</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="sh">'</span><span class="s">Longitude</span><span class="sh">'</span><span class="p">,</span>
<span class="n">z</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="sh">'</span><span class="s">Magnitude</span><span class="sh">'</span><span class="p">,</span>
<span class="n">radius</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="mi">10</span><span class="p">,</span>
<span class="n">center</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="nf">dict</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">lat</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="n">lon</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="mi">180</span><span class="p">),</span>
<span class="n">zoom</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">,</span>
<span class="n">mapbox_style</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="sh">"</span><span class="s">stamen-terrain</span><span class="sh">"</span><span class="p">,</span>
<span class="p">)</span>
<span class="n">fig</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nf">show</span><span class="p">()</span>
<span class="n">fig</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nf">write_html</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="sh">'</span><span class="s">assets/plotly/demo.html</span><span class="sh">'</span><span class="p">)</span></code></pre></figure> <hr/> <h2 id="details-boxes">Details boxes</h2> <p>Details boxes are collapsible boxes which hide additional information from the user. They can be added with the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">details</code> liquid tag:</p> <details><summary>Click here to know more</summary> <p>Additional details, where math \(2x - 1\) and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">code</code> is rendered correctly.</p> </details> <hr/> <h2 id="mermaid">Mermaid</h2> <p>This theme supports creating diagrams directly in markdown using <a href="https://mermaid.js.org/">Mermaid</a>. Mermaid enables users to render flowcharts, sequence diagrams, class diagrams, Gantt charts, and more. Simply embed the diagram syntax within a mermaid code block.</p> <p>To create a Gantt chart, you can use the following syntax:</p> <div class="language-markdown highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="p">```</span><span class="nl">mermaid
</span><span class="sb">gantt
    dateFormat  YYYY-MM-DD
    title A Gantt Diagram

    section Section
    Task A           :a1, 2025-01-01, 30d
    Task B           :after a1, 20d
    Task C           :2025-01-10, 12d</span>
<span class="p">```</span>
</code></pre></div></div> <p>And here’s how it will be rendered:</p> <pre><code class="language-mermaid">gantt
    dateFormat  YYYY-MM-DD
    title A Gantt Diagram

    section Section
    Task A           :a1, 2025-01-01, 30d
    Task B           :after a1, 20d
    Task C           :2025-01-10, 12d
</code></pre> <p>Similarly, you can also use it to create beautiful class diagrams:</p> <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>```mermaid
classDiagram
direction LR
    class Animal {
        +String species
        +int age
        +makeSound()
    }
    class Dog {
        +String breed
        +bark()
    }
    class Cat {
        +String color
        +meow()
    }
    class Bird {
        +String wingSpan
        +fly()
    }
    class Owner {
        +String name
        +int age
        +adoptAnimal(Animal animal)
    }

    Animal &lt;|-- Dog
    Animal &lt;|-- Cat
    Animal &lt;|-- Bird
    Owner "1" --&gt; "0..*" Animal

    Dog : +fetch()
    Cat : +purr()
    Bird : +sing()
```
</code></pre></div></div> <p>It will be presented as:</p> <pre><code class="language-mermaid">classDiagram
direction LR
    class Animal {
        +String species
        +int age
        +makeSound()
    }
    class Dog {
        +String breed
        +bark()
    }
    class Cat {
        +String color
        +meow()
    }
    class Bird {
        +String wingSpan
        +fly()
    }
    class Owner {
        +String name
        +int age
        +adoptAnimal(Animal animal)
    }

    Animal &lt;|-- Dog
    Animal &lt;|-- Cat
    Animal &lt;|-- Bird
    Owner "1" --&gt; "0..*" Animal

    Dog : +fetch()
    Cat : +purr()
    Bird : +sing()
</code></pre> <p>With Mermaid, you can easily add clear and dynamic diagrams to enhance your blog content.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="diff2html">Diff2Html</h2> <p>This theme also supports integrating <a href="https://github.com/rtfpessoa/diff2html">Diff2Html</a>, a tool that beautifully renders code differences (diffs) directly in markdown. Diff2Html is ideal for showcasing code changes, allowing you to clearly present additions, deletions, and modifications. It’s perfect for code reviews, documentation, and tutorials where step-by-step code changes need to be highlighted—you can even introduce changes across multiple files at once.</p> <div class="language-markdown highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="p">```</span><span class="nl">diff2html
</span><span class="sb">diff --git a/utils/mathUtils.js b/utils/mathUtils.js
index 3b5f3d1..c7f9b2e 100644
--- a/utils/mathUtils.js
+++ b/utils/mathUtils.js
@@ -1,8 +1,12 @@
-// Basic math utilities
+// Extended math utilities with additional functions

-export function calculateArea(radius) {
-    const PI = 3.14159;
+export function calculateCircleMetrics(radius) {
+    const PI = Math.PI;
     const area = PI * radius ** 2;
+    const circumference = 2 * PI * radius;
+
+    if (!isValidRadius(radius)) throw new Error("Invalid radius");
+
     return { area, circumference };
 }

-export function validateRadius(radius) {
+export function isValidRadius(radius) {
     return typeof radius === 'number' &amp;&amp; radius &gt; 0;
 }

diff --git a/main.js b/main.js
index 5f6a9c3..b7d4e8f 100644
--- a/main.js
+++ b/main.js
@@ -2,9 +2,12 @@
 import { calculateCircleMetrics } from './utils/mathUtils';

-function displayCircleMetrics(radius) {
-    const { area } = calculateCircleMetrics(radius);
+function displayCircleMetrics(radius) {
+    const { area, circumference } = calculateCircleMetrics(radius);
     console.log(`Area: ${area}`);
+    console.log(`Circumference: ${circumference}`);
 }

-displayCircleMetrics(5);
+try {
+    displayCircleMetrics(5);
+} catch (error) {
+    console.error("Error:", error.message);
+}</span>
<span class="p">```</span>
</code></pre></div></div> <p>Here’s how it will look when rendered with Diff2Html:</p> <pre><code class="language-diff2html">diff --git a/utils/mathUtils.js b/utils/mathUtils.js
index 3b5f3d1..c7f9b2e 100644
--- a/utils/mathUtils.js
+++ b/utils/mathUtils.js
@@ -1,8 +1,12 @@
-// Basic math utilities
+// Extended math utilities with additional functions

-export function calculateArea(radius) {
-    const PI = 3.14159;
+export function calculateCircleMetrics(radius) {
+    const PI = Math.PI;
     const area = PI * radius ** 2;
+    const circumference = 2 * PI * radius;
+
+    if (!isValidRadius(radius)) throw new Error("Invalid radius");
+
     return { area, circumference };
 }

-export function validateRadius(radius) {
+export function isValidRadius(radius) {
     return typeof radius === 'number' &amp;&amp; radius &gt; 0;
 }

diff --git a/main.js b/main.js
index 5f6a9c3..b7d4e8f 100644
--- a/main.js
+++ b/main.js
@@ -2,9 +2,12 @@
 import { calculateCircleMetrics } from './utils/mathUtils';

-function displayCircleMetrics(radius) {
-    const { area } = calculateCircleMetrics(radius);
+function displayCircleMetrics(radius) {
+    const { area, circumference } = calculateCircleMetrics(radius);
     console.log(`Area: ${area}`);
+    console.log(`Circumference: ${circumference}`);
 }

-displayCircleMetrics(5);
+try {
+    displayCircleMetrics(5);
+} catch (error) {
+    console.error("Error:", error.message);
+}
</code></pre> <hr/> <h2 id="leaflet">Leaflet</h2> <p><a href="https://leafletjs.com/">Leaflet</a> is created by Ukrainian software engineer <a href="https://agafonkin.com/">Volodymyr Agafonkin</a>, allowing interactive maps to be embedded in webpages. With support for <a href="https://geojson.org/">GeoJSON data</a>, Leaflet allows you to highlight specific regions, making it easy to visualize geographical information in detail.</p> <p>You can use the following code to load map information on <a href="https://www.openstreetmap.org/">OpenStreetMap</a>:</p> <div class="language-markdown highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="p">```</span><span class="nl">geojson
</span><span class="sb">{
  "type": "FeatureCollection",
  "features": [
    {
      "type": "Feature",
      "properties": {
        "name": "Crimea",
        "popupContent": "Occupied Crimea"
      },
      "geometry": {
        "type": "Polygon",
        "coordinates": [
          [
            [33.9, 45.3],
            [36.5, 45.3],
            [36.5, 44.4],
            [33.9, 44.4],
            [33.9, 45.3]
          ]
        ]
      }
    },
    {
      "type": "Feature",
      "properties": {
        "name": "Donetsk",
        "popupContent": "Occupied Donetsk"
      },
      "geometry": {
        "type": "Polygon",
        "coordinates": [
          [
            [37.5, 48.5],
            [39.5, 48.5],
            [39.5, 47.5],
            [37.5, 47.5],
            [37.5, 48.5]
          ]
        ]
      }
    },
    {
      "type": "Feature",
      "properties": {
        "name": "Luhansk",
        "popupContent": "Occupied Luhansk"
      },
      "geometry": {
        "type": "Polygon",
        "coordinates": [
          [
            [38.5, 49.5],
            [40.5, 49.5],
            [40.5, 48.5],
            [38.5, 48.5],
            [38.5, 49.5]
          ]
        ]
      }
    },
    {
      "type": "Feature",
      "properties": {
        "name": "Kherson",
        "popupContent": "Occupied Kherson"
      },
      "geometry": {
        "type": "Polygon",
        "coordinates": [
          [
            [32.3, 47.3],
            [34.3, 47.3],
            [34.3, 46.3],
            [32.3, 46.3],
            [32.3, 47.3]
          ]
        ]
      }
    },
    {
      "type": "Feature",
      "properties": {
        "name": "Zaporizhzhia",
        "popupContent": "Occupied Zaporizhzhia"
      },
      "geometry": {
        "type": "Polygon",
        "coordinates": [
          [
            [34.3, 48],
            [36.3, 48],
            [36.3, 47],
            [34.3, 47],
            [34.3, 48]
          ]
        ]
      }
    }
  ]
}</span>
<span class="p">```</span>
</code></pre></div></div> <p>The rendered map below highlights the regions of Ukraine that have been illegally occupied by Russia over the years, including Crimea and the four eastern regions:</p> <pre><code class="language-geojson">{
  "type": "FeatureCollection",
  "features": [
    {
      "type": "Feature",
      "properties": {
        "name": "Crimea",
        "popupContent": "Occupied Crimea"
      },
      "geometry": {
        "type": "Polygon",
        "coordinates": [
          [
            [33.9, 45.3],
            [36.5, 45.3],
            [36.5, 44.4],
            [33.9, 44.4],
            [33.9, 45.3]
          ]
        ]
      }
    },
    {
      "type": "Feature",
      "properties": {
        "name": "Donetsk",
        "popupContent": "Occupied Donetsk"
      },
      "geometry": {
        "type": "Polygon",
        "coordinates": [
          [
            [37.5, 48.5],
            [39.5, 48.5],
            [39.5, 47.5],
            [37.5, 47.5],
            [37.5, 48.5]
          ]
        ]
      }
    },
    {
      "type": "Feature",
      "properties": {
        "name": "Luhansk",
        "popupContent": "Occupied Luhansk"
      },
      "geometry": {
        "type": "Polygon",
        "coordinates": [
          [
            [38.5, 49.5],
            [40.5, 49.5],
            [40.5, 48.5],
            [38.5, 48.5],
            [38.5, 49.5]
          ]
        ]
      }
    },
    {
      "type": "Feature",
      "properties": {
        "name": "Kherson",
        "popupContent": "Occupied Kherson"
      },
      "geometry": {
        "type": "Polygon",
        "coordinates": [
          [
            [32.3, 47.3],
            [34.3, 47.3],
            [34.3, 46.3],
            [32.3, 46.3],
            [32.3, 47.3]
          ]
        ]
      }
    },
    {
      "type": "Feature",
      "properties": {
        "name": "Zaporizhzhia",
        "popupContent": "Occupied Zaporizhzhia"
      },
      "geometry": {
        "type": "Polygon",
        "coordinates": [
          [
            [34.3, 48],
            [36.3, 48],
            [36.3, 47],
            [34.3, 47],
            [34.3, 48]
          ]
        ]
      }
    }
  ]
}
</code></pre> <hr/> <h2 id="chartjs-echarts-and-vega-lite">Chartjs, Echarts and Vega-Lite</h2> <p><a href="https://www.chartjs.org/">Chart.js</a> is a versatile JavaScript library for creating responsive and interactive charts. Supporting multiple chart types like bar, line, pie, and radar, it’s an ideal tool for visualizing data directly in webpages.</p> <p>Here’s an example of a JSON-style configuration that creates a bar chart in Chart.js:</p> <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>```chartjs
{
  "type": "bar",
  "data": {
    "labels": ["2017", "2018", "2019", "2020", "2021"],
    "datasets": [
      {
        "label": "Population (millions)",
        "data": [12, 15, 13, 14, 16],
        "backgroundColor": "rgba(54, 162, 235, 0.6)",
        "borderColor": "rgba(54, 162, 235, 1)",
        "borderWidth": 1
      }
    ]
  },
  "options": {
    "scales": {
      "y": {
        "beginAtZero": true
      }
    }
  }
}
```
</code></pre></div></div> <p>The rendered bar chart illustrates population data from 2017 to 2021:</p> <pre><code class="language-chartjs">{
  "type": "bar",
  "data": {
    "labels": ["2017", "2018", "2019", "2020", "2021"],
    "datasets": [
      {
        "label": "Population (millions)",
        "data": [12, 15, 13, 14, 16],
        "backgroundColor": "rgba(54, 162, 235, 0.6)",
        "borderColor": "rgba(54, 162, 235, 1)",
        "borderWidth": 1
      }
    ]
  },
  "options": {
    "scales": {
      "y": {
        "beginAtZero": true
      }
    }
  }
}
</code></pre> <hr/> <p><a href="https://echarts.apache.org/">ECharts</a> is a powerful visualization library from <a href="https://www.apache.org/">Apache</a> that supports a wide range of interactive charts, including more advanced types such as scatter plots, heatmaps, and geographic maps.</p> <p>The following JSON configuration creates a visually enhanced line chart that displays monthly sales data for two products.</p> <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>```echarts
{
  "title": {
    "text": "Monthly Sales Comparison",
    "left": "center"
  },
  "tooltip": {
    "trigger": "axis",
    "backgroundColor": "rgba(50, 50, 50, 0.7)",
    "borderColor": "#777",
    "borderWidth": 1,
    "textStyle": {
      "color": "#fff"
    }
  },
  "legend": {
    "data": ["Product A", "Product B"],
    "top": "10%"
  },
  "xAxis": {
    "type": "category",
    "data": ["Jan", "Feb", "Mar", "Apr", "May", "Jun", "Jul", "Aug", "Sep", "Oct", "Nov", "Dec"],
    "axisLine": {
      "lineStyle": {
        "color": "#888"
      }
    }
  },
  "yAxis": {
    "type": "value",
    "axisLine": {
      "lineStyle": {
        "color": "#888"
      }
    },
    "splitLine": {
      "lineStyle": {
        "type": "dashed"
      }
    }
  },
  "series": [
    {
      "name": "Product A",
      "type": "line",
      "smooth": true,
      "data": [820, 932, 901, 934, 1290, 1330, 1320, 1400, 1450, 1500, 1600, 1650],
      "itemStyle": {
        "color": "#5470C6"
      },
      "lineStyle": {
        "width": 3
      },
      "areaStyle": {
        "color": {
          "type": "linear",
          "x": 0,
          "y": 0,
          "x2": 0,
          "y2": 1,
          "colorStops": [
            { "offset": 0, "color": "rgba(84, 112, 198, 0.5)" },
            { "offset": 1, "color": "rgba(84, 112, 198, 0)" }
          ]
        }
      },
      "emphasis": {
        "focus": "series"
      }
    },
    {
      "name": "Product B",
      "type": "line",
      "smooth": true,
      "data": [620, 732, 701, 734, 1090, 1130, 1120, 1200, 1250, 1300, 1400, 1450],
      "itemStyle": {
        "color": "#91CC75"
      },
      "lineStyle": {
        "width": 3
      },
      "areaStyle": {
        "color": {
          "type": "linear",
          "x": 0,
          "y": 0,
          "x2": 0,
          "y2": 1,
          "colorStops": [
            { "offset": 0, "color": "rgba(145, 204, 117, 0.5)" },
            { "offset": 1, "color": "rgba(145, 204, 117, 0)" }
          ]
        }
      },
      "emphasis": {
        "focus": "series"
      }
    }
  ]
}
```
</code></pre></div></div> <p>The rendered output is shown below, and you can also interact with it using your mouse:</p> <pre><code class="language-echarts">{
  "title": {
    "text": "Monthly Sales Comparison",
    "left": "center"
  },
  "tooltip": {
    "trigger": "axis",
    "backgroundColor": "rgba(50, 50, 50, 0.7)",
    "borderColor": "#777",
    "borderWidth": 1,
    "textStyle": {
      "color": "#fff"
    }
  },
  "legend": {
    "data": ["Product A", "Product B"],
    "top": "10%"
  },
  "xAxis": {
    "type": "category",
    "data": ["Jan", "Feb", "Mar", "Apr", "May", "Jun", "Jul", "Aug", "Sep", "Oct", "Nov", "Dec"],
    "axisLine": {
      "lineStyle": {
        "color": "#888"
      }
    }
  },
  "yAxis": {
    "type": "value",
    "axisLine": {
      "lineStyle": {
        "color": "#888"
      }
    },
    "splitLine": {
      "lineStyle": {
        "type": "dashed"
      }
    }
  },
  "series": [
    {
      "name": "Product A",
      "type": "line",
      "smooth": true,
      "data": [820, 932, 901, 934, 1290, 1330, 1320, 1400, 1450, 1500, 1600, 1650],
      "itemStyle": {
        "color": "#5470C6"
      },
      "lineStyle": {
        "width": 3
      },
      "areaStyle": {
        "color": {
          "type": "linear",
          "x": 0,
          "y": 0,
          "x2": 0,
          "y2": 1,
          "colorStops": [
            { "offset": 0, "color": "rgba(84, 112, 198, 0.5)" },
            { "offset": 1, "color": "rgba(84, 112, 198, 0)" }
          ]
        }
      },
      "emphasis": {
        "focus": "series"
      }
    },
    {
      "name": "Product B",
      "type": "line",
      "smooth": true,
      "data": [620, 732, 701, 734, 1090, 1130, 1120, 1200, 1250, 1300, 1400, 1450],
      "itemStyle": {
        "color": "#91CC75"
      },
      "lineStyle": {
        "width": 3
      },
      "areaStyle": {
        "color": {
          "type": "linear",
          "x": 0,
          "y": 0,
          "x2": 0,
          "y2": 1,
          "colorStops": [
            { "offset": 0, "color": "rgba(145, 204, 117, 0.5)" },
            { "offset": 1, "color": "rgba(145, 204, 117, 0)" }
          ]
        }
      },
      "emphasis": {
        "focus": "series"
      }
    }
  ]
}
</code></pre> <hr/> <p><a href="https://vega.github.io/vega-lite/">Vega-Lite</a> is a declarative visualization grammar that allows users to create, share, and customize a wide range of interactive data visualizations. The following JSON configuration generates a straightforward bar chart:</p> <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>```vega_lite
{
  "$schema": "https://vega.github.io/schema/vega/v5.json",
  "width": 400,
  "height": 200,
  "padding": 5,

  "data": [
    {
      "name": "table",
      "values": [
        {"category": "A", "value": 28},
        {"category": "B", "value": 55},
        {"category": "C", "value": 43},
        {"category": "D", "value": 91},
        {"category": "E", "value": 81},
        {"category": "F", "value": 53},
        {"category": "G", "value": 19},
        {"category": "H", "value": 87}
      ]
    }
  ],

  "scales": [
    {
      "name": "xscale",
      "type": "band",
      "domain": {"data": "table", "field": "category"},
      "range": "width",
      "padding": 0.1
    },
    {
      "name": "yscale",
      "type": "linear",
      "domain": {"data": "table", "field": "value"},
      "nice": true,
      "range": "height"
    }
  ],

  "axes": [
    {"orient": "bottom", "scale": "xscale"},
    {"orient": "left", "scale": "yscale"}
  ],

  "marks": [
    {
      "type": "rect",
      "from": {"data": "table"},
      "encode": {
        "enter": {
          "x": {"scale": "xscale", "field": "category"},
          "width": {"scale": "xscale", "band": 0.8},
          "y": {"scale": "yscale", "field": "value"},
          "y2": {"scale": "yscale", "value": 0},
          "fill": {"value": "steelblue"}
        },
        "update": {
          "fillOpacity": {"value": 1}
        },
        "hover": {
          "fill": {"value": "orange"}
        }
      }
    }
  ]
}
```
</code></pre></div></div> <p>The rendered output shows a clean and simple bar chart with a hover effect：</p> <pre><code class="language-vega_lite">{
  "$schema": "https://vega.github.io/schema/vega/v5.json",
  "width": 400,
  "height": 200,
  "padding": 5,

  "data": [
    {
      "name": "table",
      "values": [
        {"category": "A", "value": 28},
        {"category": "B", "value": 55},
        {"category": "C", "value": 43},
        {"category": "D", "value": 91},
        {"category": "E", "value": 81},
        {"category": "F", "value": 53},
        {"category": "G", "value": 19},
        {"category": "H", "value": 87}
      ]
    }
  ],

  "scales": [
    {
      "name": "xscale",
      "type": "band",
      "domain": {"data": "table", "field": "category"},
      "range": "width",
      "padding": 0.1
    },
    {
      "name": "yscale",
      "type": "linear",
      "domain": {"data": "table", "field": "value"},
      "nice": true,
      "range": "height"
    }
  ],

  "axes": [
    {"orient": "bottom", "scale": "xscale"},
    {"orient": "left", "scale": "yscale"}
  ],

  "marks": [
    {
      "type": "rect",
      "from": {"data": "table"},
      "encode": {
        "enter": {
          "x": {"scale": "xscale", "field": "category"},
          "width": {"scale": "xscale", "band": 0.8},
          "y": {"scale": "yscale", "field": "value"},
          "y2": {"scale": "yscale", "value": 0},
          "fill": {"value": "steelblue"}
        },
        "update": {
          "fillOpacity": {"value": 1}
        },
        "hover": {
          "fill": {"value": "orange"}
        }
      }
    }
  ]
}
</code></pre> <hr/> <h2 id="tikz">TikZ</h2> <p><a href="https://tikz.net/">TikZ</a> is a powerful LaTeX-based drawing tool powered by <a href="https://tikzjax.com/">TikZJax</a>. You can easily port TikZ drawings from papers, posters, and notes. For example, we can use the following code to illustrate Euler’s formula $ e^{i \theta} = \cos \theta + i \sin \theta $:</p> <div class="language-markdown highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="nt">&lt;script </span><span class="na">type=</span><span class="s">"text/tikz"</span><span class="nt">&gt;</span>
<span class="se">\b</span>egin{tikzpicture}
    <span class="se">\f</span>illdraw[fill=cyan!10, draw=blue, thick] (0,0) circle (2cm);<span class="sb">

    \draw[-&gt;, thick] (-2.5,0) -- (2.5,0) node[right] {Re};
    \draw[-&gt;, thick] (0,-2.5) -- (0,2.5) node[above] {Im};

    \draw[-&gt;, thick, color=purple] (0,0) -- (1.5,1.5);
    \node[color=purple] at (1.1, 1.7) {$e^{i\theta}$};

    \draw[thick] (0.7,0) arc (0:45:0.7);
    \node at (0.9, 0.3) {$\theta$};

    \draw[dashed, color=gray] (1.5,1.5) -- (1.5,0) node[below, black] {$\cos \theta$};
    \draw[dashed, color=gray] (1.5,1.5) -- (0,1.5) node[left, black] {$\sin \theta$};
    \node at (2.2, 0) [below] {1};
    \node at (0, 2.2) [left] {$i$};
    \node at (1.5,1.5) [above right, color=blue] {$(\cos \theta \, \sin \theta)$};
</span><span class="se">\e</span>nd{tikzpicture}
<span class="nt">&lt;/script&gt;</span>
</code></pre></div></div> <p>The rendered output is shown below, displayed as a vector graphic：</p> <script type="text/tikz">
\begin{tikzpicture}
    \filldraw[fill=cyan!10, draw=blue, thick] (0,0) circle (2cm);

    \draw[->, thick] (-2.5,0) -- (2.5,0) node[right] {Re};
    \draw[->, thick] (0,-2.5) -- (0,2.5) node[above] {Im};

    \draw[->, thick, color=purple] (0,0) -- (1.5,1.5);
    \node[color=purple] at (1.1, 1.7) {$e^{i\theta}$};

    \draw[thick] (0.7,0) arc (0:45:0.7);
    \node at (0.9, 0.3) {$\theta$};

    \draw[dashed, color=gray] (1.5,1.5) -- (1.5,0) node[below, black] {$\cos \theta$};
    \draw[dashed, color=gray] (1.5,1.5) -- (0,1.5) node[left, black] {$\sin \theta$};
    \node at (2.2, 0) [below] {1};
    \node at (0, 2.2) [left] {$i$};
    \node at (1.5,1.5) [above right, color=blue] {$(\cos \theta \, \sin \theta)$};
\end{tikzpicture}
</script> <hr/> <h2 id="typograms">Typograms</h2> <p><a href="https://google.github.io/typograms/">Typograms</a> are a way of combining text and graphics to convey information in a clear and visually engaging manner. Typograms are particularly effective for illustrating simple diagrams, charts, and concept visuals where text and graphics are closely integrated. The following example demonstrates a simple Typogram:</p> <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>```typograms
             ___________________
            /                  /|
           /__________________/ |
          |                  |  |
          |     Distill      |  |
          |                  |  |
          |                  | /
          |__________________|/
```
</code></pre></div></div> <p>The rendered output is shown below：</p> <pre><code class="language-typograms">             ___________________
            /                  /|
           /__________________/ |
          |                  |  |
          |     Distill      |  |
          |                  |  |
          |                  | /
          |__________________|/
</code></pre> <hr/> <h2 id="layouts">Layouts</h2> <p>The main text column is referred to as the body. It is the assumed layout of any direct descendants of the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">d-article</code> element.</p> <div class="fake-img l-body"> <p>.l-body</p> </div> <p>For images you want to display a little larger, try <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">.l-page</code>:</p> <div class="fake-img l-page"> <p>.l-page</p> </div> <p>All of these have an outset variant if you want to poke out from the body text a little bit. For instance:</p> <div class="fake-img l-body-outset"> <p>.l-body-outset</p> </div> <div class="fake-img l-page-outset"> <p>.l-page-outset</p> </div> <p>Occasionally you’ll want to use the full browser width. For this, use <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">.l-screen</code>. You can also inset the element a little from the edge of the browser by using the inset variant.</p> <div class="fake-img l-screen"> <p>.l-screen</p> </div> <div class="fake-img l-screen-inset"> <p>.l-screen-inset</p> </div> <p>The final layout is for marginalia, asides, and footnotes. It does not interrupt the normal flow of <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">.l-body</code> sized text except on mobile screen sizes.</p> <div class="fake-img l-gutter"> <p>.l-gutter</p> </div> <hr/> <h2 id="sidenotes">Sidenotes</h2> <p>Distill supports sidenotes, which are like footnotes but placed in the margin of the page. They are useful for providing additional context or references without interrupting the flow of the main text.</p> <p>There are two main ways to create a sidenote:</p> <p><strong>Using the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">&lt;aside&gt;</code> tag:</strong></p> <p>The following code creates a sidenote with <strong><em>distill’s styling</em></strong> in the margin:</p> <div class="language-html highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="nt">&lt;aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;</span>This is a sidenote using aside tag.<span class="nt">&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;</span>
</code></pre></div></div> <aside><p> This is a sidenote using `&lt;aside&gt;` tag</p> </aside> <p>We can also add images to sidenotes (click on the image to zoom in for a larger version):</p> <div class="language-html highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="nt">&lt;aside&gt;</span>
  {% include figure.liquid loading="eager" path="assets/img/rhino.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" zoomable=true %}
  <span class="nt">&lt;p&gt;</span>
    F.J. Cole, “The History of Albrecht Dürer’s Rhinoceros in Zoological Literature,” Science, Medicine, and History: Essays on the Evolution of
    Scientific Thought and Medical Practice (London, 1953), ed. E. Ashworth Underwood, 337-356. From page 71 of Edward Tufte’s Visual Explanations.
  <span class="nt">&lt;/p&gt;</span>
<span class="nt">&lt;/aside&gt;</span>
</code></pre></div></div> <aside> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/rhino-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/rhino-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/rhino-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/rhino.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> <p>F.J. Cole, “The History of Albrecht Dürer’s Rhinoceros in Zoological Literature,” Science, Medicine, and History: Essays on the Evolution of Scientific Thought and Medical Practice (London, 1953), ed. E. Ashworth Underwood, 337-356. From page 71 of Edward Tufte’s Visual Explanations.</p> </aside> <p>Sidenotes can also contain equations and links:</p> <p>In physics, mass–energy equivalence is the relationship between mass and energy in a system’s rest frame. The two differ only by a multiplicative constant and the units of measurement.</p> <aside> <p>This principle is defined by Einstein's famous equation: $E = mc^2$ <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mass%E2%80%93energy_equivalence" target="_blank">(Source: Wikipedia)</a></p> </aside> <p><strong>Using the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">l-gutter</code> class:</strong></p> <p>The following code creates a sidenote with <strong><em>al-folio’s styling</em></strong> in the margin:</p> <div class="language-html highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="nt">&lt;div</span> <span class="na">class=</span><span class="s">"l-gutter"</span><span class="nt">&gt;&lt;p&gt;</span>This is a sidenote using l-gutter class.<span class="nt">&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</span>
</code></pre></div></div> <div class="l-gutter"> <p> This is a sidenote using `l-gutter` class. </p> </div> <hr/> <h2 id="other-typography">Other Typography?</h2> <p>Emphasis, aka italics, with <em>asterisks</em> (<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">*asterisks*</code>) or <em>underscores</em> (<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">_underscores_</code>).</p> <p>Strong emphasis, aka bold, with <strong>asterisks</strong> or <strong>underscores</strong>.</p> <p>Combined emphasis with <strong>asterisks and <em>underscores</em></strong>.</p> <p>Strikethrough uses two tildes. <del>Scratch this.</del></p> <ol> <li>First ordered list item</li> <li>Another item ⋅⋅* Unordered sub-list.</li> <li>Actual numbers don’t matter, just that it’s a number ⋅⋅1. Ordered sub-list</li> <li>And another item.</li> </ol> <p>⋅⋅⋅You can have properly indented paragraphs within list items. Notice the blank line above, and the leading spaces (at least one, but we’ll use three here to also align the raw Markdown).</p> <p>⋅⋅⋅To have a line break without a paragraph, you will need to use two trailing spaces.⋅⋅ ⋅⋅⋅Note that this line is separate, but within the same paragraph.⋅⋅ ⋅⋅⋅(This is contrary to the typical GFM line break behaviour, where trailing spaces are not required.)</p> <ul> <li> <p>Unordered list can use asterisks</p> </li> <li> <p>Or minuses</p> </li> <li> <p>Or pluses</p> </li> </ul> <p><a href="https://www.google.com">I’m an inline-style link</a></p> <p><a href="https://www.google.com" title="Google's Homepage">I’m an inline-style link with title</a></p> <p><a href="https://www.mozilla.org">I’m a reference-style link</a></p> <p><a href="http://slashdot.org">You can use numbers for reference-style link definitions</a></p> <p>Or leave it empty and use the <a href="http://www.reddit.com">link text itself</a>.</p> <p>URLs and URLs in angle brackets will automatically get turned into links. http://www.example.com or <a href="http://www.example.com">http://www.example.com</a> and sometimes example.com (but not on Github, for example).</p> <p>Some text to show that the reference links can follow later.</p> <p>Here’s our logo (hover to see the title text):</p> <p>Inline-style: <img src="https://github.com/adam-p/markdown-here/raw/master/src/common/images/icon48.png" alt="alt text" title="Logo Title Text 1"/></p> <p>Reference-style: <img src="https://github.com/adam-p/markdown-here/raw/master/src/common/images/icon48.png" alt="alt text" title="Logo Title Text 2"/></p> <p>Inline <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">code</code> has <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">back-ticks around</code> it.</p> <div class="language-javascript highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">s</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="dl">"</span><span class="s2">JavaScript syntax highlighting</span><span class="dl">"</span><span class="p">;</span>
<span class="nf">alert</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">s</span><span class="p">);</span>
</code></pre></div></div> <div class="language-python highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="n">s</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="sh">"</span><span class="s">Python syntax highlighting</span><span class="sh">"</span>
<span class="k">print</span> <span class="n">s</span>
</code></pre></div></div> <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>No language indicated, so no syntax highlighting.
But let's throw in a &lt;b&gt;tag&lt;/b&gt;.
</code></pre></div></div> <p>Colons can be used to align columns.</p> <table> <thead> <tr> <th>Tables</th> <th style="text-align: center">Are</th> <th style="text-align: right">Cool</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td>col 3 is</td> <td style="text-align: center">right-aligned</td> <td style="text-align: right">$1600</td> </tr> <tr> <td>col 2 is</td> <td style="text-align: center">centered</td> <td style="text-align: right">$12</td> </tr> <tr> <td>zebra stripes</td> <td style="text-align: center">are neat</td> <td style="text-align: right">$1</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <p>There must be at least 3 dashes separating each header cell. The outer pipes (|) are optional, and you don’t need to make the raw Markdown line up prettily. You can also use inline Markdown.</p> <table> <thead> <tr> <th>Markdown</th> <th>Less</th> <th>Pretty</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td><em>Still</em></td> <td><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">renders</code></td> <td><strong>nicely</strong></td> </tr> <tr> <td>1</td> <td>2</td> <td>3</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <blockquote> <p>Blockquotes are very handy in email to emulate reply text. This line is part of the same quote.</p> </blockquote> <p>Quote break.</p> <blockquote> <p>This is a very long line that will still be quoted properly when it wraps. Oh boy let’s keep writing to make sure this is long enough to actually wrap for everyone. Oh, you can <em>put</em> <strong>Markdown</strong> into a blockquote.</p> </blockquote> <p>Here’s a line for us to start with.</p> <p>This line is separated from the one above by two newlines, so it will be a <em>separate paragraph</em>.</p> <p>This line is also a separate paragraph, but… This line is only separated by a single newline, so it’s a separate line in the <em>same paragraph</em>.</p>]]></content><author><name>Albert Einstein</name></author><category term="distill"/><category term="formatting"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[an example of a distill-style blog post and main elements]]></summary></entry></feed>